真实故事改编
1983年
当你爱一个人，你必须相信他
SAM: [Voiceover] When you love someone,
you've gotta trust them.
别无它法
There's no other way.
你得将掌管生命中一切的那把钥匙给他
You've got to give them the key
to everything that's yours.
要不然有什么意义？
Otherwise, what's the point?
一直以来，我深信我拥有的是这样的爱
And, for a while,
I believed that's the kind of love I had.
[Dramatic operatic music]
[Operatic music becomes calmer]
在我开赌场及被炸之前…
SAM: Before I ever ran a casino,
or got blown up...
艾斯罗斯坦，可是最诺娜马预测者
Ace Rothstein was a hell of a handicapper.
我告诉你
I can tell you that.
我旺到每次只要我下注，全国的赌盘赔率…
I was so good that whenever I bet,
I'd change the odds...
都会随着改变
for every bookmaker in the country.
不盖你，我对赛马的研究精湛到…
I'm serious, I had it down so cold...
让我晋升人间天堂
that I was given paradise on Earth.
我被升为拉斯维加斯最大赌场之一坦吉乐的管理人…
I was given one of the biggest casinos
in Las Vegas to run, the Tangiers...
唯有聘请我的那帮人才能如此大手笔
by the only kind of guys that can actually
get you that kind of money.
六千两百七十万美元
$62, 700, 000.
我不知道细节
I don't know all the details.
老实说，没人知道细节…
NICKY: [Voiceover] In fact,
nobody knew all the details...
原本应该很完美的
but it should've been perfect.
他有我这好友尼奇山多罗挺他…
He had me, Nicky Santoro,
his best friend, watching his ass...
他手中也揽着他爱的女人，金吉儿
and he had Ginger,
the woman he loved, on his arm.
到头来，我们全搞砸了
But in the end, we fucked it all up.
原本应多完美
It should've been so sweet, too.
结果，我们这样的小混混…
It turned out to be the last time
that street guys like us...
在这次之后就再也无缘搞油水这么丰富的大生意了
were ever given anything
that fucking valuable again.
那时的赌城，是蠢蛋们…
SAM: Vegas was a place where suckers...
一毛一毛存足了钱飞来…
flew in every year on their own nickel...
直到输光了家当才走人的地方
and left behind about a billion dollars.
在夜晚，你看不到包围拉斯维加斯的沙漠
But at night, you couldn't see
the desert that surrounds Las Vegas.
但城里许多的问题却都是在沙漠里解决的
But it's in the desert where lots
of the town's problems are solved.
沙漠里的坑洞可多着呢
NICKY: Got a lot of holes in the desert...
里面埋藏了很多问题
and a lot of problems
are buried in those holes.
只是程序要对
Except you gotta do it right.
你得先把洞挖好…
You gotta have the hole already dug...
再将货从汽车后车箱载来
before you show up
with a package in the trunk.
要不然你就得在沙漠挖上个30到45分钟
Otherwise, you're talking about
30 or 45 minutes of digging.
谁又知道期间会有什么人出现？
Who knows who's gonna be coming along
in that time?
不知不觉中，你又得多挖好几个洞
Before you know it,
you gotta dig a few more holes.
搞不好一整晚都得耗在那儿
You could be there all fucking night.
公爵
[Horns honking]
坦吉乐
精华地段-拉斯维加斯，十年前
THE STRIP - LAS VEGAS
TEN YEARS EARLIER
[Upbeat jazz music]
谁抗拒的了？
SAM: Who could resist?
在别处，我只是个登记赛马的一个赌徒…
Anywhere else, I was a bookie, a gambler...
老是得小心翼翼，成天被条子们骚扰
always looking over my shoulder,
hassled by cops, day and night.
但在这儿，我可是罗斯坦先生
But here, I'm Mr. Rothstein.
不但不偷鸡摸狗，还管间赌场
I'm not only legitimate,
but running a casino.
那就像是将梦想换为现金
And that's like selling people
dreams for cash.
我聘任了赌场的一个老朋友
比利雪伯当经理，然后开始工作
I hired an old casino pal, Billy Sherbert,
as my manager, and went to work.
这是负责牌室的罗尼
And this is Ronnie,
who takes care of the card room.
像我们这种人
拉斯维加斯洗去了我们的罪孽
SAM: For guys like me,
Las Vegas washes away your sins.
像是道德洗车场一样
It's like a morality car wash.
它对我们的效用就像法国露德
对驼背和残障的人一样
It does for us what Lourdes does
for humpbacks and cripples.
[Upbeat jazz music intensifies]
不但让我们重见天日…
SAM: And along with making us legit...
还带来了现金，数不尽的钱
comes cash, tons of it.
不然你以为我们没事
跑到这沙漠中央干嘛？
What do you think we're doing
here in the middle of the desert?
就是为了这些钱
It's all this money.
这是所有炫目的灯光…
This is the end result
of all the bright lights...
所有的招待、香槟、免费住宿…
and the comped trips,
of all the champagne...
女人与喝不完的酒
最终所造成的结果
and free hotel suites,
and all the broads and all the booze.
全都是为了
让我们弄走你的钱
It's all been arranged
just for us to get your money.
这就是赌城的真面目
That's the truth about Las Vegas.
我们是唯一的赢家
We're the only winners.
赌徒们一点机会都没有
The players don't stand a chance.
而他们的钱从赌桌上…
And their cash flows from the tables...
流入我们的收银柜再进入保险笼…
to our boxes through the cage...
最后流入全赌场最神圣的房间
and into the most sacred room
in the casino.
他们计算钱的地方…
The place where they add up all the money...
注意-请勿进入
万物之首，计算室
the Holy of holies, the count room.
这儿可不是闲杂人等可进出的
Now, this place was off-limits.
连我都进不去
Even I couldn't get inside.
当然，但我的工作是让它保持
满满的状态
But it was my job to keep it filled
with cash. That's for sure.
里头的钱多到…
NICKY: They had so much money in there...
可让你用百元大钞砌栋房子
you could build a house out
of stacks of $100 bills.
最棒的是…
And the best part was that upstairs...
上头董事会什么屁都不知道
the Board of Directors didn't know
what the fuck was going on.
在他们看来一切都干净俐落
没人动手脚
To them everything looked
on the up-and-up.
不是吗？当然不
Right? Wrong.
确认五千元
Verify $5,000.
在计算室的那些人…
NICKY: The guys in the counting room...
都是被派进去将里头吸干的
were all slipped in there
to skim the joint dry.
他们会少算钱，将计单弄掉
They'd do short counts,
they'd lose fill slips.
甚至直接从箱里拿走现款
They'd even take cash
right out of the drop-boxes.
全是靠这家伙…
And it was up to this guy right here...
站在两百万元前的这位…
standing in front of $2 million...
在被国税局或任何人发现前…
to skim the cash off the top
without anybody getting wise...
把钱摸走
the IRS or anybody.
在计算室里
好像都没人在看
Notice how in the count room
nobody ever seems to see anything.
不知怎的，大家都视若无睹
Somehow, somebody's always looking
the other way.
看看这些家伙
他们看来真忙，不是吗？
Look at these guys. They look busy, right?
他们在算钱，谁会吵他们呢？
They're counting money.
Who wants to bother them?
我的意思是，天晓得他们会不会
犯了错而忘记偷钱
I mean, God forbid they should make
a mistake and forget to steal.
这期间，你可来去自如
Meanwhile, you're in and you're out.
走过那些鸟事不干的警卫
每礼拜还多拿一百元…
Past the jag-off guard
who gets an extra $100 a week...
只为了看门
just to watch the door.
一如往常一样规律…
It's routine. Business as usual...
走进、走出、你好、再见
in, out, hello, goodbye.
就这么简单
That's all there is to it.
就只是个拎着皮箱
走出赌场的肥猪
Just another fat fuck walking out
of a casino with a suitcase.
但那口箱子
会直接送往一个地方
Now, that suitcase was going
straight to one place:
堪萨斯市，那里是…
right to Kansas City, which was as close...
中部的老大能离拉斯维加斯
最近的地方…
to Las Vegas as the Midwest bosses
could go...
而不用怕被逮捕
without getting themselves arrested.
堪萨斯市
老大们要的只是那口箱子
That suitcase was all
the bosses ever wanted.
每个月都要
And they wanted it every month.
圣马利诺意大利超市
这个摩门教的混蛋…
Now this old Mormon fuck here...
他每个月都得拿着箱子飞来
he had to fly in with suitcases
once a month, nice and easy.
-什么东西这么香？
-他们做了好料的
-Something smells good.
-They made us something to eat.
老大们会从各地飞来…
NICKY: The bosses
would come from all over:
底特律、克里夫兰、密尔瓦基…
Detroit, Cleveland, Milwaukee...
整个中西部…
all over the Midwest...
他们都会在这个位于
堪萨斯市的市场碰面
and they would meet in this produce market
in Kansas City.
根本没人会知道
Nobody even knew it.
有一个让他妈做菜
One of the guys made
his mother do the cooking.
你有看到杰瑞史塔瑞欧吗？
Do you ever see that guy Jerry Steriano?
这些老头们看来可能不怎么样
NICKY: These old greaseballs
might not look it...
但相信我…
but believe me...
他们才是赌城的秘密操纵者
these are the guys
who secretly controlled Las Vegas.
妈妈，那男人又来了
WOMAN: Mama, that man's here again.
因为他们控制着
全美卡车司机工会
NICKY: Because they controlled
the Teamsters Union.
而要开赌场非得到那儿去借钱
And that's where you had to go
to borrow money to buy a casino.
-你要放虾吗？
-我会的
WOMAN 2: Would you put in shrimp?
WOMAN: I would.
要是这些家伙们每月拿不到
这只小箱子…
NICKY: Nobody got a Teamsters'
loan unless the guys in this room...
那谁就都别想贷到款
knew they were gonna get
their little suitcases.
像这从底特律来的老家伙
Guys like this antique over here,
out of Detroit.
或尤其是像利蒙盖吉
这群人的首脑
Or especially guys like Remo Gaggi,
the outfit's top boss.
有大概数字吗？
You got a round figure on it?
绝对是这房里最重要的人物
NICKY: Definitely the most
important guy in this room.
-十公斤，那就差不多七十万了
-很好
FRANK: About 20 pounds.
Around $700,000.
REMO: Good.
虽说对拉斯维加斯还有点早…
STONE: It's a little early for Las Vegas...
但我想邀请赌博游乐业界的
先生与小姐们…
but I want to welcome the ladies
and gentlemen of the gaming industry....
就以世界所知…
SAM: As far as the world was concerned...
安迪史东卡车司机工会
退休基金会的负责人…
Andy Stone,
head of the Teamsters' Pension Fund...
是个清白的人物
was a legitimate guy.
有权力的人
A powerful man.
他与总统一同打高尔夫
He played golf with the President.
代表卡车司机工会退休基金会…
ANDY: On behalf
of the Teamsters' Pension Fund...
-我很高兴将这…
-但安迪也听命于人
I'm glad to present...
SAM: But he also took orders.
当他被指示将基金贷款
贷给菲立浦葛林…
When he was told to give
a pension-fund loan to Philip Green...
六千两百七十万的支票…
...this check for $62,700,000...
给全新的坦吉乐
for the new Tangiers.
他就会乖乖听话
...he did what he was told.
他可是最完美的傀儡
NICKY: Here was the perfect front man.
他还能干嘛呢？
他什么都不知道
What the fuck else could he be?
He didn't know too much.
也什么都不想知道…
He didn't want to know too much...
尤其是老大们让工会借钱给他
especially that the bosses
made the Teamsters lend him money.
他想相信他们是因为
他的才智贷款给他
He wanted to believe they gave him
the money because he was smart.
我了解这城市的竞争性有多大
才会说出此话
I say that knowing just how much
competition we have in this city.
[Upbeat jazz music]
他们从哪儿找来葛林的？
NICKY: And where they got Green from?
谁知道啊？
Who the fuck knows?
我只知道他在亚利桑那州
是个房地产经纪…
All I know is that he was
an Arizona real-estate hustler...
却连开来拿支票的油钱
都差点付不出来
who barely had enough gas money
to come and pick up his fucking check.
美国中部
卡车司机工会退休基金
是由老大的人…
And it was the bosses' man...
安迪史东下所有的命令
Andy Stone, who gave all the orders.
并不是由董事会主席
菲立浦葛林
Not the Chairman of the Board,
Philip Green.
我了解
I understand.
[Upbeat jazz music intensifies]
现在只缺…
NICKY: Now all they needed was...
一个可信任的人来管理赌场
someone they could trust to run the casino.
有谁比艾斯更适合？
他已经在赌城混了几年…
And who better than Ace?
He was already in Vegas a couple years...
他对这儿t若指掌
and he had the fucking place clocked.
艾斯的一贯作风
你给他个管理赌场的机会…
But typical Ace,
give him a shot to run a casino...
他还推三阻四
and he tries to talk you out of it.
我不知道自己行不行
I don't know if I could do this.
赌博游乐委员会绝不会
发执照给我的
The Gaming Commission
would never give me a license.
我最起码有两打以上
赌博与赛马被逮的前科
I have at least 24 gambling
and bookmaking pinches on me.
在赌场工作不需要执照
You don't have to have a license
to work in a casino.
你只需要去申请
All you gotta do is apply for one.
州法律允许你在申请期间…
The State law says that
you can work in a casino...
在赌场做事
while they process your application.
他们文件进度现在落后十年
ANDY: They got a 10-year backlog.
若他们发现了怎么办？
What happens when they do find out?
他们为什么会想发现？
ANDY: Why would they want to find out?
我们在这儿投资了一亿
他们何必赶我们走？
We're putting $100 million here.
Why would they lock us out?
他们不会发现的
你只需要一直改变职位头衔
ANDY: They'll never find out. All you
gotta do is keep changing your job title.
像从赌场执行长改到
餐饮主席
Like, from Casino Executive
to Food and Beverage Chairman.
然后他们又会将你的申请表
摆到最下面去
Then they put your application
at the bottom of the pile.
我有大把的员工
已经工作三十年了还没执照
I know guys who've worked there
for 30 years don't have a license.
这不是容易的决定，安迪
It's a tough proposition, Andy.
若我去做，得让我用我的方式
If I did it, I'd have to run it my way.
没问题
ANDY: You got it.
我说真的，不能有干涉
I'm serious. No interference.
没有人会干涉你管理赌场
Nobody's gonna interfere
with your running the casino.
我保证
I guarantee it.
[Upbeat jazz music]
艾斯就是这样接手的
NICKY: And that's how they got Ace
to take over.
要艾斯是因为
他不管是吃喝拉撒睡时都在赌
They wanted him because Ace ate,
slept and breathed gambling.
他们还给了他个很可爱的头衔…
They worked out a real cute job title, too...
坦吉乐公关理事
Tangiers Public Relations Director.
但他只管赌场
But the only thing he ever directed
was the casino.
他从十五岁时第一次下注就没输过
He made his first bet when he was 15,
and he always made money.
他不像你我那样赌
He didn't bet like you or me.
就为了他妈的好玩
Having some fun with it, shit like that.
你在哪儿学当庄家的？
Where did you learn how to deal?
他下注时就像是脑部外科医生一样
NICKY: He bet like a fucking brain surgeon.
筹码得摆对
SAM: Place the checks properly.
-像这样
-是的
-That's the way you do it.
-Yes, sir.
他得洞悉一切
NICKY: He had to know everything.
他知道没人晓得的内幕…
He'd find out the inside stuff
nobody else knew...
他会根据此下注
and that's what he'd put his money on.
在老家时
就连在老家时
BACK HOME YEARS AGO
Even back home, years ago...
当我们刚认识的时候…
他都知道四分卫有没有吸可卡因
when we first hung out,
he'd know if the quarterback was on coke...
我赌哥伦比亚两万
I'll take Columbia for $20,000.
或他的女友是否怀孕
...if his girlfriend was knocked up.
他会去测风速
只为了预测射门得分
He'd get the wind velocity
so he could judge the field goals.
他算出了篮球场上…
He even figured out the bounce
you got off different kinds of wood...
不同木材质地板的弹性
on college basketball courts.
他从早到晚都在做这些
He'd be working on this day and night.
他对他要下注的赌局
t若指掌
He knew everything about a game
he would bet on.
艾斯下了六千
我也跟下六千
Ace got down at $6,000.
Get me down at $6,000.
一季又一季…
NICKY: Season after season...
那小子是我唯一认识的绝对赢家
the prick was the only guaranteed winner
I ever knew.
但他那么认真下注…
But he was so serious about it all...
在我看来他从不放轻松享受享受
that I don't think he ever enjoyed himself.
但那就是他
But that's just the way he was.
当时，老大们也不会在乎他享不享受
Back then, the bosses didn't give a fuck
whether he enjoyed himself or not.
对他们而言，他像是棵摇钱树
To them, he was a cash register.
他们只要摇一摇就可拿钱
All they had to do was ring the bell
and take money.
尤其利蒙…
Especially Remo...
他是个逢赌必输的衰客
who was a fucking degenerate gambler
who always lost.
靠，这么多满贯
All those fucking sweeps.
-除非艾斯下注
-真是够了！
NICKY: Unless Ace made his bets.
Enough now!
艾斯一个周末为他们赚的钱…
NICKY: Ace made more money
for them on a weekend...
比我抢劫一个月的还多
than I could do heisting joints for a month.
艾斯将他听到的小道消息
都告诉了利蒙
Whatever Ace picked up on the street,
he told Remo.
内定的拳赛，下了药的马…
Fixed fights, doped horses...
买通的裁判，预定的分数
crooked fucking zebras,
locked-in point spreads.
他什么屁都告诉了利蒙
He told fucking Remo everything.
说真的，我也不能怪他
And, to tell you the truth, I don't blame him.
用钱财让利蒙快乐…
Keeping Remo happy with money...
是世上最好的保险
was the greatest insurance policy
in the world.
王八蛋！
Son of a bitch!
你怎么知道是
奥克拉荷马或密西根
How did you get Oklahoma-Michigan?
根本没人猜到奥克拉荷马
你是怎么办到的？
Nobody ever had Oklahoma....
How'd you do it?
所以他们才赔得高啊
That's why they paid so well.
你看吧？
什么都不跟我说
REMO: You see? Never tells me nothing.
下礼拜的怎么样？
What do we got on for next week?
现在还太早了
我得要星期四才知道，可以吗？
It's a little too early. I'll know
by Thursday. Is that all right?
-你会来家里吗？
-我会绕过来的
REMO: You'll come by the house?
SAM: I'll come by.
七点
At 7:00.
做得好，小子
继续啊
REMO: Good job, my boy. Keep it up.
嘿，尼克
REMO: Hey, Nick.
我马上去
I'll be right out.
看到那家伙了吗？好好看着他
See that guy? Keep a good eye on him.
他为我们赚了很多钱
He's making a lot of money for us.
他会继续为我们赚钱
所以你得好好看着他
And he'll continue making money for us,
so keep a good eye on him.
不像你外面那群没脑的政府官员
Not like the fucking Feds out there,
without brains.
-好吗？
-没问题
REMO: Okay?
NICKY: All right.
要我带走吗？
Want me to take this?
所以这么多事之外…
NICKY: Now, on top of everything else...
我还得担保
没人会动我们的大红人
I gotta make sure nobody fucks
with the Golden Jew.
帮小姐们倒几杯酒
Couple of shooters for the ladies.
我们真是好搭挡
SAM: Yeah, we made a great pair.
我下注而尼奇负责收钱
I made book and Nicky made sure
we always collected.
老头子们爱死我们了
The old men loved us, and why not?
他们全靠我们赚钱
They all made money with us.
尼奇怎么收钱？
How did Nicky collect?
别问
Don't ask.
钱他妈的在哪儿？
我没见到
Then where the fuck is the money?
I don't see it.
-你们好，玛莉莎，海蒂
-你好，山姆
-Hi, Melissa, Heidi.
-Hi, Sam.
那是谁？
Who's this guy?
-去你的，我下九
-是八
MAN: Get the fuck out. I laid nine.
NICKY: It was eight.
艾斯告诉他芝加哥小熊队的注
NICKY: Ace, tell him the line
on the Bears game.
-八
-他要不知道，就没人知道了
-Eight.
-If he don't know, nobody knows.
-是八
-那我怎么算成九？
NICKY: It was eight.
MAN: How come I laid nine?
因为你是个蠢才
'Cause you're a jag-off.
-对不起？
-什么？
-Excuse me.
-What?
-这是你的笔吗？
-是我的，怎样？
-Is this your pen?
-Yeah, that's my pen. Why?
很好看，我不知道是谁的
It's nice. I didn't know whose it was.
我不想它弄丢
I didn't want it to get lost.
谢谢
你为什么不拿那只笔…
Thank you.
Why don't you take that fucking pen...
捅到你屁眼里去，你这蠢才
and shove it up your ass,
you fucking jag-off?
-我只是…
-王八蛋
-Well, I was just offering--
-Asshole.
小心，乔
MAN: Look out, Joe.
[Woman shrieking]
[Nicky grunting]
[Man groaning in pain]
[Pop music continues]
那是什么？
你有没有听到女孩哭？
What's that? You hear a little girl?
是个小女孩吗？
Is that a little fucking girl?
刚叫我朋友捅什么的…
What happened to the tough guy...
那个硬汉呢？
who told my friend to stick it
up his fucking ass?
尼奇，够了
Nicky, take it easy.
[Man whimpering]
我还在想那人
为什么这么说时…
SAM: While I tried to figure out
why the guy said what he said...
尼奇就动手了
Nicky just hit him.
不管一个人多大个子
尼奇都会跟他拼命
No matter how big a guy might be,
Nicky would take him on.
你拿拳头打他
他就会拿球棒回你
You beat Nicky with fists,
he comes back with a bat.
你拿刀捅他
他就会用枪射你
You beat him with a knife,
he comes back with a gun.
你若拿枪射他
那你最好是杀了他…
If you beat him with a gun,
you'd better kill him...
因为他会一直不停的回来…
because he'll keep coming back and back...
直到你挂了为止
until one of you is dead.
[Pop music continues faintly]
由我保护艾斯…
NICKY: With me protecting Ace...
他为老大们狠狠赚了一票
he made a fortune for the bosses.
这就是他来赌城的原因
That's what got him to Vegas.
他根本就是印钞机
He was a money machine.
为这些家伙赚大钱
A tremendous earner for these guys.
他一来就把供金增加了一倍
As soon as he took over,
he doubled the fucking drop.
艾斯来后，赌场从就没见过
那么多的钱
With Ace, the casino never saw
so much money.
老大们当然是笑不拢嘴
And the bosses, they couldn't be happier.
[Rhythmic blues music]
在赌城，我还得跟附近有关系的
一些牛仔找事做
SAM: In Vegas, I had to keep
a few juiced-in local cowboys working.
他们与老家伙们很熟
They were close to the good old boys.
要不是我们
那些家伙现在都还在铲驴粪
Without us, these guys
would still be shoveling mule shit.
场子得保持干净
You've got to keep a cleaner station.
需要清洁工就呼叫他
If you need Mr. Clean, page him.
下次不会了，山姆
Won't happen again, Sam.
-罗斯坦先生
-下次不会了，罗斯坦先生
SAM: Mr. Rothstein.
MAN: It won't happen again, Mr. Rothstein.
这家伙又是一个蠢白人吗？
Is this guy just another dumb fucking
white man, or what?
-你需要他
-弄不走是吗？
-You need this guy.
-Can't get rid of him?
他有关系的
他是县辅导的表兄弟
He's juiced in.
He's the County Commissioner's cousin.
我连清洁工都不会给他做
SAM: I wouldn't give the bum a mop job.
别无选择，我必须照顾他们
I had no choice. I had to take care of them.
这些乡巴佬当权
These yokels ran the state.
多谢，议员
DEALER: Thanks, Senator.
-他们立法，又掌管法院
-我要开房间
SAM: They passed the laws,
owned the courts.
I need a room.
我每周都有十多个政客来访
SAM: I had dozens of politicians
and state officials coming through weekly.
-他要什么都给他
-当然
SAM: Get him what he wants.
BILLY: Certainly.
何不让他们快乐？
SAM: Why not make them happy?
[Upbeat R&B music]
对于政客
例如我们这位州议员…
For politicians,
like our State Senator up there...
一切都是免费的
everything was on the house.
他们的招待生涯
在当选时就赢得了
These guys won their comped life
when they got elected.
-=字幕:CHD720P代刻=-
何不加以利用？
Why not take advantage of it?
政客还是小事，我们解决的了
Still, the politicians came cheap.
We could handle them.
是像市川那种…
It's a whale, like K.K. Ichikawa...
百家乐一把下三万的豪赌客
who plays $30, 000 a hand in baccarat.
这种才该看紧
That's the one you really gotta watch.
他下注动作快，玩得大
他的资金雄厚…
He plays fast and big.
He has the cash and the credit...
足可把你玩垮
to turn out your lights.
一年前他让开曼群岛上
好几家赌场洗底
A year ago he cleaned out a couple
of casinos in the Cayman Islands.
他从赌场赢了我们两百万…
Downstairs he takes us for $2 million...
又从酒店套房拿了免费的
肥皂、洗发精与毛巾
and upstairs he takes free soap,
shampoo and towels.
又是一个
喜爱免费套房…
Another billionaire cheapskate
who loved his free rooms...
免费私人飞机又赚得我们两百万
的亿万富翁小气鬼
free private jets
and $2 million of our money.
我们也不好惹
But we got him back.
我让机师告诉他飞机故障
I had our pilot tell him
the plane was on the fritz.
-发生什么事？
-非常抱歉
ICHIKAWA: What went wrong?
BILLY: I'm awfully sorry.
是机械故障
These mechanical things happen.
在这儿总比在上面好
Better here than up there.
然后他赶不上回日本的飞机
SAM: Then he missed the flights
connecting with Japan.
竟然没有空房
I can't believe there's no room.
我们给了他一整楼的房间
SAM: We got him back with
a whole floor of rooms to himself.
-真抱歉让你赶不上飞机
-你想要赢回我的钱啊
-Sorry you missed your plane.
-You'd like some of my money back.
不，不赌了
Oh, no. No gambling.
[Upbeat R&B music]
他回来后开始下小注
SAM: And once he was back,
he played small.
一把只赌一千
而不是平常的三万一把
He bet $1,000 a hand,
instead of his usual $30,000 a hand.
但我知道这些豪赌客的习性…
But I knew the trick
with whales like Ichikawa...
他们不可能一直下小注的
was that they can't bet small for long.
他不觉得是赢一万…
He didn't think of it as winning $10, 000...
他会想成是输九万…
he thought of it as losing $90, 000.
所以他开始加码
So, he upped his bets.
直到他将赢得的输光
再加上自己一百万的现金
Until he dropped his winnings back
and gave up $1 million of his own cash.
在赌场里，第一原则就是
让他们一直赌…
In a casino, the cardinal rule
is to keep them playing...
也让他们一直回来
and keep them coming back.
赌得越多就输得越多
The longer they play, the more they lose.
最终钱就都是我们的
In the end, we get it all.
[Upbeat R&B music]
在赌城，每个人都得注意着别人
In Vegas, everybody's gotta watch
everybody else.
玩家是来赢赌场钱的…
Since the players
are looking to beat the casino...
庄家得看好玩家…
the dealers are watching the players...
收付赌注得看好庄家…
the boxmen are watching the dealers...
管场的注意着收付赌注的人…
the floormen are watching the boxmen...
赌区经理看着管场的…
the pit bosses are watching the floormen...
值班经理看着赌区经理…
the shift bosses are watching
the pit bosses...
赌场经理看着值班经理…
the casino manager is watching
the shift bosses...
我则看着赌场经理…
I'm watching the casino manager...
而监视照相机看着我们大家
and the eye in the sky is watching us all.
另外，还有十多个家伙…
Plus, we had a dozen guys...
大多以前都是老千
他们知道所有的骗术
most of them ex-cheats,
who knew every trick in the house.
[Upbeat R&B music continues]
好啊！
Yes!
-非常好
-我就跟你说我今天很旺
-Very nice.
-I told you I was hot tonight.
好样的
Looking good.
来吧，为了金吉儿，快
MAN: Let's go. This is for Ginger.
一百赌你没老A
MAN: Let me have $100 on your hard 10.
谢谢
Thank you.
来吧
MAN: Here we go now.
[Upbeat R&B music]
-对不起
-骰子
-Oh, I'm sorry.
-The dice.
多谢
Thank you very much.
多谢你
I appreciate that.
保重，史蒂夫
要冒险啊，开快车
Take care, Steve. Take chances, drive fast.
这一百给你，甜心
多谢你赏光
This $100 is for you, love.
Thanks for your time.
-快点
-怎么了？
-Come on.
-What's the matter?
我帮你赚了不少，我要我的份
I made a lot of money for you, I want my cut.
什么钱？我看到你偷钱
What money? I've seen you stealing.
“什么钱？”
你看看这堆筹码
"What money?" Look at the stack of chips.
-我要我的一半
-我观察你一夜了
GINGER: I want my half.
GAMBLER: I've watched you.
-我要我的钱
-你皮包里全是熟筹码
-I want my money.
-Your bag is full of chips.
-我才没偷你的东西
-滚吧！
GINGER: I didn't steal anything from you.
GAMBLER: Get lost!
-滚吧？
-没错！
GINGER: Get lost?
GAMBLER: Yes!
-这怎么样呢？
-别这样！
-Well, how about that?
-Come on!
[Upbeat R&B music continues]
[Romantic pop music]
真酷，让我一见钟情
SAM: What a move. I fell in love right there.
但在赌城，像金吉儿这样的女孩
得花上大钱
But in Vegas, for a girl like Ginger,
love costs money.
[Romantic rock music]
我去补个妆
I'm gonna go powder my nose.
-金吉儿的人生目标是钱
-马上回来
SAM: Ginger's mission in life was money.
I'll be right back.
-待会见，金吉儿
-多谢你
DOORMAN: See you.
GINGER: Thanks for asking.
她在赌场可是皇后
SAM: She was a queen around the casino.
她召来大赌客
并也帮他们花大钱
She brought in high rollers
and helped them spend a lot of money.
-你好
-嘿，金吉儿，你好吗？
-Hello.
-Hey, Ginger. How you doing?
好得很，一点小意思
你帮我搞定了吗？
GINGER: Great. You might have
something for me. Got me covered?
-非常感谢
-自己保重喔
GINGER: Thank you.
VALET: Take care of yourself.
我有些幸运丸给你，安迪
I got some lucky pills for you, Andy.
谁不想要金吉儿？
她是城里名声最响亮…
SAM: Who didn't want her?
She was one of the best known...
也是道上最受欢迎的江湖人物
best liked and most respected hustlers
in town.
像她这么聪明的玩家
可以让男人…
Smart hustlers like her
could keep a guy awake...
两三天不睡
然后再让他一文不名的…
for two or three days
before sending him home broke...
回到老婆与银行审查主任身边
to the little woman and his bank examiners.
[Romantic rock music continues]
有找钱吗？
Any change?
我回来时小赌了几把
Oh, I hit a few games on the way back.
那根本是胡扯
她把钱收起来了
SAM: But that was all bullshit.
She just pocketed the cash.
-你今天好吗？
-不错啊
GINGER: How you doing tonight?
CASHIER: Good.
-你呢？
-衰死了
CASHIER: How are you?
GINGER: Beat.
-金吉儿洞悉玩家们的习性
-给你一百
SAM: Ginger had the hustlers' code.
GINGER: Take one for you.
-多谢
-她懂得如何买通他人
CASHIER: Thank you.
SAM: She knew how to take care of people.
这就是赌城的座右铭
That's what Vegas is all about.
-六千八百元
-谢啦
CASHIER: $6,800.
GINGER: Thanks.
-这里是讲究回扣的城市
-晚安
SAM: It's kickback city.
GINGER: Have a good night.
她罩庄家…
SAM: She took care of the dealers...
赌区经理，管场经理…
pit bosses, floor managers...
但尤其关照停车小弟…
but, mostly, the valet parkers...
他们能帮你找到任何东西
也能帮你解决任何事
the guys who could get you anything
and take care of anything.
金吉儿搞定了停车的…
Ginger took care of the parkers...
他们搞定警卫
而警卫会摆平警察…
who took care of the security guards,
who took care of the cops...
-让她可继续开工
-我今晚需要那东西
who let her operate.
I need that stuff tonight.
-没问题
-你真好
VALET: No problem.
GINGER: You are a doll.
停车赚的钱多到…
SAM: The valet parking job
was such a money-maker...
得买通酒店经理才能排上空缺
they had to pay off the hotel manager
just to get the concession.
不过有一点我不懂…
But one thing I didn't understand...
她将一切都控制的好好的…
was that she had everything under control...
却被她那拉皮条的男友
莱丝特戴蒙德吃得死死的
except for her old pimp boyfriend,
Lester Diamond.
我得顾到其他人，我的搭挡们
I got other people in this. I got partners.
在这事上有我罩你，知道吗？
I'm looking out for you in this thing, okay?
你将获你应得的
而且第一个拿到，好吗？
You'll get yours back,
and you'll get it back first. Okay?
-好的
-你去哪儿了？
-All right.
-Where you going?
你在哪儿？
你又飘走了
Where are you? You're in that place.
-我在这儿
-不，你不在
-I'm here.
-No, you're not.
你在哪？
Where are you?
我永远在你身边
I'm always here for you.
-真的
-是啊
-You are.
-I am.
我所认识的金吉儿
根本不会多看这怪胎一眼
SAM: The Ginger I knew
wouldn't even look at this creep.
-祝你好运
-是啊
-Good luck.
-Yeah.
他是个老千，专作假牌…
SAM: He was a moocher, a card cheat...
老在高尔夫俱乐部招摇撞骗
一个瘪三…
a country club golf hustler, a scumbag...
-为了几块钱追着牙医屁股跑
-小心点
-chasing dentists for a few bucks.
-Careful.
他永远都没钱，永远都有藉口
SAM: He was always broke.
He always had a story.
不知为何，她却拒绝不了他
Somehow, she could never turn him down.
在金吉儿眼里，他只是运气不好
The way Ginger saw it
was that he was just an unlucky guy.
总得有人照顾他
Somebody had to take care of him.
在老家
BACK HOME
但尼奇可不需要人照顾
But nobody had to take care of Nicky.
你找到现金的话
我们就跟你平分
You find any cash in there,
we'll whack it up with you.
他把自己照顾得太好了
SAM: He took care of himself only too well.
这也是为什么老家的条子
都想抓他到案
That's why every badge back home
wanted to nail him.
我将这些都折得好好的
能不能放尊重点
I folded these things beautifully.
I would appreciate a little respect.
别看我，兄弟
我还得跟她同床共枕
Don't look at me, pal, I gotta live with her.
就连去渡个假
他们在机场时都不放过他
SAM: Even after a vacation,
they hassled him at the airport.
法兰克玛雷诺在那儿等他
条子们也在
Frank Marino was there to meet him.
So were the cops.
他们想逮他…
They wanted to pinch him...
-因为一宗在安特卫普的钻石窃案
-帮忙折吧
-for a diamond burglary in Antwerp.
-Help me fold these.
他们随时愿意嫁祸于他
不管是在哪儿发生什么事
SAM: They were ready to blame him
for anything, no matter where.
他们通常是对的
They were usually right.
因为尼奇很喜欢混帮派
Because Nicky enjoyed being a gangster.
他也不在乎有谁知道
And he didn't give a damn who knew it.
看看，美极了
GINGER: There we go. Look at that.
Beautiful!
让我担心的是…
SAM: I mean that's what worried me...
尼奇似乎要被派来拉斯维加斯
'cause it turns out,
Nicky was about to be sent to Vegas.
-好了，就这样
-还有
JENNIFER: All right, we're clear.
NICKY: There's more.
一定还有些卡在里面
NICKY: There's a couple stuck in there.
-我告诉你都拿出来了
-快
-I'm telling you, they're out!
-Come on.
别急于辩护
可能还有些卡在你头发里
Don't get so defensive,
it could be stuck in your hair.
那是什么？
What's that?
没有了，谢谢
There's no more. Thanks.
我迫不及待想去拉斯维加斯
NICKY: I couldn't wait
to get my hands on Vegas.
但老大可不是送我去玩的
But the bosses didn't send me out
to have a good time.
他们要我去确保
没人找艾斯的麻烦
They sent me out to make sure
that nobody fucked with Ace.
也确保没人干扰每月的抽头
And nobody interfered
with the fucking skim.
-嘿
-你好吗？
-Hey.
-Hey, how you doing?
嘿，山姆
Hey, Sammy.
-天呀，瞧瞧这地方
-不可思议
-Boy, look at this place.
-Incredible.
欢迎来赌城
SAM: Welcome to Vegas.
-好样的，山姆
-不错吧
NICKY: Okay, Sammy.
SAM: Something, huh?
金吉儿
Ginger.
靠，你都在这儿干嘛？
Holy shit. What've you been doing out here?
甜心，过来
SAM: Honey, come here.
这是珍妮佛与尼克
我的好朋友们
This is Jennifer and Nick.
They're dear friends of mine.
-你好，珍妮佛
-幸会
-Hi, Jennifer.
-A pleasure.
好样的，山姆
Okay, Sammy.
晚餐后，我们让珍妮佛
与金吉儿一块儿…
SAM: After we ate,
we left Jennifer and Ginger...
我们俩则出去谈话
and we took a ride to talk.
然后他对我丢了颗炸弹
And then, he hit me with it.
你觉得我也搬来如何？
What do you think
about me moving out here?
有问题吗？
You got a problem with that?
当然没有
No, of course not.
你是说你允许罗？
You mean I have your permission?
当然罗
但我得告诉你…
Sure, you do. But I just gotta tell you...
在这儿可不能开玩笑
it's no joke out here.
你得保持低调
You gotta keep a low profile.
不像是在老家
这儿他们不喜欢我们
It's not like back home.
They don't like guys like us.
警长是个不折不扣的牛仔
This sheriff's a real cowboy.
连巡警都不怕在沙漠里埋人
Even coppers aren't afraid
to bury people in the desert.
我不在乎
我只想离开老家一阵子
I don't care. I want to get away
from back home for a while.
我厌倦了那里
I'm tired of that shit back there.
看看这地方，简直是钱砌的
Look at this place. It's made of money.
知道最诺氖鞘裁矗
You know what the best part is?
没人知道我们在干嘛
Nobody's gonna know what we're doing.
没人看着我们，大家都在老家
There's nobody here to see us.
Everybody's back home.
我无缘故被逮了两次
I got pinched twice for no reason.
我真得小心了
I really gotta be careful.
我管理的地方是有执照的
全是合法的
I'm running a licensed place.
Everything's legit.
别担心，我什么都不会做的
Don't worry about it.
I'm not gonna do anything.
我尤其不会拖你下水
I'm especially not gonna involve you
in anything.
艾斯看赌城的观点…
NICKY: Ace saw Vegas one way...
-你跟他说过我要来吗？
-当然
NICKY: Call and tell him I'm coming?
JACK: Of course.
我的看法不同
...but I saw it another.
我视它为未开发的
I saw it as untouched.
多的是可勒索的赌马组头
皮条客与毒贩…
They had bookies, pimps,
and drug dealers I could shake down.
他们能找谁靠？
Who the fuck were they gonna run to?
我开始一个一个下手
So I started getting everybody in line.
最诺氖牵我这辈子第一次…
Best of all, for the first time in my life...
发觉了稳赢的方法
I figured out a way not to lose.
他是有个稳赢之计
SAM: He had a foolproof scheme.
虽然不高明，但起码行得通
It wasn't very scientific, but it worked.
他赢时就收钱
When he won, he collected.
输时就叫赌马组头去死
When he lost,
he told the bookies to fuck off.
他们能怎样？逼迫尼奇？
尼奇就是逼迫者
What were they gonna do? Muscle Nicky?
Nicky was the muscle.
-你好吗？
-Hey, how you doing?
-How you doing?
-你有东西给我吗？
-什么东西？
-You got that thing for me?
-What thing?
尼奇，我以为你是来下注的
Nicky, I thought you was laying.
下注？不，我来收钱
I was laying? No, I'm taking it.
-你确定？
-非常
-You sure?
-I'm positive.
-我搞混了
-你搞混了？
-I'm a little confused.
-You're a little confused?
或许在我把你的脸砸过这窗户后…
Maybe if I stick your fucking face
through this window...
你就会清楚点
you'll get unconfused.
-把钱他妈的给我
-对不起
-Give me the fucking money.
-I'm sorry.
我不是故意的
I didn't mean anything by it.
所以你连钱都准备好了
你他妈的以为我要下注
That's why you had it ready.
You thought I was laying it.
-我的头
-放聪明点
-My fucking head.
-Smarten up.
而现在尼可拉斯山多罗
要来跟我们说第一总统的故事了
And now Nicholas Santoro will come up
and tell us about our first President.
乔治华盛顿出生在…
George Washington was born--
但最起码还风平浪静了一阵子
SAM: But still, it was nice
and quiet for a while.
我们带着尼奇与珍妮佛满街亮相…
We presented Nicky and Jennifer
all over town...
像是明星似的
like regular Ozzie and Harriets.
你棒挥得很好
COACH: You got a beautiful swing.
艾斯让我儿子，小尼奇
参加市区青少棒，真的很好
NICKY: Ace got Little Nicky
involved with Little League. It was great.
结果其中的一位教练
是市立警察局情报单位的
Turned out that one of the other coaches
was a metro intelligence cop.
不过无所谓，这纯粹是孩子的事
But it didn't matter. It was all about the kids.
他得明白不是每棒都能挥出全垒打
He's gotta realize
everything can't be a home run.
我也是这样告诉他
不过那小子就是这样
That's exactly what I tell him,
but that's the kind of kid he is.
[People applauding]
尼奇就是尼奇
他总是引人注目
SAM: And Nicky being Nicky,
he made his presence known.
尤其是在他不工作的赌场
Especially at the casino
where he definitely did not work...
大家都明白
people got the message.
就是我，这也是老大为何派我来
NICKY: Me, that's why
the bosses sent me out here.
我是来确定
没有其他人在拿这儿的钱
I was to make sure no other crews
robbed the joint.
像在那边的那两个蠢才
Like these two fucking balloon heads
over here.
想从我们这儿骗走二十万
They were gonna try to bang us
out of $200, 000.
走着瞧
Yeah, right, I'm sure.
你好吗？你怎么会在这儿？
How are you? What are you doing here?
我到这儿来了
I'm over here now.
-到这儿来？
-是啊，跟他们一起
-You're over here?
-Yeah, I'm over here with them.
我们在等卡尔曼
We're waiting on Carmine.
是啊，在等卡尔曼
Yeah, we're looking for Carmine.
他本来在这儿
拿了口箱子后来就走了
He was here before.
He had a suitcase, and then he left.
卡尔曼走了？
Carmine left?
他走了吗？
He's gone?
他不在这儿？
He's not here?
他出去了？
Carmine's out?
他好像过了马路还是什么的
I think he went across the street
or somewhere else or something.
是喔，听着，祝你在这儿好运
Well, listen, good luck with the joint.
-谢啦，艾迪
-非常好运
-Thanks, Eddy.
-Lots of luck.
也祝你好运
Good luck to you, too.
他们忘了签名
CASHIER: They forgot to sign their papers.
他们不需要这个了
They don't need those anymore.
因为基本尊重
我只给别帮家伙一点警告
SAM: Out of respect, guys
from other crews got away with a warning.
其他的人可得小心了
Everybody else, watch out.
像这群乡巴佬…
Like these yokels here...
从没听过尼奇或他老家的老大们
who never heard of Nicky
or the bosses back home.
这种王八蛋最麻烦了
They're the morons
who give you the most trouble.
被我们抓到后又会溜回来…
We'd catch them
and they'd try to sneak back...
戴着假胡子、假发、假鼻子
with beards and wigs and fake noses.
只要看这些王八蛋下注的方式
你就可辨认他们
You can spot these assholes
by watching the way they bet.
像这家伙，以紫筹码下注…
Like this guy. He's betting lavender chips...
每次下五百，不过只有个小问题
at $500 each with only one little problem.
他每次都猜对
He's always guessed right.
要不是他这么贪心
可能还不会这么明显
If he wasn't so fucking greedy,
he'd have been tougher to spot.
不过到头来，他们每个都贪
But in the end, they're all greedy.
[Upbeat rock music]
我看到庄家很弱
但他们并不是一伙的
I saw that the dealer was weak,
but he wasn't in on it.
他只是没保护好自己的牌
He just wasn't protecting his hand.
他把底牌掀得太高了
He was lifting his hole card way too high.
有个家伙在看庄家的底牌…
Here's this guy
reading the dealer's hole card...
再对他坐在桌上的兄弟打手势
and signaling his buddy at this table.
[Metallic clicking]
这些在外混的就是这样
And that's just what these hustlers look for.
他们从一家赌场到另一家
找寻着弱庄家…
They cruise from casino to casino
looking for weak dealers...
像是狮子们找着弱小的羚羊
the way lions look for weak antelope.
接线生，这是罗先生
Operator, this is Mr. R.
立刻叫阿姆斯壮
与佛莱迪来二号赌台区
Get me Armstrong and Friday
over to Pit 2 right away.
[Upbeat rock music continues]
二十一点第十九桌
第二个位子的那个大胡子
BJ 19, second base, the beard.
接线生，来段生日快乐曲
要大声点
Operator, I need Mr. Happy. Loud.
祝你生日快乐
WAITRESSES: [Singing] Happy birthday
to you
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you
亲爱的杰夫
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday, dear Jeff
Happy birthday to you
[Electric zap]
有人倒下！
GUARD: Man down!
叫救护车，有人心脏病发
Go get medical.
We got a cardiac arrest here.
他没事了，大家
麻烦给我们一点空间
He's fine, folks.
Just give us some room, please.
他们根本搞不清状况
SAM: They never know what hit them.
若他们真的发现是被电击棒电到…
If and when they do find out
they got zapped by a cattle prod...
他们会希望自己其实是心脏病发
they wish they really did have a heart attack.
结果发现这两个家伙已在这儿
招摇撞骗好多年了
Turns out this guy and his fucking pals
were knocking this place dead for years.
-他身上有窃听器
-你在干嘛？
GUARD 1 : He's wired.
HUSTLER: What are you doing?
在那儿，就是它了
GUARD 1 : There it is. That's it.
-老千的正法
-我的天！
GUARD 2: Cheater's justice.
HUSTLER: Oh, God!
[Saw whirring]
不！
No!
我要所有人知道这儿跟以往不同了
SAM: I wanted everybody to
know that things were changed around here.
我们得用这些家伙来让大家知道
他们的好日子不长了
We had to make an example of these pricks
that the party was over.
我很好奇
I'm just curious.
我看到你用右手玩筹码
I saw you shuffling your checks
with your right hand.
-你两只手都可以这样吗？
-不
-Can you do that with both hands?
-No.
-不能用两只手吗？
-不能
SAM: You can't do it with both hands?
HUSTLER: No, sir.
-左手可以吗？
-我从没试过
-Can you do it with your left hand?
-I never tried.
-所以你是右撇子
-是
-So, you're a righty.
-Yeah.
那你现在得学习用左手罗
Now you're gonna have to learn
with your left hand.
-十万，不，十一万吧
-是啊
-It's $100,000, $1 10,000 I think.
-Yes, it is.
好的
Okay.
嗨
Hi.
在大庭广众数这么多钱
That's a lot of money
to be counting out in public.
为何不让我拿到办公室确认？
Why don't I take him
over to the office and verify it?
多一点隐私
A little privacy.
顺便叫一瓶好香槟来
By the way, send over
a nice bottle of champagne on ice.
-没问题
-要很特别的
CASHIER: Sure will.
BILLY: Real special.
对了，我是赌场经理
比利雪伯堤
By the way, I'm Billy Sherbert,
casino manager.
-还玩得愉快吗？
-是的
BILLY: Having a good time?
HUSTLER 2: Yes.
你在较有隐私的地方算比较好
You want to count the money in privacy.
我得赶飞机去克里夫兰
我可以领取我赢得的钱吗？
HUSTLER 2: I have a plane to catch.
Can I get my winnings?
看他们对我的手做了什么
Look what they did to my hand, man.
我给你一个选择
SAM: I'm gonna give you a choice:
你可以拿钱然后被锤头砸
或者是从这儿走出去
You can have the money and the hammer,
or you can walk out of here.
-你要哪个？
-我要走
-What do you want?
-I wanna get out of here.
告诉你那群朋友，他们若来乱搞
会发生什么事
Tell your friends what happens
if they fuck around here.
-对不起，我犯了大错
-你真他妈的说对了
-I'm sorry, I made a bad mistake.
-You're fucking right.
你们要是再敢回来
我会敲烂你们的头
SAM: If you come back, either one
of you, we'll break your fucking heads.
你看到那锯子没？不是放着好看的
我们不是在开玩笑
You see that fucking saw? We're gonna
use it. We don't fuck around here.
-懂吗？
-是
SAM: Got it?
HUSTLER 2: Yes.
-给我滚
-谢谢你
-Get out of here.
-Thank you.
把他丢到后街去
跟条子说他被车撞到了
Throw him out in the alley.
Tell the cops he got hit by a car.
不到一会儿，一切就都搞定了
SAM: Within no time,
everything was set in place.
我们弄走了那些老千
盈利上扬好多…
We got rid of the freelance scamsters,
the pro was way up...
上头老大高兴极了
the gods were happy,
or as happy as the gods can ever be.
然后我决定将生活复杂化
And I decided to complicate my life.
对不爱冒险的我来说…
For a guy who likes sure things...
我用我的下半辈子
下了笔胜算不大的赌注
I was about to bet the rest of my life
on a real long shot.
我们也不年轻了
We're not getting any younger.
你不觉得是时候了？
Don't you think it's time?
你对这些不厌烦吗？
这边睡、那边混？
Aren't you getting tired of all this shit?
Banging around, hustling around?
-你想要妨碍我吗？
-我想给你更好的
-Are you trying to handicap me?
-I'm gonna do you one better.
我想娶你进门
I'm trying to marry you.
你想嫁我吗？
SAM: You wanna marry me?
我说真的
SAM: I'm serious.
我想定下来，想有个家
I wanna settle down. I want a family.
你找错人了，山姆
You got the wrong girl, Sam.
我会是个好爸爸
你也将是个好妈妈
I'd be a good father,
you'd be a good mother.
你不知道我
You don't know me.
你才认识我两、三个月
你了解什么？
You've known me two, three months.
What do you know?
我已经43岁了，我不想再等了
I'm 43 years old. I don't want to wait.
我对你的了解深到
令我自己知道我非常爱你
I know you well enough
to know that I really love you very much.
你是我心目中最理想的人
I can't think of anybody better to be with.
我不想再等了
I don't feel like waiting anymore.
你见过很多婚姻美满的人吗？
我可没见过
You know a lot of happily married people?
'Cause I don't.
这我都懂
I know all that.
[Sighs]
我在乎你
I care about you.
但我对你没有那种感觉
But I just don't have
those kind of feelings for you.
对不起，我并不爱你
I'm sorry. I'm not in love with you.
-好的
-懂吗？
SAM: All right.
GINGER: Understand?
对不起
GINGER: I'm sorry.
不…
No....
那可以培养
That can grow.
只要互相尊重
感情是可以培养的
As long as there's a mutual respect,
that kind of thing can grow.
我很现实，我可以接受
I'm realistic. I can accept that.
爱到底是什么？
SAM: What is love anyway?
不就是互相尊重
不就是一心一意
SAM: It's a mutual respect. It's a devotion.
是一个人在乎另一个人
It's a caring from one person to another.
若我们可以设立一个基础…
And if we could set up
some kind of foundation...
以相互尊重为底…
based on that mutual respect...
我觉得迟早你会对我有情…
I feel that eventually
you would care enough about me...
这样我能接受
that I could live with that.
若行不通的话…
If it doesn't work out...
若行不通的话
那我怎么办？
if it doesn't play out,
then what happens to me?
我现在做得不错
往后会越来越好
I'm doing well now.
I'm gonna do even better.
不论如何…
So whatever happens...
就算我们俩行不通…
if it doesn't work out between us...
我都会确保你下半辈子的生活
I'll make sure you're okay
for the rest of your life.
尤其如果有了孩子…
If there are kids, especially...
我会给你今生最好的照料
I'll take care of you better
than you'd imagine.
-你葫芦到底卖什么药？
-我都明讲了
GINGER: What are you pitching me?
SAM: Just what I said.
你下半辈子都不用愁
You'll be set up for the rest of your life.
这我可保证
That I can promise you.
要不要试试？
Want to take a chance?
[Applause and clinking glasses]
[Romantic instrumental music]
我娶金吉儿时就听过她的一切往事…
SAM: When I married Ginger,
I knew all the stories...
但我不在乎
我是山姆罗斯坦
but I didn't give a fuck.
I'm Sam Rothstein, I said.
我能改变她
I can change her.
这是典型的艾斯
NICKY: It was typical Ace.
他请了城里所有的大人物
他知道他们都会出席
He invited the biggest people in town.
He knew they'd show.
他知道他们都有求于他
He knew they all wanted
something from him.
艾斯绝对不可能不求回报
连金吉儿也不例外
With Ace, nobody ever got a free ride.
Even Ginger.
一切还是依他行事
With her, he still covered his bets.
他们在结婚前得先有孩子
They had to have the baby first,
before they could get married.
他甚至还托我们帮忙看艾美几天…
He even made us watch Amy
for a few days...
好让他们去渡蜜月
when they went on their honeymoon.
无所谓啊
我们爱死那孩子
I didn't mind, we loved the kid.
你感到我的眼神？
LESTER: Can you feel my eyes on you?
你感到我看透你的心吗？
Can you feel me look into your heart?
你能感到我躺在你肚皮上吗？
Can you feel me in the pit of your stomach?
你能在体内感受我？
Can you feel me in you?
在心里？
In your heart?
别等我过去
Don't make me come there.
回答我
Answer me.
我爱你
GINGER: [Crying] I love you.
宝贝，你知道我也爱你吗？
Baby, do you know that I love you, too?
-不，莱斯特
-你知道吗？
GINGER: No, Lester.
LESTER: Do you know that?
知道
GINGER: Yes.
这是我目前能为自己做的
最好的事
This is the best thing I can do
for my life right now.
没错
That's right.
所以会没事的
So it's going to be okay.
你发誓？
Promise?
我希望你幸福
I wish you all the luck in the world.
-真的？
-是，我真的这么想
GINGER: You do?
LESTER: Yeah, I do.
这是你目前能做的最好的事
It's the best thing you can do right now.
我说真的
I mean this.
你生活会很安稳
You have real security.
甜心，你将坐在赌城最有利的位子
Sweetheart, you're gonna be situated
just right in Vegas.
这对我们来说再好不过了
Come on. This is great for us.
我会一直都在你身边的
我哪儿都不会去
I'm always gonna be here for you.
I ain't going no place.
我现在就在看着你
I'm looking at you right now.
仿佛生平第一次见到你似的
I'm seeing you for the very first time,
right this minute.
我可听到我的心悸动
I'm saying I can feel my heart click.
我看到你十四岁时
I see you 14 years old.
我在见你的第一秒就看到你了
I see you the first second I ever saw you.
我看到你，像匹长腿的小马儿…
I see you, long-legged little colt...
还戴着蠢蠢的牙套
stupid braces on your teeth.
-好吧
-我每次见你时都看到这些
Okay, then.
LESTER: Every time I see you,
that's what I see.
再聊罗，再见
Talk to you later. Bye.
-你还好吗？
-嗯
-You all right?
-Yeah.
为什么哭？
Why are you crying?
我没有哭
I'm not crying.
-别喝这么多了吧
-我没事
-Maybe you shouldn't drink so much.
-I'm okay.
[Ginger sniffles]
希望你能理解
You just have to understand.
我自小就跟莱斯特在一起
I've been with Lester since I was a kid.
我只是想道别
I just wanted to say goodbye.
我只是…
I just....
我想我有权这样做
I think I have a right to do that.
好吗？
GINGER: Okay?
没关系
It's all right.
你那段人生已经完结了
That part of your life is over with.
-不是吗？
-是的
SAM: Right?
GINGER: Yeah.
你现在跟我
You're with me now.
-是的
-不是吗？
-Yeah.
-Right?
-你确定吗？
-是的
SAM: You're sure?
GINGER: Yeah.
-要走了吗？我们回去吧
-好的
SAM: Want to go? Let's go back in.
GINGER: Okay.
[Soothing instrumental music]
很好
GINGER: It's great.
[Soothing music continues]
[Ginger exclaims in delight]
都是我的东西，天呀
GINGER: It's all my stuff. Oh, my God.
你把我的东西都带来了！
You brought all my stuff!
我不能…
I can't....
试试看，这是你的
Try it on. It's yours.
别开玩笑了
You're kidding.
我的天
My God.
-是什么毛？
-是龙猫
-What is it?
-It's chinchilla.
好软喔
It's so soft.
很好喔？
Nice, isn't it?
从没有人对我这么好
No one's ever been so nice to me.
[Exclaiming]
我的老天！
GINGER: Oh, my God!
我要是在同一天将它们全都戴上
会不会太过火啊？
Do you think it's too much
if I wear these all on the same day?
你想怎样就怎样
You can do whatever you want.
我有没有实现我的诺言啊？
Do I keep my promises
or do I keep my promises?
你太好了
这些珠宝也不错
You're so wonderful.
The jewelry's not so bad either.
我们不应该把这些放在家里
应该摆到银行去
We shouldn't keep this in the house.
We gotta put it in the bank.
我不能留一副在家吗？
Come on. Can I keep this one in the house?
仔细听好
Pay attention to me.
我要告诉你一件重要的事
What I'm gonna tell you is very important.
这全部都不算什么
All this stuff doesn't mean anything.
钱财珠宝
如果没有信任就毫无意义
Money, this, doesn't
mean anything without trust.
我得要信任你到可将生命交给你
I have to be able to trust you with my life.
洛杉矶
总价值超过一百万的现金与珠宝
锁在赌城的银行里…
SAM: With over $1 million in
cash and jewels tucked in a bank in Vegas...
全归她所有
金吉儿非常有安全感
only for Ginger, she was secure and happy.
她最爱那些
She loved that shit.
但在我这行里
手上得有许多流动的现金
But a guy in my line of work
has to have a lot of payoff cash around.
贪污的条子与绑匪
他们都不收支票
Crooked cops and kidnappers,
they don't take checks.
考林先生，需要帮忙吗？
Need any help with that, Mr. Collins?
所以我在洛杉矶的银行里
也摆了两百万…
SAM: So I put $2 million cash
in a Los Angeles bank...
用考林先生与夫人的名义
under the name
of Mr. and Mrs. Tom Collins.
这纯粹是我个人的赎金与保金
This was strictly
my shakedown and kidnapping money.
因为在我最需要这笔钱时
我不是蹲在牢里就是被关在衣柜…
Since I'd be in jail or locked in a closet
when I needed the money most...
所以我将这笔钱唯一的钥匙
给了金吉儿好让我能保命
I gave Ginger the only key to the cash
that could get me back alive.
[Upbeat pop music]
这是签名卡
This is just a signature card.
她签了之后就会是世上…
Once she signs, she'll be the only person...
唯一可以开保险箱的人
连我都开启不了？
to have total access to the box,
no one else, including myself?
是的，这是你的要求
BANKER: That's right. That's the way
you wanted it.
山姆，我问你个问题
Sam, let me ask you a question.
你一定很信任你老婆
You must really trust your wife.
是啊，怎么啦？
Sure I do. Why?
很好啊，只是很少见
It's good. It's just unusual.
实不相瞒
我有很多客户都不信任
To tell you the truth,
so many of my clients don't.
[Singing romantic ballad]
将金吉儿还有钱的事解决后
我安心多了
SAM: With Ginger and the money
in place, I felt covered.
为了安全起见，我又将头衔…
To play it safe, I switched job titles again...
换成餐饮董事
and made myself
Food and Beverage Director.
这样一来就没人可以
为执照的事找我麻烦
This way nobody would bother me
about a license.
赌城对我来说像是个梦
Vegas was like a dream for me.
问题是尼奇也梦想着
他自己的赌城
Trouble was Nicky was dreaming
of his own kind of Vegas.
我将钱放出，每天三分利
NICKY: I put money out on the street
charging three points a week.
庄家高利贷
Juice to the dealers.
-别逼我们找上门
-你不会需要这样的
-Don't make us look for you.
-You won't have to look for me.
多谢了，尼奇
I appreciate it. Thanks, Nicky.
他们不是烂赌鬼就是烂毒鬼
NICKY: They were degenerate
gamblers, coke freaks.
没多久，坦吉乐一半的庄家
都在我手掌心里
In no time, I had half the dealers
in the Tangiers in my pocket.
下一步，我开始出千骗大赌客的钱
Then, the next thing I did, I started
busting out high-stakes poker players.
好明显
SAM: It was so obvious.
尼奇所有的小把戏
全都是靠手势
All of Nicky's half-assed mechanics,
they were signal-happy.
我下五百
I'm gonna open for $500.
互相打手势
SAM: Signaling back and forth.
[Gamblers chattering]
尼奇以为没人注意到他
但是他错了
Nicky thought nobody was watching him.
But he was wrong.
我不想要那些探员在我的地盘
I didn't want any of those agents
near my place.
-四条A
-我不相信
-Four aces.
-I can't believe this.
我唯一的运气好像就是手气背
GAMBLER 2: If I didn't have bad luck,
I wouldn't have any luck.
我真希望尼奇与他那票人
可以马上消失
SAM: I wished Nicky and his whole crew
would just get lost.
但我能怎样？
回老家去挑起场战争？
What am I gonna do?
Go back home and start a war?
尼奇在帮里算是有头有脸的人物
我不能那么做
Nicky's a made guy and I'm not.
I can't do that.
到处都是赌博游乐公会的探员
Gaming agents are all over the place.
这儿不允许手气旺的人吗？
I'm not allowed to get lucky in this place?
你已经旺了一个礼拜了
他们在找机会逮你
You've been lucky all week.
They're looking to nail you.
艾斯太在意他的赌场…
NICKY: Ace was so worried
about his casino...
他忘了我们当初为什么而来
he forgot what we were doing out here
in the first place.
最少有一百万次
我都好想在他耳边大喊…
A million times,
I wanted to yell in his fucking ear:
这儿是拉斯维加斯
"This is Las Vegas.
“我们本来就是来抢钱的
你这个蠢犹太人”
"We're supposed to be out here robbing,
you dumb fucking hebe. "
[Lively pop music playing]
我才不在乎他有什么关系
I don't give a shit who he's connected to.
叫他把脚从桌上拿下来
Tell him to take his feet off the table.
他以为这儿是什么廉价的地方？
Does he think
this is a goddamn sawdust joint?
先生，麻烦你将脚放下…
Sir, would you mind
taking your feet off the table...
并将鞋穿上，好吗？
and put your shoes on, please?
是，是很麻烦
我今天已经够背了
Yeah, I would mind. I'm having a bad night.
那王八蛋动都不动
Fucking asshole won't budge.
叫警卫
Call security.
你好吗？
How are you?
好，你呢？
Good. How are you?
给个面子，把你的脚放下去
然后把鞋穿上好吗？
Do me a favor. Want to take your feet off
the table and put your shoes on?
去你的
Fuck you.
我要你把这家伙从赌场架着丢出去…
I want you to exit this guy
off the premises, off his feet...
用他的头来开门
and use his head to open the fucking door.
先生，你得离开
麻烦你跟我们出去
Sir, you're gonna have to leave.
You mind coming with us outside?
妈的，我哪儿都不跟你去
Bullshit. I ain't going anywhere with you.
-妈的，你给我滚
-去你的！
GUARD: Bullshit. You're out of here.
MAN: Fuck you!
你知道你在招惹谁吗？
你知道吗？
MAN: You know who you're fucking with?
Do you?
你他妈的王八蛋！
你知道你招惹了谁吗？
You fucking faggot!
Do you know who you're fucking with?
别碰我！
MAN: Leave me alone!
-喂！
-别闹了！
GUARD: Come on!
MAN: You gotta be kidding me!
不出所料，我一小时后就接到电话
SAM: Sure enough, an hour later,
I get the call.
艾斯，那边怎么了？
你知道那家伙是跟我的吗？
Ace, what happened over there?
Did you know that guy was with me?
我不知道，你知道他做了什么吗？
I didn't know that. You know what he did?
我很有礼貌的走过去
他却叫我回家吃自已
I walked over to him politely,
and he tells me to fuck myself.
-还骂我是臭玻璃
-什么？
SAM: Then he called me a faggot.
NICKY: What?
-我把那王八蛋踢出去了
-过来
SAM: I threw that cocksucker out.
NICKY: Come here.
你骂我的朋友臭玻璃
还叫他回家吃自己？
You called my friend a faggot?
Told him to go fuck himself?
你这样说？
叫他回家吃自己？
Is that what you did?
Tell him to go fuck himself?
你这个死乡巴佬！
NICKY: [On phone] You fucking hick, you!
你给我过去道歉
NICKY: You go over there. You apologize.
你最好求他让你进去
NICKY: You better hope he lets you back in.
你要再敢没大没小
我会将你的头打到…
If you get out of line again,
I'll smash your head so hard...
你连那牛仔帽都戴不上
死乡巴佬
you won't be able
to get that cowboy hat on. Fucking hick.
听着，这家伙压根就不知道
自己在跟谁说话
Listen, this guy obviously doesn't know
who he was talking to.
他不知道我们是好兄弟
He doesn't know that we're dear friends.
他非常抱歉
He's already very sorry.
但如果你可买我个面子
让他再进去…
But if you could do me a favor
and let him back in...
我发誓他再也不会乱来
I swear he'll never get out of line again.
若他再敢乱来，就别想再踏进这儿
If he does it again, he's out for good.
我永远都不会再让他进门
I'll never let him in the place again.
真是对不起
NICKY: I'm sorry about this.
好吗，艾斯？
谢了，兄弟
All right, Ace? Thanks, pal.
你把鞋都脱了？
把脚放在桌上？
You took your boots off?
You put your feet on the table?
你这全身马粪骚的混蛋！
You shit-kicking, stinky,
horse-manure-smelling motherfucker, you!
你要敢再去丢我的脸
我会在沙漠里将你埋了
You fuck me up over there,
I'll stick you in a hole in the desert.
-快给我去道歉
-尼奇，对不起
NICKY: Go over and apologize.
MAN: Nicky, I'm sorry.
艾斯可是个很敏感的人
NICKY: Ace could be a very touchy guy.
尤其是当他在城里越来越出名后
Especially when he got bigger in town.
像他将强纳森与大卫
从凯撒宫挖角来时…
Like when he hired Jonathan and David
away from the Palace...
他为他们盖了全新的舞台
还给了他们一人一辆劳斯莱斯
by building them a new stage
and giving them a silver Rolls-Royce.
但我得说
他真的知道怎么吸引群众
But, I tell you,
he knew how to bring in the crowds.
他懂得一切门路
He knew all the fucking angles.
他将整个蛇蝎美人的秀
从巴黎搬来…
He brought the whole Femme Fatale show
from Paris...
但他却忘记那些欧洲跳舞妹有多懒
but he forgot how lazy them
European dancing broads can get.
他还得每周为她们秤体重
她们的身材才不至于像吹气球
He had to weigh them once a week
so they wouldn't blow up like balloons.
你还是4公斤过重
You're still eight pounds over.
-为什么会这样？
-罗斯坦您…
-What's the reason for this?
-Mr. Rothstein, sir--
别在那儿您了
她为什么会超重4公斤？
Never mind the "sir."
Why is she eight pounds over?
我只是尊重您
I'm trying to use respect.
罗斯坦先生就可以了
Mr. Rothstein is good enough for you.
嗯，有时当你给她们
太多的压力…
Well, sometimes when you put
that pressure point on them--
你只需要给我答案
给我正确答案就好
All you do is give me answers.
Just give me the right answer.
我不知道，她害怕要是不减肥
她就会被解雇
I don't know why. She's frightened
if she doesn't lose weight she'll get fired.
没错，她会被解雇
送她回巴黎…
That's right, she will get fired.
Send her back to Paris--
-我们一贯的做法是…
-停
-It's been our policy--
-Stop everything.
-她很出名
-这就是问题，她太懒散
AGENT: She's an institution.
SAM: That's the problem. She's lazy.
我得佩服这家伙
NICKY: I gotta give the guy credit.
我的意思是
他做了最明显的事
I mean, he does the most obvious thing.
这里是全国唯一可以合法签注的地方
This is the only town in the country
where a bookie joint is legit.
为什么不加以利用呢？
So why not take advantage, right?
所以他把签注从街上…
So he took bookie joints off the street...
开到赌场内
and opened them up inside the casino.
没几年后…
Within a few years, he had...
精华地段的每家赌场都想抄袭他
every casino on The Strip
trying to copy off of him.
我的创意…
SAM: Between my innovations...
加上尼奇对工作的投入…
and Nicky's dedication to his job...
我的赌场很快就成为
精华地段中最好的赌场
I soon had the best operation on The Strip.
小心点，你最近很引人注目
Watch yourself. There's a lot of heat on you.
怎么，有人抱怨吗？
Why, somebody is complaining?
我从警卫那儿听来的
他们以前都曾是警察
I'm hearing things from security.
They're all ex-cops.
警长已将你放入黑名单了
The sheriff wants to put you
in the Black Book.
那黑名单根本就是个屁
That Black Book is a bunch of bullshit.
全国只有两个人的名字在里面
There's two names in it
for the whole country...
教父艾尔卡邦就是其中之一
and one of them is still Al Capone.
你上了名单麻烦就大了
They put you in that book,
you're gonna be in trouble.
你将进不了赌场
You won't be able to walk into a casino.
我只不过是在养家活口罢了
I'm trying to make a living, that's all.
我只是跟你讲一声
别说我没警告你
I'm just telling you.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
[Upbeat swing music]
罗斯坦夫人，请看前面
很好，谢谢你
PHOTOGRAPHER: Mrs. Rothstein,
straight ahead. Very nice. Thank you.
[People chattering]
因他的努力与认真…
PHILIP: For his hard work and dedication...
与他为拉斯维加斯带来的新生命…
and the new life blood
he has instilled in Las Vegas...
山姆将自己建立为赌博游乐业界…
Sam has established himself
as an indispensable member...
不可缺乏的成员
of the gaming community.
以坦吉乐赌博游乐集团
董事长的名义…
As the head of
the Tangiers Gaming Corporation...
我很容幸为你们介绍
山姆罗斯坦…
it's my pleasure to welcome
Sam Rothstein...
维加斯谷乡村俱乐部新成员
to the Vegas Valley Country Club.
[Applause]
嘉许状
要是在老家，我所做的
早就让我蹲牢房去了
SAM: Back home, they'd put me in jail
for what I'm doing.
但在这儿，他们却颁奖给我
But out here, they're giving me awards.
我很荣幸能获得…
It is with great pleasure that I accept
this certificate of appreciation...
拉斯维加斯慈善基金会
颁发的嘉许奖状
from the Charitable Foundations
of Greater Las Vegas.
恭喜你，甜心
Congratulations, sweetheart.
山姆募得了有史来
最多的捐款
Sam raised more than
we've ever raised before.
但我最爱的还是看着我老婆
金吉儿周旋全场
SAM: But my greatest pleasure
was watching my wife work the room.
他们爱死她了
但你又怎能不爱她？
They all loved her.
How could you not love her?
她是世上最有魅力的女人
She could be the most charming woman
you ever saw.
人们都喜欢在她身边
People loved to be around her.
你一定得带艾美来参加
莎夏的生日派对
You've got to bring Amy
to Sasha's birthday party.
星期六下午三点
我们很希望她能来
LADY: We'd love to have her there.
3:00, Saturday.
-好的
-太好了
-Yes, okay.
-Great.
她让大家都开心
SAM: She made everybody feel good.
-恭喜你，山姆
-谢谢
-Congratulations, Sam.
-Thanks.
嗨，罗斯坦夫人，你好吗？
Hello, Mrs. Rothstein. How are you?
你是我见过最美丽的女人
罗斯坦先生，你真是个幸运的男人
You're one of the most gorgeous women
I've seen. You're a lucky man, Mr. Rothstein.
多谢夸奖
Thanks for that compliment.
他是赌场里的小伙子
挺好又聪明的小子
SAM: He was a young kid
from the casino. Nice kid. Bright boy.
这小子真他妈的带种
我第二天就炒了他
What balls on this fucking kid.
The next day I fired him.
金吉儿对人就是有这种魅力
她甚至鼓励他们这样
Ginger had that effect on people.
I think she even encouraged them.
你想看看这件吗？
GINGER: Do you wanna see this one?
[Ginger exclaims]
爸爸帮我买了这么多珠宝
因为他好爱我
GINGER: Daddy gave me all this jewelry
because he loves me so much.
但不管他们多爱她…
SAM: But as much as they loved her...
真美丽
GINGER: Fabulous.
他们都不知道什么让她感动
...they didn't know what really moved her.
看看这个
GINGER: Look at this.
爸爸给我的…
GINGER: Daddy gave me....
金吉儿快快乐乐的
我才能专心去做我所专长的…
SAM: With Ginger happy, I was
able to concentrate on what I knew best.
较松的机器都在后面
Loose machines are right back over there.
它们在那儿干嘛？
看都看不到
What are they doing back there?
You can't even see them.
好吧
Okay.
那最大累积奖金的那些呢？
What about the progressives
with the high jackpots?
这些是我们最好的机子
都是靠它们
These are our best machines.
They bring all the action.
难怪盈收变少了
重头戏都在前面
No wonder the drop is off.
The action is in the front.
-摆到前面去
-好的，我会
-Bring them up front.
-All right, I will.
听好了
在这有三种做事方法
Listen carefully.
There are three ways of doing things here.
正确的、不正确的
和我的方法
The right way, the wrong way,
and the way that I do it.
-懂了没？
-我懂了，马上去办
-Understand?
-I do understand. I'll get right on it.
-谢谢
-别谢我，去做就是了
-Thank you.
-Don't thank me. Just do it.
你是吃角子老虎机的经理
我不应该还需要告诉你这些
You're the slots manager.
I shouldn't have to tell you this.
唉，你说得真对
真是抱歉
Dang, you are right. I'm so sorry.
我一天得工作18个小时
SAM: So I ended up working 18-hour days.
金吉儿反倒是成为
真正享受赌城的人
Ginger was the one who wound up
enjoying the best of Vegas.
请跟我来，我带您去更好的桌
Come with me, please.
I have a better table for you.
你到底跟那王八蛋说了些什么？
What did you say
to that fucking jerk, anyway?
我跟她说我是罗斯坦夫人
I told him that I was Mrs. Sam Rothstein.
当然得加以利用罗
You might as well get something out of it.
不久后我所担心的事就发生了
SAM: It wasn't long before what I was afraid
was gonna happen, happened.
尼奇把自己搞到成为
全赌城的拒绝往来户
Nicky managed to get himself banned
from every casino in Vegas.
闲置马刺-97公里到拉斯维加斯
从那时起，我在赌城完全不能
被人看见与他交谈
From then on, I couldn't be seen talking
to him anywhere in or near Vegas.
这他妈的是什么意思？
NICKY: What the fuck is
that supposed to mean?
因对业者有害…
"...detrimental to gaming and...
“他将被禁止进入
拉斯维加斯中任何赌场”
"he will be ejected from
any casino in Las Vegas.
“违反此规的赌场
在他每次出现时…”
"And the casinos can be fined
as much as $100,000...
“都将被罚款逾十万元”
"every time he shows up."
-你相信吗？
-是啊，你被禁了
-You believe this shit?
-Yeah, you got banned.
“因为众所周知的恶名昭彰”
"Because of notorious
and unsavory reputation."
那些混蛋
Motherfucker.
[Nostalgic country music]
-有什么可摆平的方法吗？
-不，没办法
-Is there any way around this?
-No, there's no way.
例如说…
Let's say, for instance...
我去了家刚好就附设赌场的餐厅…
I want to go into the restaurant,
which happens to be in the casino...
为了想吃它的三明治呢？
to get one of those sandwiches I like?
别想了，你连停车场都踏不进去
Forget it. You can't even
set foot in the parking lot.
就是这么严重
That's how serious it is.
-换句话说，我玩完了？
-换几句话都是这意思
-in other words, I'm fucked?
-in so many words, yes.
他完全都没了解那黑名单的意义
SAM: It didn't sink into his head
about the Black Book and what it meant.
不能进赌场只是其一…
Not being able to go into a casino
is just one thing...
这名单会将你的名字刻在
每一个联邦调查员的脑海里
but being in this book etched your name
into the brains of every cop and FBI agent.
你与芝加哥教父是一样的
但尼奇不在乎
You're listed in there with Al Capone.
But Nicky didn't care.
我得想想办法
他们赶不走我的
I gotta do something.
They ain't getting rid of me.
他们赶不走我的
我要待在这儿，去他们的
They're not getting rid of me.
I'm staying here. Fuck them.
所以他们一开始这鸟规矩…
NICKY: So once they pulled that shit...
我就开始做自己突发奇想的事情
I started doing my own things in Vegas
nobody had thought of doing.
为了多点眼线
我将我弟弟与些恶汉从老家带来…
To keep an eye on things, I brought in
my kid brother and some desperados...
开始抢劫一些赌场豪客、赌场老大…
from back home and started knocking over
high rollers, casino bosses...
下注组头等等，全部一网打尽
bookmakers, anybody right here in town.
说真的，我这队人马还真是不错
I had a good fucking crew going for me,
I'll tell you that.
我有沙尔福斯寇
最擅长从二楼进屋偷东西
I had Sal Fusco, a great second-story guy.
杰克哈迪在被关六年前
曾在保险箱制造公司工作
Jack Hardy worked for a safe company
before he did a six-year bit.
还有本尼布卢
这家伙不论什么警铃都能解除
Then there was Bernie Blue.
This guy could bypass any alarm for me.
就像以前一样
It was like old times.
我也开了自己的珠宝店
叫做掏金热潮
I opened up my own jewelry store, too.
The Gold Rush.
有时我会为了刺激好玩
而参与偷窃
Sometimes I used to go along on a heist,
just for the fun of it.
我不喜欢被我偷的人看着我…
I didn't like the people
I was ripping off looking at me...
所以我都将他们的照片转过去
so I turned their fucking pictures around.
-为什么这么久？
-这东西真他妈的！
NICKY: What's taking so long?
JACK: This is a motherfucker!
-在动了
-学会怎么开就不用整个搬走了
It's working.
NICKY: Learn to open these
instead of taking them.
这些宝石的瑕疵真多
NICKY: These stones got
a lot of niggers in them.
那该死的皮皮要是私下偷换钻石…
If that fucking Pepe's
switching stones on us...
他最好给我骑骆驼回奈及利亚
he better take a fucking camel
back to Nigeria.
[Phone rings]
-他们在总统套房K
-单独登记吗？
-They're in Penthouse "K."
-Check in alone?
-是的
-他们出去了吗？
-They checked in alone.
-Are they out now?
-是，别担心
-好的，谢啦
-Yes. Don't worry.
-All right. Thanks.
我们在整城里都有线民
从旅馆侍者…
SAM: He had tipsters
all over town. Bellmen...
-得快点
-好的
-You got to hurry.
-Okay.
-停车小弟…
-他们正在登记
-...valet parkers...
-They're just checking in now.
-我会告诉他
-赌区经理…
-I'll tell him.
-...pit bosses...
在西洛可的1230房
Room 1230 at the Scirocco.
-1230房，收到
-还有秘书
-1 230. Right.
-...secretaries.
-完美状况的硬币
-完美状况吗？收到
-Mint condition coins.
-Mint condition? All right.
他们当然都有一份
SAM: They all got a piece of the score.
车来了
MAN: Car's coming.
[Energetic rock music]
他们都很谨慎
SAM: They were very careful.
他们每次都先解除警铃
要不然…
They always bypassed the alarms,
or else, if not...
就在墙上打洞然后凿墙而入
they'd drill enough holes to knock through
the walls with a sledgehammer.
尼奇能偷的都偷了
Nicky was grabbing everything he could.
外头根本没有人想到
会有像他那样的人
Nobody out there was expecting
a guy like him.
对尼奇来说
拉斯维加斯就像是蛮荒西部
For Nicky,
Las Vegas was the fucking Wild West.
我才刚拿到一批从以色列来的钻石
I just got a shipment of diamonds
from Israel.
他们他妈的想要我怎样？
我得赚钱，不是吗？
NICKY: What the fuck did they
expect from me? I had to earn, didn't I?
-这些钻石有瑕疵
-没有瑕疵
-This diamond has flaws in it.
-There's no flaws in it.
别告诉我怎么做
我在这行已经25年了
Don't tell me. I'm doing this for 25 years.
你的放大镜最好擦干净点
因为这批钻石没有瑕疵
You better clean your loupe,
because there's no flaws in this diamond.
通常要是附近来的货…
NICKY: When we got local merch...
我们都会送到棕榈泉市
或是亚利桑那州与洛杉矶
we'd usually send it to Palm Springs,
or Arizona, L.A.
我有几个熟识的中东佬
你知道，阿拉伯人
I had a couple of sand niggers out there.
You know, Arabs.
你们是要开会还是要买钻石？
Are you gonna have a meeting
or buy some diamonds?
我懂他的语言，我跟他讲讲
I know his language. I'm talking with him.
全部四万块
$40,000, you buy the whole package.
两万，不要拉倒
$20,000. That's my final offer.
他突然会说英文了
别玩游戏了，两万五
He suddenly talks English.
Let's talk turkey. $25,000.
我将我的房间改为保险箱
保留一些我特选的好东西
NICKY: I actually turned my bedroom into
a bank vault where I kept the choice stuff.
因为警察可能会突然临检
所以不能将其留在店里…
I couldn't leave it at the Gold Rush
in case we got raided by the cops...
也防止我手下手痒
or if my crew got cute.
我保有唯一的钥匙
珍妮佛才不在乎
I had the only key.
Jennifer didn't give a fuck.
她每晚都在沙发上
看电影看到睡着
She fell asleep on the couch
watching TV every night.
这些全是我的东西
我一样也没送回老家
This stuff was all mine.
I didn't send any of this back home.
其实我也不行
因为我根本不应该做这些
Actually, I couldn't,
because I wasn't supposed to be doing it.
老大们光是赌场就赚饱了…
The bosses were making
so much money with the casinos...
他们不希望有人惹是非
that they didn't want anybody
making any waves.
你的人马每人都分到了吗？
You've all given your crew a piece of that?
我大家都罩好了
I took care of everybody.
这就是为什么在我来之前
拉斯维加斯并没有犯罪集团
NICKY: That's why there was no real
organized street stuff in Vegas before I came.
但我家衣柜里又能藏多少钱呢？
But how much cash could I bury
in my closet, right?
你必须要了解
而我也相信你了解…
You have to understand,
and I'm sure you do...
做这种风险大的投资…
that in a venture of this kind...
要有可能亏损的心理准备
you must be prepared
to take some kind of loss.
我将一些钱交给查理克拉克
艾斯的银行经理，做一些正当投资
NICKY: I put some money in legitimate
deals with Charlie Clark, Ace's banker.
-你会尽力而为，不是吗？
-是的
-You will try to push it through, won't you?
-Yes.
你得了解我现在
给了你五万元现金
You got to understand,
I'm giving you $50,000 cash.
然后我将更多钱投入正当的投资
例如我开的餐馆
NICKY: Then I put more money
in some legitimate places, like my restaurant.
-剩这个了？
-是
DOMINICK: Is that the last one?
COOK: Yeah.
我让我小弟，多明尼可经营
NICKY: I had my kid brother,
Dominick, run it.
王八蛋
Fuckers.
在这里
DOMINICK: Here you go, guys.
-谢了
-慢慢享用
-Thanks a lot.
-Enjoy it. Have a good time.
-噎死你，王八蛋
-嗨，小多
-Choke on it, motherfucker.
-Hi, Dom.
你怎么样？
How you doing?
是啊，尼奇很喜欢餐馆
他对开餐厅也很拿手
SAM: Yeah, Nicky loved restaurants.
He was a real restaurant buff.
这么多年来，他逢开餐厅必赚
And over the years,
he always made money with them.
他在拉斯维加斯开了比萨斜塔
很受大家欢迎
In Vegas, he had the Leaning Tower.
It was a very popular spot.
常有政客、脱衣舞娘
还有电影明星光顾
He had politicians, showgirls
and movie stars hanging out all over.
佛罗明哥的那场秀越做越好罗
That show at The Flamingo
gets better and better.
对了，山姆说
请你有空时打个电话给他
By the way, Sammy said whenever
you have a minute, give him a call.
-你也变传话的了啊？
-有钱我什么都做啊
-Made you a messenger, too?
-I'll do anything for a buck.
-他对每个人都这样，好好享用晚餐
-谢啦
-He does it to everybody. Enjoy your dinner.
-Thanks.
尼奇最喜欢的
当然就是脱衣舞娘
SAM: I got to tell you, the thing Nicky
liked most was the showgirls.
对她们来说，尼奇像是电影名星
To them, Nicky was the movie star.
-你就这样走过？
-这是雪莉
-You walk past me?
-This is Shelly.
-嗨，雪莉，你好吗？
-嗨
-Hi, Shelly. How are you?
-Hi.
这是史黛希
This is Stacy.
-这是尼克，想吃晚餐吗？一起吧
-好啊
-This is Nick. Wanna have dinner? Come on.
-All right.
我带你去厨房看看
失陪一下
Let's check the kitchen first.
Excuse us one second.
来吧，我带你去
我每天都空运新鲜的东西进来
NICKY: Come on, I'll show you.
I fly stuff in fresh every day.
我从老家运面包
从加州运鱼
I get bread from back home.
I get fish from California.
光从我们用奶喂食的小牛肉就看得出
我们绝对是好餐厅
You can always tell a great kitchen
like ours because of the milk-fed veal.
这就是诀窍
奶喂小牛的肉是纯白色的
That's the secret.
See, milk-fed veal is pure white.
其他餐馆都用那种粉红色的小牛肉
过去点，甜心
Out here, they got that pink veal.
Slide over, honey.
粉红色的那种小牛肉
你就算是追个两天两夜
Now, pink veal you can pound for two days.
它还是不会变嫩
你懂我的意思吗？
NICKY: It'll never ever get tender.
You know what I mean?
我从这儿拿钱离开时
在街上被抢了
AL: I left here with the money.
Got muscled on the street.
是几个我欠钱的家伙
所以我把钱给他们了
A couple guys, I owe them.
So I gave them the money.
-就是这样
-是吗？
-That's what I did.
-Yeah?
你还敢自称是男人吗？
You call yourself a man?
你知道你是个撒谎的杂碎
他妈的烂赌的狗东西吗？
You know you're a lying lowlife,
motherfucking gambling degenerate prick?
你知道自己是什么东西吗？
家里有两个小孩
You know that's what you are?
Two small kids at home.
我给你钱付房租…
I gave you money to pay the fucking rent...
买菜、开暖气
and buy groceries, put the heat on.
你知道你老婆打给法兰克
说家里连暖气都被停了吗？
You know your wife called Frankie
and told him the fucking heat's off?
你没拿钱去赌吗？
你敢这样跟我说吗？
You didn't gamble that money?
Can you tell me that?
-你没有吗？
-没有
-No, you didn't?
-I didn't.
别耍我，艾尔！
别把我当傻子
Don't fuck with me, Al!
Don't make a fuck out of me.
你当我是傻子是吧？
你没去赌？
You wanna make a fool out of me?
You didn't gamble?
告诉我你把钱拿去赌掉了
我就给你钱回去交电费！
Tell me you gambled the money and
I'll give you the money to put the heat on!
有没有赌？
Did you gamble?
真是他妈的狗东西
Fucking degenerate, you.
孩子在家里
Fucking kids at home.
拿去，给我滚
Here. Get the fuck out of here.
-谢了，尼克
-是啊，谢了
AL: Thanks, Nick.
NICKY: Yeah, thanks.
若被我知道是你搞砸的
我会把你扔在我找到你的地方
If I find out you fucked up,
I'll leave you where I find you.
-你要吃几个？
-两个
NICKY: How many of these you gonna eat?
NICKY JR.: Two.
但早上六点半，当他下班时…
SAM: At around 6:30 a.m.,
when he finished his day...
不管他在那里或是在做什么…
no matter where he was
or what he was doing...
他都会回家为儿子，小尼奇做早餐
he always went home to make breakfast
for his son, Nicky boy.
我知道你喜欢
NICKY: I know you like this.
一点点牛油，对不对？
不要很多，你知道为什么，对不对？
NICKY: A little butter, right?
Not a lot. You know why, right?
-为什么？
-因为会堵塞心脏
NICKY: Why?
NICKY JR.: 'Cause it clogs up your heart.
你真是聪明的孩子
What a smart kid you are.
快吃吧
NICKY: Okay, eat.
每隔几个礼拜我就会派玛雷诺
去老大那儿…
NICKY: Every couple of weeks,
I sent Marino back to the bosses...
在老家
也分他们一份
当然不是很多，但他们哪知道？
BACK HOME
with a piece of what I made.
Not a big piece, but what did they know?
他们在2500里外，天高皇帝远
They were 1,500 miles away, and I don't
know anybody who can see that far.
收货地点是个修车场…
Their drop was a truck stop garage...
利蒙他们以前常在那儿数钱
where Remo and the guys
used to hang out and count their millions.
条子们也知道，但他们不在乎
他们早协议好了
The cops knew, but they didn't give a fuck.
They worked it out.
尼奇向你们问好
Nicky sends his warmest regards.
我知道怎样让老大们服服帖帖
NICKY: I knew how to keep
the bosses happy.
每当他们有些小事需要我做
例如传个话之类的…
Whenever they gave me little jobs to do,
you know, to send a message...
我一定做到完美
I would carry things out to a "T."
就像那次东尼道格
那个听说是城里的新硬汉…
Like the time Tony Dogs, who was supposed
to be the new maniac tough guy in town...
在利蒙的一家酒吧乱开枪
shot up one of Remo's bars.
这混蛋打死了两个利蒙的手下…
Here's a fucking guy
who kills two of Remo's guys...
还有一个代班的倒霉女侍者
and a poor fucking waitress
who was just working on her night off.
这家伙根本就
等着被我们杀鸡儆猴
This guy's just begging
to be made an example of.
我要知道当天有谁跟他一起动手
I want the names of all the other people
he had with him.
我要你不择手段去查
懂不懂？
I don't care what you have to do to them
to get them. You understand?
我搞定，利蒙
FRANK: I'll take care of it.
说真的，我还蛮佩服这混蛋的
NICKY: To be truthful with you,
I had to admire this fucking guy.
他真是我所遇过
最硬脖子的爱尔兰人
He was one of the toughest
Irishmen I ever met.
这家伙真是个硬汉
This son of a bitch was tough.
我们痛殴了他两天两夜
For two days and two nights,
we beat the shit out of him.
还用冰锉刺他的G丸
We even stuck ice picks in his balls.
他最好快吐个名字出来
法兰克，要不然我就递你的上去
NICKY: Hope he gives me a name,
or I'll give him yours, Frank.
谢谢喔
FRANK: Thanks a lot.
但他守口如瓶
NICKY: But he never talked.
我知道你要供早就供了
NICKY: I know you would've ratted by now.
最后，我还得他妈的把他的头
摆在夹板里
NICKY: In the end,
I had to put his fucking head in a vice.
你听到了没？
NICKY: Can you hear me?
听好，你的头在夹板里
Listen to me. I got your head in a vice.
再不给我个名字
我就夹爆你的头
I'll squash your head like a grapefruit
if you don't give me a name.
别逼我这么做，拜托你快说吧
NICKY: Don't make me do this.
Please, come on.
别逼我当坏人
Don't make me be a bad guy.
去你的
Fuck you.
王八蛋，你相信吗？
他妈的两天两夜
Motherfucker. You believe this?
Two fucking days and nights.
去我的？你这个王八蛋！
Fuck me? You motherfucker!
去我老母？
你是这意思是吧？
Fuck my mother?
Is that what you're telling me?
你这混蛋！
You motherfucker!
天呀，给我一个名字！
Oh, God. Give me the fucking name!
查理
Charlie M.
-查理
-查理？
-Charlie M.
-Charlie M?
你逼我将你眼珠都爆出来…
You make me pop your eye out your head...
就为了保护这狗屁名字？
to protect that piece of shit?
王八蛋加蠢才！
You dumb motherfucker!
杀了我啊，混蛋！
Kill me, you fuck!
你这王八蛋！
You motherfucker!
法兰克，你帮帮他吧
Frankie, do him a fucking favor.
镇上流传着…
SAM: Word got around that finally...
说这儿终于出了个真的帮派份子
there was a real gangster in town.
尼奇成了拉斯维加斯的新老大
Nicky was the new boss of Las Vegas.
NICKY: Charlie M.
[Coins clinking]
四个轮，一排七个
三个一万五的奖金
SAM: Four reels, sevens across.
Three $15,000 jackpots.
你知道这机率是多少吗？
You have any idea what the odds are?
要好几百万，可能更多
It's gotta be in the millions. Maybe more.
二十分钟内三个大奖？
Three jackpots in 20 minutes?
你为什么没停机？
为什么没通知我？
Why didn't you pull the machines?
Why didn't you call me?
发生得太快，一下就三个人赢
我还没机会
It happened quick. Three guys won.
I didn't have a chance.
你没看到出千吗？
You didn't see the scam?
这无法确定
There's no way to determine that.
有，绝对有
他们赢了就是最好的证据
Yes, there is. An infallible way. They won!
这里是赌场，总会有人赢的
It's a casino. People gotta win sometimes.
你气死我了
你在污辱我的智慧
You're pissing me off.
You're insulting my intelligence.
你认为我是白痴？
You think I'm an idiot?
一定有人对转轮动了手脚
Somebody had to get into those machines
and set the reels.
一台机的机率是一百五十万比一
The probability on one machine
is a million and a half to one.
连续三台的机率是好几兆比一
这根本不可能
On three machines in a row,
it's in the billions. It can't happen.
你到底是怎么了？
SAM: What's the matter with you?
你难道不知道你被骗了吗？
Didn't you see you were being set up
on the second win?
-你没看到吗？
-我觉得你有些反应过度
-You didn't see that?
-I think you're overreacting.
听着，智障，我受够你了
Listen, you yokel, I've had it with you.
我从到这儿时就一直罩你
I've carried your ass ever since I got here.
把东西收收走吧
Get your things and get out of here.
-你开除我？
-我就开除你
-You're firing me?
-I'm firing you.
-你可能会后悔
-留你我一定后悔
-You might regret this.
-I'll regret it if I keep you.
-不应该这样对人
-若你不知道有人出千…
-This is not the way to treat people.
-If you didn't know about the scam...
你就蠢到不配在这儿工作
若你知道，你就是共犯
you're too dumb to work here.
If you did, you were in on it.
不管怎样，你都得走
Either way, you're out. Go on.
在我看来那家伙已经被炒了
The guy is history as far as I'm concerned.
你不能开除他
他的姐夫是县辅导
You can't fire him.
His brother-in-law is County Commissioner.
这里每个穿马靴的不是辅导
就是辅导的亲戚
Everyone out here with cowboy boots
is a commissioner or related to one.
我受够了
I'm sick of this.
这是他的州，他的叔叔是大法官
This is his state. His uncle's Chief Judge.
他的姐夫管理县委员会
His brother-in-law runs
the County Commission.
一定有方法让他回来
There's gotta be a way to work him back in.
你是搞帐目的，在楼上
你看不到下面发生的事
You're in the finances, upstairs.
You don't see what's going on.
我有上千的赌客
却只有五百个庄家
I've got thousands of players.
I got 500 dealers.
他们每天24小时都在想着
怎么将我抢空
They're all looking to rob me blind
24 hours a day.
我必须要让他们知道
我随时都在注意每个细节
I have to let them know I'm watching
all the details all the time.
我不会漏掉任何一样事情
That there is not one single thing
I will not catch.
看你的，看
SAM: Look at yours. Look at that.
再看这个，什么都没有
SAM: Look at this. There's nothing.
你看你的蓝莓那么多
Look how many blueberries your muffin has.
-我一个都没有
-你在说什么？
-I have nothing.
-What are you talking about?
自己不动手做就弄不好
If you don't do it yourself,
it never gets done.
你要去哪儿？
PHILIP: Where are you going?
从现在开始
我要你全都放同份量的蓝莓
SAM: From now on, I want you to put an
equal amount of blueberries in each muffin.
An equal amount of blueberries
in each muffin.
你知道那多花时间吗？
Do you know how long that will take?
我不管要多久
每个松饼的份量都要一致
I don't care how long it takes.
Put an equal amount in each muffin.
再吃一点，乖
Just a little. That a girl.
-你要找妈妈？
-来妈妈这儿？
SAM: Wanna go to Mommy?
GINGER: Wanna come to Mommy?
好的，甜心
It's all right, sweetheart.
我要跟你谈谈，我需要点钱
GINGER: I need to talk to you.
I need some money.
-你要什么？
-抱好了吗？
-What do you need?
-Got her?
我需要很多，比平时要多
I need a lot. I need more than usual.
为什么不从你户头领呢？
Why don't you take it out of your account?
我本想，只是…
I would, it's just that...
我需要更多，我要两万五
I need more than that. I need $25,000.
两万五千元？
$25,000?
-你自己要？
-是啊
-For yourself?
-Yeah.
你为什么要那么多？
SAM: Why do you need that much?
有什么差别？我需要就是了
What's the difference? I just need it.
我一定得问啊
那很多钱耶，又不只是一盒爆米花
I gotta ask you. That's a lot of money.
It's not a box of popcorn.
我们不用将这变成件大事
We don't have to turn this into a big deal.
我们不用吵架
We don't have to have a fight.
只是对我很重要，算了
有些想做的事罢了
GINGER: It was important to me. Forget it.
Something I wanted to do.
谁在吵架？
告诉我钱的用处
Who's fighting? Tell me what it's for.
为什么不能告诉我？
Why can't you tell me what it's for?
现在我要你告诉我
Now I want you to tell me.
我老婆跑来问我要两万五
你想买大衣吗？
My wife comes to me and asks me
for $25,000. Do you want a coat?
-不
-如果想买大衣，就去买啊
GINGER: No.
SAM: If you want a coat, you got it.
不是钱的问题
只是，你为什么要？
It's not the money.
It's just, why do you want it?
我无权过问吗？
Am I not entitled to ask that?
我一辈子都很独立
我从不为任何事求人
I've been independent all my life.
I never had to ask anybody for anything.
现在你要我求你是吧
Now you're making me beg you for this.
-你在说什么？
-好，你还羞辱我
-What are you talking about?
-Okay? And you're embarrassing me.
-为什么得让我如此难受？
-你问我要两万五
Why make me feel so bad?
SAM: You're asking me for $25,000.
我不是要让你难堪
我只是希望能信任你
I'm not out to make you feel bad.
I want to just be able to trust you.
是信任问题
It's about trust.
我必须要连性命都能交托于你
I have to be able to trust you with my life.
你懂吗？
Do you understand?
我能信任你吗？
Can I trust you?
我能吗？告诉我
Can I trust you? Answer me.
你能
You can trust me.
好，那你就可以告诉我
钱要拿来干嘛
Good. So then you can tell me
what the money is for.
[Sentimental jazz music]
她现在正离开银行
She's leaving the bank now.
我跟着她
I'll follow her.
那是什么？
LESTER: What is that?
我知道那神情，那表情是什么意思？
I know that look. What does that look mean?
意思是我有钱
GINGER: It means I got the money.
你好吗？是莱斯特吧？
How are you doing? It's Lester, right?
Sam.
我记得你不是玩牌老手…
From my recollection,
aren't you the card shark...
高尔夫球骗子
比佛利山庄的皮条客吗？
the golf hustler,
the pimp from Beverly Hills?
若记错了，请纠正我
SAM: If I'm wrong, correct me.
我从不知道你也是个小偷
I never knew you to be a heist man.
不过如果是的话，这样吧
But if you are, you know what?
我的也拿去吧
Here, take mine, too.
拿吧，反正你已拿了她的
Take it. You already have hers.
她是我老婆
She's my wife.
看着我
SAM: Look at me.
你知道吧？
你知道她是我老婆吧？
You did know that, didn't you?
You knew she's my wife?
-看着我
-我知道
SAM: Look at me.
LESTER: I know that.
知道啊？
SAM: You do, yeah?
你下次若再想回来…
If you ever come back again...
拿她的钱，记得带枪
to take her money, next time bring a pistol.
这样你才有机会
That way you got a chance.
当个男人，别做皮条客
Be a man, don't be a fucking pimp.
现在，卖我个面子
快滚吧
Now, you want to do me a favor?
Get out of here.
我想跟我老婆独处
给我他妈的滚
I wanna be alone with my wife.
Get the fuck up and get out of here.
混蛋狗杂种
SAM: Fucking piece of shit.
记得那晚你打电话跟他道别吗？
Remember when you called him that night
and said goodbye to him?
他并没说：   “别结婚，我马上来”
He didn't say, "Don't get married.
I'll be right down."
-他没这样说吧？
-不，没有
-He didn't say that, did he?
-No, he didn't.
那他说了什么？
What did he say?
“跟他睡，捞光他的钱”
"Fuck him.
Take him for everything he's got."
过来，我给你看样东西
Come here. I want to show you something.
[Men shouting]
[Car horn honking]
叫他们停！
GINGER: Make them stop it!
[Ginger screaming hysterically]
不是他的错！是我的错！
It's not his fault! It's my fault!
[Ginger continues screaming]
没用的狗杂种
THUG: Piece of shit.
自己来吧，你这没胆的混蛋！
LESTER: Do it yourself,
you chickenshit cocksucker!
他太可恶了
He's such a prick.
他叫旅馆的人揍他
He had some guy from the hotel
beat him up.
他自己不想动手
He didn't want to do it himself.
他不想将手弄脏
He didn't want to get his own hands dirty.
他为什么要这样？
Why did he have to do that?
告诉我
Tell me.
-那不是件好事…
-废话
NICKY: It wasn't a nice thing to do--
GINGER: No shit.
你得了解，他并不知道这人
是不是在骗你的钱
You gotta understand it. He doesn't know
if this guy is shaking you down.
我在结婚前就告诉过他这个人了
I told him all about this guy
before we got married.
-这并不是什么新鲜事
-是吗？我并不知道
-This is no fucking surprise.
-You did? I didn't know that.
他只是我的朋友
我想要帮他，有什么大不了？
He's just a friend of mine
I was trying to help. So what?
我第一次看到你们俩在一起时…
The first time I ever saw you guys together...
我从未见他那么快乐过
I never saw him so happy.
我知道他是个犹太疯子…
NICKY: I know he's a crazy Jew fuck
and everything...
但我从未见过他跟别人一起时这样
but I never seen him act like that
with anybody else.
他为你疯狂
他真的很爱你
I think he's crazy about you.
He really loves you.
-他真的是
-拜托
NICKY: He does.
GINGER: Come on.
我是睁着双眼走进这关系的
I went into this with my eyes open.
我知道随时都可能变卦
GINGER: I knew the bottom
could drop out any time.
我也混过，你真以为
我在没有保障的情况下…
I'm a working girl. You don't think
I'm gonna go into a situation like this...
会走这条路吗？
if I don't think I'm covered on the back end?
是啊，我可以了解
Sure, I can see that.
他买了好多珠宝给我
好多好多
So he put aside some jewelry for me.
A lot of jewelry.
很多贵重的珠宝？
大概值多少？
A lot of expensive jewelry?
About how much?
你想偷吗？
You want to steal it?
不，只是好奇
我是在想…
No. I'm just curious. I was wondering...
他会在那种东西里
投入多少钱
how much he would put
into a thing like that.
他跟我说大约一百万
可能更多
I'm told it's worth about $1 million,
maybe more.
那就是罗
这说明了什么？
NICKY: There you go.
What does that tell you?
一百万的珠宝
$1 million in jewelry.
这不说明了他爱你爱到疯了吗？
Does that tell you he is crazy about you?
我根本就不该嫁给他的
I should have never married him.
他是双子座的，双子加三级，两面人
He's a Gemini. Triple Gemini. Duality.
双子座就像条蛇
你不能相信蛇
Gemini is the snake, you know.
You can't trust a snake.
我说真的
I mean it.
我懂你的意思，金吉儿，听着
I know what you mean. Listen, Ginger.
这可能不是…
我也没有答案
This is probably not....
I don't have the answers anyway.
-这可能不是你想听的
-我想
-This is probably not what you want to hear.
-I do.
你不高兴，我可以理解…
You're a little upset, and I understand that.
但先撑着点吧
慢慢来，看看会发生什么事
But try to make the best of it now.
Go slow. See what happens.
他差点杀了他！
He could've killed him!
他用不着打他
我又没跟他上床
He didn't have to hit him.
I'm not sleeping with the guy.
他让我得偷偷摸摸的
跟我的朋友见面
He makes me sneak around
to see my own friends.
这算什么呢？
What the fuck is that all about?
我想是因为他太爱你了吧
他吃醋又担心
I guess it's 'cause he loves you so much,
he's jealous and worries.
谁会在乎我做什么？
Who gives a fuck what I do?
我会试着问问到底怎样
I'll try to find out what the hell is going on.
-遇到他时我会跟他谈谈的
-好
-When I see him, I'll talk to him.
-Okay.
-可以吗？
-好
-All right?
-Yeah.
谢了…
Thanks...
忍受我唠叨
for putting up with me.
别喝这么凶吧
这只会让情况更糟
Take it easy with this shit.
This can only make matters worse.
你是个美女，别搞砸了
You're a beautiful girl. Don't ruin that.
我看过太多漂亮女孩
因这个变丑八怪
I've seen a lot of girls
get shot to hell from this stuff.
你真好
You're so nice.
好了啦
我不想见你不快乐
Come on, now.
I don't wanna see you unhappy.
谢了
Thanks.
没事啦
It's all right.
[Phone ringing]
县辅导派特委布来见你
County Commissioner Pat Webb
is here to see you.
-等一下
-好的，请稍候
-Give me a minute.
-Okay. Just a minute.
你需要什么吗？
RECEPTIONIST: Can I get you anything?
不，谢谢，小姐
No, thank you, little lady.
让他进来，然后四分钟后打给我
Send him in and call me four minutes after.
罗斯坦先生，我是派特委布
Mr. Rothstein, I'm Pat Webb.
你好吗？
How do you do?
-幸会
-我常听起你的事
-It is a pleasure.
-I heard a lot about you.
过奖了，庄家最近还过得去
PAT: Thank you, sir. House is doing well.
那么多钱滚滚而来
All that money is rolling in.
我很感激你愿意见我这老公仆
I appreciate you taking the time
to see a poor old civil servant.
-不如坐下吧？
-谢谢您
SAM: Why don't you have a seat?
PAT: Thank you, sir.
我是来亲自化解…
PAT: I come here personally
to smooth over...
一些小误会的
any fracas about a certain matter.
你可能不知道…
Maybe you didn't know it...
但道恩华德在镇上挺受欢迎的
but Don Ward is a very well-liked man
in this town.
他有许多朋友
他们家族及产业也很久了
He's got lots of friends. His family
and their money go back many years.
朋友是选民
家人与金钱都能助选
Friends vote, family and money votes.
这对你我都很重要
That's important to me and you.
若你从这个角度
来看我们这个小问题的话…
If you'll think about our little problem
along them lines...
很抱歉我得这么说…
and you'll forgive me for saying it...
但他可能不该被开除
maybe he did not deserve to be fired.
他非常清楚我们…
He knew about our getting hit...
在一瞬间被赢了三个大奖
但他却袖手旁观
on three big machines in a row,
and he did nothing about it.
他要不是跟他们一伙
那很抱歉，他就是蠢到看不见
Either he was in on it
or, forgive me, he was too dumb to see it.
不论如何，我都无法让一个
这样的人在这儿工作
Either way, I cannot have
a man like that working here.
在将过错都推给道恩前…
Before we point the dirty end
of the stick at old Don...
我们得先确定有证据这样指控他
we better be sure
we can prove them charges.
相信我，要是有证据
他早就被逮捕了
Believe me, if I could prove it,
he'd be under arrest.
你确定要让赌博游乐委员会…
Are we certain that you want
the Gaming Control Board...
过目你与你的帮派朋友
尼奇的记录吗？
eyeballing your record
and your gangster pals like Nicky?
我觉得你这样跟我说
有点太过份了
I think you're way out of line
talking to me like that.
你所说的几乎是毁谤
你无权怀疑我的专业
What you're saying is libelous. You're
in no position to challenge my expertise.
我已尽我所能去
帮助并善待那孩子
I went way out of my way
to be helpful and courteous to that kid.
他太弱了也很无能
他使这地方濒于险境
He's weak. He's incompetent.
He jeopardizes the whole place.
我对他真的无能为力
There's not much more I can do for him.
这倒是真的
You have got me there.
道恩就像公猪身上的奶头一样无用
Old Don is as useless as tits on a boar.
[Pat coughs]
但他还是我的小舅子…
But he is my brother-in-law...
我会当是我欠你的一个人情
and I would look on it
as a personal favor...
若你愿意考虑重新聘用他
if you'd think some more
on hiring him back.
我不能
I can't do that.
我知道他是你的小舅子
I appreciate the fact
that he's your brother-in-law.
我也想帮你更喜欢卖人情
I do want to help you
and I like to do favors.
我也知道你的地位
但我真的不能这么做
And I know who you are.
But I cannot do that.
日后是否会有其它较适合的…
Could there be any position...
职位呢？
farther down the trough?
抱歉，并没有
I'm sorry. I can't do anything.
他太无能了
最终还是他不能被信任
He's too incompetent.
The bottom line is he cannot be trusted.
[Phone ringing]
好吧，谢谢
SAM: Okay, thanks a lot.
抱歉
That's it. I'm sorry.
罗斯坦先生
你们这帮人永远都不会懂…
Mr. Rothstein,
your people never will understand...
这里的世界如何运作
the way it works out here.
你们只不过来此地做客
You're all just our guests.
但却喧宾夺主
But you act like you're at home.
让我告诉你，老兄
这并不是你家
Let me tell you something, partner.
You ain't home.
家是我们州长生气时
送你们回的地方
But that's where we'll send you
if it harelips the Governor.
-多谢你空出时间见我
-没问题
-Thank you for your time.
-No problem.
-对不起
-当然
-Sorry.
-You bet.
我的药呢？
SAM: What happened to my pills?
你喝那么多酒还不够吗？
你还要吃我的药？
Isn't it bad enough you drink too much?
You're taking my pills, too?
我没吃你的药
GINGER: I didn't take your pills.
我因为胃溃疡，才吃半颗
For my ulcer, I take a half of one of these.
而且是痛到无法忍时才吃
That's when I have extreme pain.
我本来有三个月份的
你弄到哪里去了？
I had a three-month supply.
What did you do with them?
你用不着打他的
GINGER: [Crying] You didn't have to
beat him up.
什么？
SAM: What?
我只是想帮他
GINGER: I was just trying to help him.
好像我跟他上床似的
GINGER: Like I'm sleeping with the guy.
是吗，我哪知道？
Yeah, how do I know?
你不能让我完全不关心别人
GINGER: You can't make me stop
caring about people.
-什么？
-我说…
SAM: What?
GINGER: I said...
你不能让我完全不关心别人
you can't make me
stop caring about people.
听着…
SAM: Listen...
我只想让一切比较好
I'm trying to make the best
of everything here.
老天啊，你是我老婆
I mean, you're my wife, for Christ's sakes.
镇上的人都很看重你
People look up to you in this town.
你知道吗，艾斯？
那关我屁事
You know what, Ace? I don't give a shit.
我要离开
I'm getting out of here.
你冷静一点
SAM: You gotta get a hold of yourself.
-好
-不为我，也为艾美
GINGER: Okay.
SAM: If not for me, at least for Amy.
懂吗，你酒喝得太过份了
SAM: Understand? Your drinking's
getting way out of hand.
我帮你安排去做治疗
这儿有很多好疗养所
I'm gonna get you into a program.
They got plenty of good ones.
-我不需要
-你需要，那很隐密的
-I don't need one.
-Yes, you do. It's very discreet.
姓名也不会被公布
There's no names in the papers.
你只在乎名誉
That's all you care about.
你不在乎我
GINGER: You don't care about me.
-我在乎
-不，你不在乎
SAM: Yes, I do.
GINGER: No, you don't.
你怎能这样说？
How could you say that?
你是个美丽的女人
你在摧残自己
You're a beautiful woman.
You're destroying yourself.
你不需要那些
你现在芒刺在背
You don't need that stuff,
that fucking leech living off you.
我比你还要了解你
I know you better than you know yourself.
你像只老虎，你比我还坚强
You're a tiger. You're stronger than I am.
只要你下定决心的事
你就做得比任何人都要好
When you set your mind on doing
something, you do it better than anybody.
你一定得去
You're gonna do it.
天啊
Oh, God.
[Ginger sobbing]
我试
I'll try.
我会的
GINGER: I will.
别生我气，好吗？
Don't be mad at me, okay?
不管在计算室外有多少问题…
NICKY: No matter what
the problems were outside the count room...
都是值得的
it was all worth it.
现金滚滚而来…
The cash kept rolling in...
皮箱也不停的进出
and the suitcases kept coming and going.
让我告诉你
除了钱还是钱
And let me tell you,
the fucking bottom line here is cash.
唯一的问题是过了一阵子后…
The only problem was that after a while...
老大们发觉皮箱越来越轻
the bosses noticed that
the suitcases were getting a little light.
等一下，你是说…
Wait a minute. You mean to tell me...
我们抢的钱被人抢？
that the money we're robbing
is being robbed?
有人抢我们？
Somebody's robbing from us?
我们这么大费周章
竟有人在抢我们？
We go through all this fucking trouble
and somebody's robbing us?
如我所说，这就是这行的一部分
就当做是遗漏的
Like I said, it's part of the business.
It's considered leakage.
遗漏，狗屁
我要找到抢我们的人
Leakage, my balls.
I want the guy who's robbing us.
就连约翰南斯
主导这骗局的人…
NICKY: Even John Nance,
that's the guy who ran the scam...
都知道自己无能为力去阻止
he knew there wasn't much
he could do about it.
你得知道一个肯帮你偷钱的人…
You gotta know that
a guy who helps you steal...
就算你把他照顾得好好的…
even if you take care of him real well...
他还是为自己多偷一点
he's gonna steal a little extra for himself.
很合理不是吗？
Makes sense, don't it? Right?
试着让这些固执的老头们了解吧
You go try and make these hard-headed
old greaseballs understand that.
如果自己抽完还要被别人抽
还有什么意义？
What's the point of skimming
if we're being skimmed?
这样我们根本就在做白工嘛
It defeats the whole purpose
of what we're doing.
他们是我的手下才帮我们拿钱
就睁只眼闭只眼吧
They take this money because they're
my guys, so give them some leeway.
但老大们从来就不相信这理论…
NICKY: But the bosses never believed
in leeway...
听听他们做了什么
so listen to what they do.
他们将艾题派斯康
堪萨斯市的二佬…
They put Artie Piscano,
the underboss of K. C...
调来管理
确定没有人抽头
in charge of making sure
nobody skimmed the skim.
-你那时在干嘛？
-我与我马子一起
BOSS: What were you doing?
I was with my cumari.
-你跟你马子那时在干嘛？
-我打她一巴掌
BOSS: What were you doing
with your cumari?
I gave her a schiaffo.
问题是，派斯康是个麻烦
NICKY: The only trouble was,
Piscano was a disaster.
这家伙连泡咖啡都可搞砸
This guy could fuck up a cup of coffee.
-你都在干嘛？
-我在那儿的时间比在这儿多
BOSS: What you been doing?
ARTIE: I'm out there more than I'm here.
当时没人想到
后来会演变为何
NICKY: Little did anybody know
where this would lead.
若有人早知道
去做念珠可能都还好些
If they did, they would've
been better off making fucking novenas.
你得回去跟那家伙讲
You gotta go back there and talk to that guy.
-我上次的花费都还没补给我
-什么花费？
-My expenses weren't paid for the last trip.
-What expenses?
我一直自掏腰包
却什么都拿不回来
I'm laying money out of my own pocket,
and I never get anything back.
你得再回去
You gotta go back out there.
从今开始
我得开始做记录了
From now on,
I'm gonna start keeping records.
你要记录干嘛，缴税吗？
What are you gonna do with records,
pay taxes?
我不能一直这样自己出钱
跑来跑去
I can't keep laying out
my own fucking dough for these trips.
我们他妈的到底在那儿干嘛？
What the hell are we doing over here?
我花钱让你去赌城玩
You're going to Las Vegas and having
a good time at my expense.
我靠，我是说…
What the fuck? I mean, after all....
不论你做了几符念珠…
SAM: No matter how many
novenas you could make...
都无法阻止接下来
在赌场发生的事
nothing was gonna stop
what came up next at the casino.
-我不相信你会这样做
-我们有协议
PHILIP: I can't believe you're doing this.
ANNA: We made a deal.
结果菲立浦葛林，   “老实先生”…
SAM: It turned out Phil Green,
"Mr. Integrity"...
有个没人知道的搭挡…
had a partner nobody knew about...
当她出现并向坦吉乐要钱时…
and when she showed up
and demanded money from Tangiers...
-你为什么这样对我？
-因为你错了
-Why are you doing this to me?
-Because you're wrong.
-我没错
-你有
ANNA: I'm not.
PHILIP: You are.
不，我没错
No, I am not wrong.
葛林试着搪塞她
...Green tried to stonewall her.
我不会这么轻易的放过你的
ANNA: I will see that
you don't get away with this.
所以她一状告到法庭去
So, she sued him in court.
本庭现在将开始审理
安娜史考特…
The court will now hear the matter
of Anna Scott...
对坦吉乐集团与其总裁
菲立浦葛林
against Tangiers Corporation
and its President, Philip Green.
-葛林先生将由欧伯伦辩护
-安娜史考特的律师则是罗根
OBERON: Oberon on behalf of Mr. Green.
LOGAN: Logan on behalf of Anna Scott.
-欧伯伦先生，可以开始了
-谢谢，大人
JUDGE: Mr. Oberon, you can proceed.
OBERON: Thank you.
我觉得判决很公正
而我也对判决非常满意
I believe he was fair,
and I'm delighted with the decision.
有麻烦了
We got a problem.
官司结果不理想，葛林得呈交帐簿…
It didn't go too well.
Green has to open up the books...
他得解释钱是怎么来的
has to show how he got the financing.
这可不好
That's not good.
她官司还打得不错
NICKY: She was doing pretty good
with her lawsuit.
但在钞票还未落入她口袋之前…
But before she could start
counting her money...
老家的老头子们就已决定庭外和解
the boys back home decided
to settle the case out of court.
因此他们派我
So they sent me.
你对安娜史考特的谋杀
有什么想法吗？
REPORTER: Any comment on
the murder of Anna Scott?
-你在说什么？
-她昨晚被人发现中弹身亡
What are you talking about?
REPORTER: She was found last night
shot in the head.
只是有关房地产合伙问题吗？
MAN: Was this just
a real estate partnership?
她的律师说你们是搭挡
MAN 2: Her lawyer said you were partners.
我们是在多年前
在一些小房地产交易上合作过
We were involved
in minor real estate deals many years ago.
称不上是搭挡
It was never a partnership.
你听过.22口径杀手吗？
MAN: Did you ever hear
of the.22 caliber killer?
现在条子不只是盯尼奇…
SAM: Now, Instead of the cops
only looking at Nicky...
他们也开始盯葛林
they started looking at Green, too.
他本是我们的正派门面
And he was supposed to be
our squeaky-clean front man.
我得接受访问
让大家都知道…
I had to start giving interviews
to make sure everybody knew...
赌场没有牵涉到案子
the casino was on the up-and-up.
你多常帮他代班？
So how often do you really fill in for him?
葛林一个月大约来个两、三次…
Green's here about two or three times
a month...
他还有其他房地产交易
和别的事要忙
and he's busy
with other real estate deals, and things.
所以葛林不在时
你就是老大罗？
So in Green's absence,
then, you're the boss?
我很荣幸能为董事会的主席服务
I serve at the pleasure
of the Chairman of the Board.
我的责任是管理赌场的日常运作
My responsibilities are
to run the day-to-day operations.
所以平常日子你就是老大？
So day-to-day, then, you're the boss?
可以这么说吧…
Well, in a sense, you could say
that I am the boss...
当葛林先生不在时
when Mr. Green is away.
可以这么说
You could say that.
山姆罗斯坦：   “我是老大！”
你看了没？
PAT: Have you read this?
关于罗斯坦先生
About Mr. Rothstein.
上面说：   与黑道有关连的
中西部下注者…
It says, "The Midwest bookmaker
with mob ties...
“说他才是价值一亿的坦吉乐赌场
真正的老板”
"says that he is the real boss
of the $100 million Tangiers casino empire."
-你相信吗？
-他真的这么说？
PAT: Do you believe that?
OFFICIAL: Did he really say that?
他当然是这么说的
这儿不都写了吗
Why, of course he really said that.
It's right here.
这家伙申请执照了没？
Has that man even filed for his license yet?
我不知道，得查查
I don't know. We have to check the files.
去查查看吧，用不着太激动
Without getting your shorts in a knot,
would you do that?
查仔细点，我们也许能
将这死犹太人踢出城了
And check closely, 'cause we may
have to kick a kike's ass out of town.
谢谢
PAT: Thank you.
赌博游乐委员会开始调查
坦吉乐的高层主管…
A Gaming Control Board investigation
of Tangiers executive...
山姆罗斯坦的赌博游乐执照
还没核发下来…
Sam Rothstein's application
for a gaming license is underway.
罗斯坦负责管理坦吉乐赌场的运作
并也是赌城黑手党老大…
Rothstein, who heads the Tangiers casino
operation and is a boyhood friend...
尼奇山多罗的儿时好友…
of Las Vegas mob boss Nicky Santoro...
他有可能会失去
在赌场工作的权力…
could lose his ability
to work in the casino....
[Phone rings]
喂？
Hello?
我要去你家见见银行经理，好吗？
我得见见清洁工
在小巴黎如何？
I gotta meet Charlie the Banker
right away at your house, okay?
I gotta meet Clean Face right away.
What about the Chez Paris?
你得要订位，一定客满了
You gotta make a reservation.
It's all booked up.
不用，没关系
NICKY: No, it's okay.
我不要在家见客
不可能啦，绝对客满
而且很难进去
I don't want a meeting at my house.
It's impossible. It's booked up,
and it's very difficult to get in.
我会从高尔夫球场过来
六点见
没关系，我走后门
九点见
I'll come in from the golf course side.
See you at six.
It's okay, I'll use the service entrance.
I'll see you at nine.
好
All right.
州政府赌博游乐处官员
与坦吉乐高层…
The battle between state gaming
officials and Tangiers casino boss...
山姆“艾斯”罗斯坦之战正如火如荼
Sam "Ace" Rothstein is heating up.
今晚，看看艾斯罗斯坦如何
尝试取得州立执照…
Tonight, a look at Ace Rothstein's
attempt to get state licensing...
虽然面对警方的指控
怀疑罗斯坦与犯罪集团有勾结
despite law-enforcement allegations of
Rothstein's organized crime connections.
山姆罗斯坦与黑道人物
尼奇山多罗之间的友谊…
Will Sam Rothstein's friendship
with organized crime figure, Nicky Santoro...
是否会阻碍罗斯坦
管理坦吉乐赌场呢？
keep Rothstein
from running the Tangiers casino?
而州政府的赌博游乐法规
是否会因儿时友谊而受到威胁呢？
And can the integrity of state gaming laws
be jeopardized by a boyhood friendship?
你少喝点吧？
SAM: Why don't you take it easy
on that stuff?
来，我扶你下楼
Come on. Let me help you down.
我们在谈话
We're talking about some stuff.
今晚六点，儿时的友谊是否…
NEWSCASTER: At 6:00,
will a boyhood friendship...
会让罗斯坦失去坦吉乐
老大的位子？
unseat Rothstein
as the Tangiers casino boss?
KBBO独家专题报导
Exclusive on the KBBO special news report.
下楼去，到楼下去
Go down. Just go downstairs.
你不能让这影响你，艾斯
别管这些了
You can't let this concern you, Ace.
Don't worry about that stuff.
只是政治圈找替死鬼游戏
It's just a political witch hunt.
你要喝什么吗？
SAM: Do you want something to drink?
-查理，你还要吗？
-好啊
-Charlie, you want a refill?
-Yeah, that would be great.
我什么都不要
嗨，克拉克先生，我一直在找你
I don't want nothing. Hi, Mr. Clark.
I've been trying to reach you.
-你比总统还难找
-最近比较忙
-You're tougher to get than the President.
-I've been busy.
是吗？但你至少也该
回我个电话吧
Yeah? At least you could return
my phone calls, though.
听着，尼奇，我们谈过这个
Listen, Nicky, we talked about this.
我也跟你解释过
你可能会有亏损
And I explained to you that you might
have to take some kind of loss.
Yeah.
我想把钱拿回来
I think I want my money back.
你是要威胁我吗？
What are you gonna do, strong-arm me?
我想你可能误解我了
I think you've gotten
the wrong impression about me.
我觉得为公平起见…
I think, in all fairness...
我应该告诉你我打算怎么做
I should explain to you
exactly what it is that I do.
明天一大早我就会散步去银行…
Tomorrow morning I'll get up nice
and early, take a walk to the bank...
走进去看看
若还没把我的钱准备好的话…
and walk in and see,
and if you don't have my money for me...
我就会在众人面前爆开你的头
I'll crack your fucking head
wide open in front of everybody.
而当我服完刑出狱时…
And just about the time
that I'm coming out of jail...
希望你也能从昏迷中苏醒
hopefully, you'll be coming
out of your coma.
知道吗？
我会再爆开你的头
And guess what? I'll split
your fucking head open again.
因为我是个傻子
我完全不在乎坐牢
'Cause I'm fucking stupid.
I don't give a fuck about jail.
这就是我的职业
我会做的事
That's my business. That's what I do.
我们知道你的职业
We know what you do.
你把人的钱骗走
然后大摇大摆的走开
You fuck people out of money
and get away with it.
-你不能这样对我说话
-你这只爱尔兰肥猪！
You can't talk to me like that.
NICKY: You fat Irish prick!
你害我领不到我的钱
你最好把它弄出来，不然我要你好看
You put my money to sleep.
Get it, or I'll put your brain to sleep.
山姆别看，这是我们的事
Never mind Sam. This is personal.
我明天早上一定到
你试试看啊，肥猪
I'll be there in the morning.
You can try me, fatso.
-你觉得他懂了吗？
-你在干嘛？
-You think he got the point?
-What are you doing?
他是个老实的生意人
他会去找联邦调查局的
He's a square guy, for Christ's sakes.
He's gonna run to the FBI.
这混蛋躲了我三个礼拜了
That prick's been dodging me
for three weeks.
-你在告诉我该怎么做吗？
-我没有要告诉你该怎么做
-You're trying to tell me what to do?
-I'm not trying to tell you what to do.
你太过份了，你的脑哪里去了？
You're way out of line. Where's your head?
我的脑？
你的种又去了哪儿？
Where's my head?
Where's your fucking balls?
我有更大的计划
你知道我在说什么
I'm trying to put something big together.
You know what I'm talking about.
如果你现在就这个样
我还怎么指望你啊？
If you're acting like this now,
how can I depend on you?
很多事都要改变了
你若要跟我一起…
A lot of things gonna change.
If you wanna be there with me...
你就得听我的
you're gonna have to go my way.
你得体谅我的处境
我得对上千名员工负责
You got to understand my situation.
I'm responsible for thousands of people.
我每年都得经手一亿元
SAM: I got $100 million a year
going through the place.
我若拿不到执照就玩完了
It's all over if I don't get that license.
相信我，我若玩完了
很多人就会跟着完蛋
Believe me, if it goes bad for me,
it's gonna go bad for a lot of people.
去他妈的什么烂执照
Forget about your fucking license.
到时候我说的就是法律
你根本不需要什么执照
I plant my own flag out here,
you ain't gonna need a license.
我不知道为什么
但越和你说话…
I don't know what it is,
but the more I talk to you...
我越觉得你不会挺我
the more I feel like you just
don't want to go along with me.
-不，我不打算和你一起
-好
-No, I don't want to come along with you.
-All right.
我不想涉入你所说的任何事，好吗？
I don't want to be involved
in anything you're talking about, okay?
我只想好好经营赌场
我只要我的执照
I want to run a square joint.
I just want my license.
我只想一切都安静下来
I want everything quiet. That's it!
这样叫安静？
“我是老大”这样叫安静？
Quiet like this?
"I'm the boss"? That's quiet?
他们扭曲了意思
我根本控制不了
It's taken out of context. I had no control.
罗尼与比利可以告诉你整个经过
Ronnie and Billy will tell you
exactly what happened.
这在老家很难看
Back home that looks bad.
难看？每次只要你上电视
就会提到我，这才叫难看
Looks bad? Every time you're on television,
I get mentioned. That looks bad.
你到底怎么了？
What the fuck happened to you?
-你怎么了？整个失控？
-我失控？
-What happened to you? You lost control?
-I lost control?
你他妈的像个电影明星似的走来走去
You're fucking walking around
like John Barrymore.
穿粉红色的浴袍还拿烟盒？
是我失控？
A pink robe and a fucking cigarette holder?
I lost control?
我本来不想提的，但你不尊重人
连你老婆都不例外
I don't wanna bring this up, but you treat
people with disrespect. Even your own wife.
我老婆？关她什么事？
My wife? What does she have
to do with this?
她为了许多事不高兴
尤其是莱斯特戴蒙德那档
She was upset about a lot of things,
especially that Lester Diamond incident.
你是她哭诉的对象？
你没告诉她那事你也有份？
You're the shoulder to cry on?
Did you tell her about your role in that?
没有，那不是重点
No, that's not the fucking point.
重点是，她不快乐
你也有问题
The point is, she's upset,
and you've got a problem.
我希望你不要干涉
我的私生活
I'd appreciate it if you'd stay out
of my personal life.
若我这样你也会不爽吧
You wouldn't like it if I did it to you.
她来找我说话的
我该赶她出去吗？
She came to talk to me.
Was I supposed to throw her out?
离她远一点
不关你的事
Stay away from her.
It's none of your business.
一周前就是我的事，现在就不是
你需要我时，我就得到
A week ago it was. Now it's not.
When you need me, you need me.
是啊，就像你需要我
帮你做担保一样
Right, the way you need me
to vouch for you as a citizen.
我得去解决你刚刚对那人
所做的事情
I'm gonna have to straighten out
what you did with this guy.
他会去找联邦调查局的
This guy's gonna run to the FBI.
你的自尊比你的赌场还大
这就是你的问题
NICKY: Your head's bigger than your casino.
That's your problem.
我知道他想做什么，但我不想参与
尼奇想自个儿当老大
SAM: I knew what he wanted
and I didn't want any part of it.
He wanted to take over.
他想干掉盖吉
抽头，还有一切
He wanted to go after Gaggi,
the skim, everything and everybody.
他不再每件小事都要老家批准
He also stopped asking permission
from back home for every little thing.
一位赌场大亨与他老婆被杀了
调查员侦问了尼奇
A casino boss and his wife were killed.
The bulls questioned Nicky.
一位西洛可的庄家
他们也询问尼奇
A dealer from the Scirocco.
They questioned Nicky.
几个线民死在自己的后车箱里
他们也追问尼奇
Stool pigeons wound up in the trunks
of their cars. They questioned Nicky.
一个律师
A lawyer.
They questioned Nicky.
他们问尼奇
When some guys who didn't pay
their shylocks began disappearing...
当一些拖欠高利贷的人
莫名的开始消失…
尼奇的名字布满每家报纸
Nicky's name was in every newspaper.
尼奇因为一堆谋杀案调查被侦讯
但他们每次都放他走
Nicky was questioned in two dozen
murders, but they always had to let him go.
从来没有目击者
There were never any witnesses.
条子把所有的不顺
都归昝于我
NICKY: The coppers blamed me
for everything that went wrong.
小心点
你会好看的
Watch yourself.
You're gonna get runned over.
若有个家伙踩到香蕉皮跌倒
可能都要带我回局里
NICKY: If a guy tripped over
a banana peel, they'd bring me in for it.
客气点
Be nice.
老大们也没好到哪儿去
他们抱怨事情运作不顺
NICKY: The bosses were no better.
They complained because things
don't run smooth.
不过在我这行
真抱歉，事情本来就不会顺
In my line of work,
things don't run so smooth. I'm sorry.
我每天对付的可是些三教九流之徒
I'm dealing with degenerate
animals out here.
老大们在乎个屁啊？
The bosses, what do they give a fuck?
他们只会坐着喝酒
They're sitting on their asses
drinking anisette.
而这期间我得做牛做马
Meanwhile, I'm the guy in the trenches.
那些王八老大们
真以为天下的午餐都是免费的
Fucking bosses think it's
a fucking free lunch out here.
法兰克，他们在沙漠里
找到一个家伙的头
Frankie, they found
a guy's head in the desert.
你知道吗？
You know about that?
听说了
I heard.
大家都在讲，报纸里也有登
Everybody's talking about it and making
a big deal out of it. It's in all the papers.
你要怎么办？
What are you gonna do?
这可不好
That's no good.
叫他做事要小心点
Tell him to take care of things a little better.
我会的，利蒙
I'll tell him, Remo.
王八老大们抽着雪茄
NICKY: Fucking bosses
smoking their Di Nobilis...
吃着他们的美食…
and eating trip' and fucking soffrit',
fried pigs' guts...
而我若想私下找人谈话
我还得坐在公车站
while if I wanna talk private,
I gotta go to a fucking bus stop.
-他们在乎个屁？只要我拿钱回去
-他们在抱怨了
-What do they care? Long as I send money.
-They're complaining.
让他们抱怨，是我在这儿
活都是我在做
Let them complain. I'm the one
who's here. I do all the work.
-有人不喜欢，就去他的
-你决定罗
NICKY: Somebody don't like it, fuck them.
FRANK: It's up to you.
他们他妈的想打仗？
我准备好了
NICKY: They want a fucking war? I'm ready.
我只要干掉那五个
其他的自然会水到渠成
If I take care of five of those guys,
the rest will fall into place.
被我抓到了吧，这群王八羔子
NICKY: Peek-a-boo, you fucks, you.
我看到你们了，混蛋
I see you, you motherfuckers.
问题是，尼奇不只是
让自己更受注目，还连累到我
SAM: Nicky was not only bringing heat
on himself, but on me, too.
联邦调查局盯着他的每一步
但他不在乎
The FBI watched every move he made,
but he just didn't care.
想要盯我，我就盯回去
NICKY: If they're gonna watch me,
I'm gonna watch them back.
或许花了很多钱
但谁在乎？
I spent a few bucks. Top dollar.
Who gives a shit?
我买了最先进的反窃听装置
向卖给中央情报局的那家买的
I got the latest anti-bugging equipment
from the same places that sell to the CIA.
我有所有的警察特殊频道对讲机
FBI的解干扰器、夜光照相机…
I had all the special police frequency radios,
FBI de-scramblers, night-vision cameras....
这些衰角从未抓到我任何把柄
So, the miserable sons of bitches never
caught me doing anything I couldn't handle.
我工作都快丢了
但他却玩得不亦乐乎
SAM: I got my job on the line,
he's having the time of his life.
全州的警察都在盯他
他却在打高尔夫球
He has every cop in the state watching him,
and he's out playing golf.
对我来说时期最坏不过
And at the worst possible time for me.
我的执照听证会要到了
我不想有一点点失败的机率
I had my license hearing coming up and
I didn't want to leave anything to chance.
若不能在赌城工作
那我要去哪儿？
If I can't work in Vegas,
where am I gonna go?
你一直都很合作
从文件到帐簿
You've been very open with us
with the books and papers.
这对委员会是很重要的
That'll mean a lot
when you go before the commission.
-我只希望能有个公正的听证会
-你的诚实会为你赢的
-All I ask is a fair hearing.
-This honesty will guarantee it.
[Plane engine sputtering]
接下来…
We'll move on to....
我想听听关于堪萨斯市
SAM: I want to hear about Kansas City.
这他妈的是什么？
What the fuck is this?
这家伙要停在哪里，球场上吗？
Where's this fucking guy gonna land,
in the fairway?
他们是探员，法兰克
来看看
They're fucking agents, Frankie.
Look at this.
他们盯尼奇打高尔夫盯到…
SAM: The Feds were watching
Nicky play golf for so long...
飞机没油
they ran out of gas.
还真是我需要的
就在委员会面前
Just what I needed,
right in front of the control board.
赌一百看谁先打到飞机
$100, whoever hits the plane.
祸不单行，随后就看到派斯康
堪萨斯市的老二
SAM: If things weren't bad enough...
in comes Piscano,
the Kansas City underboss.
在堪萨斯市收皮箱的那家超市
就是他开的
He ran the grocery store in Kansas City
where they brought the suitcases.
又在为皮箱的事吵了
你知道这代表什么吗？
Fighting over those suitcases again.
You know what that means?
我又得去拉斯维加斯了
又要花我好几千
I gotta take another trip to Vegas.
It's gonna cost me another couple grand.
他和他姐夫一起开店…
SAM: He ran it with his brother-in-law...
但他大多都在跟他姐夫与岳母
抱怨他去赌城的事
but he mostly complained about his trips
to Vegas to his brother-in-law and mother.
你得表明态度
要不然他们当你是病猫
You gotta lay down the law,
or they'll make a fool out of you.
我全记下来了，他妈的每一分一毛
I write it all down.
Every fucking nickel goes down.
-你是怎么了？
-全都在这儿
-What's the matter with you?
-Everything's here.
-你何时开始这样讲话？
-抱歉
-Since when do you talk like that?
-I'm sorry.
南斯要是找我麻烦
我就将他的眼挖出来
Nance gives me trouble, I'll
take the eyes out of his freaking head.
-又来了
-我没骂粗话
-Again.
-I didn't curse, I said, "freaking head."
-够了
-抱歉
-That's enough.
-I'm sorry.
接下来发生的事
简直是出乎意料
SAM: What happens next,
you can't believe it.
谁会想到联邦调查局
会在里面装窃听器…
Who'd believe the FBI
had a wire in the place...
为了调查很久以前的一桩命案…
looking for information
about some old homicide...
为了一个不知在何时
也不知为何事被干掉的人
about some guy who was whacked out
God knows when over God knows what?
你怎么阻止拿皮箱的人
拿走他想要的？
What prevents him with the suitcases
from taking what he wants?
南斯从坦吉乐拿了两口箱子回来
若其实有三箱或四箱呢？
Nance brings back two suitcases from
the Tangiers. What about three or four?
我们没有人在计算室里看着
那是法律
We've got nobody in the room to watch.
That's the law.
我们甚至连计算室都进不去
We can't even go into the count room
to watch our money.
他有他的人在里面
他们搞不好根本是一伙的
He's got his people in there.
They could all be in on it together.
若我知道是葛林干的
我会埋了那王八蛋
I'll find out. If it's Green himself,
I'll bury that bastard.
我从就不相信他
我后脑都有眼睛
I never trusted him.
I got eyes behind my head.
他们信任那混蛋，我可不
They trust that scumbag. I don't.
我该给他们一人一铲
I'll hit the two of them
in the head with a shovel.
冷静点
MA: Take it easy.
妈，抱歉
但他们一直跟我玩阴的
Ma, I'm sorry.
They're beating me left and right.
-抱歉，我很生气
-我知道，可是够了
ARTIE: I'm sorry. I'm upset.
I know, but that's enough.
你也知道他们在对我做什么
我受不了了
You know what they're doing to me.
I can't take this no more.
-冷静，别心脏病发
-我知道，我太气了
MA: Take it easy. You'll get a heart attack.
ARTIE: I know. I'm too upset.
该死的是，他们听得一清二楚…
SAM: The damn thing is,
they hear all this stuff...
关于拉斯维加斯，赌场还有皮箱…
about Las Vegas, casinos, and suitcases...
玩完了
and that's it.
[Sentimental swing music]
全都是从我口袋里掏
我得付钱
ARTIE: Everything's coming out
of my pocket. I gotta pay.
你相信有这么巧吗？
SAM: Would you believe this could happen?
华府
我是来赚钱的，不是亏钱
ARTIE: I'm in this to make money, not lose it.
全国每个联邦调查局探员
都张大了耳朵
SAM: Every FBI man
across the country had their ears open now.
要将事情办好就得靠自己
ARTIE: If you want something done right
you gotta do it yourself.
派司康这家伙
几乎搞砸了所有人的生活
SAM: Piscano, this guy,
basically sunk the whole world.
有些好的就有些坏的
MA: There are some that are good
and some that are bad.
1980年
COUNSELOR: Members
of the Commission...
主席先生
委员会的同仁…
今天罗斯坦先生很荣幸能在这儿
Mr. Rothstein is pleased to be here today.
当那天终于来时
我已准备好了
SAM: When the day finally came, I was ready.
我自信满满的认为
我只需要呈上我的案件
I felt so confident that all I had
to do was present my case.
我们拥有文件，其中一份是由
一位退休的联邦探员写的…
COUNSELOR: We have documents, one of
which is a report by retired FBI agents...
上头清楚的记载罗斯坦先生
并未触犯任何法律
which completely absolves Mr. Rothstein
from any wrongdoing.
-律师，在你继续前…
-我要将这呈为…
-Counselor, before you continue...
-I want to have this marked....
本委员会针对是否应
驳回罗斯坦的申请书在此动议
...this Commission acts on a motion
denying the Rothstein application.
-驳回？
-有人赞成驳回吗？
COUNSELOR: Denying?
SENATOR: Do I hear a motion seconded?
主席先生，我赞成
Mr. Chairman, I second the motion.
还有赞同票吗？
Do I have a vote on the motion?
同意！
-Aye!
Aye!
同意票获胜，听证会结束
The ayes have it. This hearing is adjourned.
-开什么玩笑
-什么叫结束？
-You have to be kidding.
-Adjourned? What do you mean?
议员，你答应我一场听证会的
你连联邦调查局的报告都没看
Senator, you promised me a hearing.
You didn't even look at the FBI reports.
你来坦吉乐作客时
不是答应我会有公平的听证会？
When you were my guest at the Tangiers
Hotel, didn't you promise me a fair hearing?
-我从未是你的客人
-不是我的客人？我没招待过你？
SENATOR: I was never your guest.
SAM: Never my guest? I never comped you?
难道我一个月
没有最少招待你三次？
I don't comp you
at least three times a month?
我现在回答这个问题
I'd like to answer that at this time.
罗斯坦先生的反应很常见
他在撒谎
Mr. Rothstein is being very typical
to this point. He's lying.
我唯一一次去过坦吉乐
就是巴尼葛林斯坦那次晚宴
The only time I was at the Tangiers
was a dinner with Barney Greenstein.
-我当时在场吗？
-你四处周旋着
Was I at the dinner?
SENATOR: You were wandering around.
-我在场吗？
-你四处周旋
SAM: Was I at that dinner?
SENATOR: You were wandering.
-你在室内
-我在室内？
SENATOR: You were in the building.
SAM: I was in the building?
你很清楚我在那儿
你向我保证会有公正的听证会
You know damn well I was there.
You swore I would have a fair hearing.
没有吗？
Did you not?
至少承认说我那天在场
这总可以了吧
Tell me I was at least at the dinner.
Allow me that much.
-至少也得说我在场吧！
-是，你在
SAM: Give me that much at least!
SENATOR: Yes, you were.
多谢你没说我是骗子
你这个狗东西
Thanks for not calling me a liar,
you son of a bitch.
一场例行的听证会
在昨晚成了一场闹剧…
A routine licensing hearing
turned into bedlam yesterday...
当抢眼的坦吉乐高层
山姆“艾斯”罗斯坦…
when the flamboyant Tangiers Casino
executive, Sam "Ace" Rothstein...
指控赌博游乐委员会高官贪污
accused top gaming officials of corruption.
你在我的旅馆接受招待
并答应我会有公平的听证会
...promised me a fair hearing
when you were comped at my hotel?
你还要求将你的帐单挂公帐
And you asked for copies of your bill
to put on your expense account.
当赌博游乐执照被驳回时大吼大叫…
In a wild outburst that followed his gaming
license denial...
Bullshit!
-狗屁！
-罗斯坦与好几名…
...Rothstein followed several...
错愕的委员到走道
并持续着他的指控…
stunned commissioners into the hallway
where he continued his harangue...
直到他的律师与朋友劝他离开
until his own lawyers and friends
urged him to leave.
你有过去，我也有过去
我的不见得比你的糟糕
You have a past. I have a past.
My past is no worse than yours.
你们还自以为有权去判决别人！
You guys think you have
the right to pass judgment!
被怀疑长期无照管理坦吉乐…
NEWSREADER: Long suspected
of running Tangiers without a license...
昨天的听证会本是要决议
像罗斯坦如此背景的人…
yesterday's hearing was to determine
if someone with Rothstein's history...
是否有资格正式在赌博游乐界
担任如此高的职位
was qualified to officially hold
a top gaming post.
罗斯坦玩完了
王八伪君子！
REMO: Fucking hypocrites!
-他现在怎么办？
-我不知道
-What the hell's he gonna do now?
-I don't know.
他在干嘛？
What's he doing?
他也知道他大吼大叫的那群人
都是我们的朋友
He knows all those guys he yelled at
are friends of ours.
他是怎么了，搞得一团糟？
What's the matter with him,
making all this mess?
他或许可以用另一个头衔管事
Maybe he could run things
with another job title.
这不是最好的
但我们又能如何呢？
Won't be the best,
but what are we gonna do?
他不论管什么，都得安静点
让他躲到楼上办公室去
REMO: However he runs things, it's gotta be
quiet. Let him hide upstairs in the office.
说他是工友，我不在乎
Say he's a janitor. I don't give a shit.
但拜托，不管他做什么
都得低调点
But please, whatever job he takes,
make sure it's something quiet.
各位先生与女士…
ANNOUNCER: [On TV]
Ladies and gentlemen...
坦吉乐大饭店
非常荣幸能为您介绍…
the Tangiers Hotel
proudly presents the all-new...
山姆罗斯坦秀，艾斯的单人牌
Sam Rothstein show, Aces High.
艾斯的单人牌
今晚，从最新的球赛赌区
现场实况转播…
Tonight, taped live
from the all-new sports book...
我们为您带来艾斯的单人牌的
首次演出…
we present the premiere showing
of Aces High...
连同莎夏西门诺夫交响乐团…
with the Sasha Semenoff Orchestra...
与山姆罗斯坦舞群！
and the Sam Rothstein dancers!
罗斯坦先生是位职业赌徒
也是全美最棒的美式足球下注者
Mr. Rothstein is a professional gambler
and the best U.S. football handicapper.
一位能带领你进入
真正的拉斯维加斯的人
A man who will take you inside the real
Las Vegas as no one has ever done before.
现在让我们欢迎
坦吉乐赌场新的娱乐董事…
Now, the new entertainment director
of the Tangiers Hotel Casino...
山姆罗斯坦先生
Mr. Sam Rothstein.
[Audience applauding]
[Band playing upbeat dance music]
欢迎来到山姆罗斯坦秀
很高兴你们能参与
Welcome to the Sam Rothstein show.
We're happy to have you here this evening.
我左边的这位小姐是特茹蒂…
The young lady to my left is Trudy...
她是我们巴黎秀新的首席舞者
who is a lead new dancer
in our fabulous show from Paris.
我们今晚的第一位来宾…
Our first guest this evening...
法兰克艾华伦
is Frankie Avalon.
-看好他
-我有个大家庭
PAT: Keep an eye on him.
FRANKIE: I've got a large family.
-你有几个孩子？
-我很自豪的说，八个
SAM: How many kids do you have?
I'm very proud to say, eight children.
-太了不起了
-没什么，是我的荣幸
-That's amazing.
-There's nothing to it. It was my pleasure.
[Audience laughing]
别这样
PHILIP: Ace, don't do it.
天啊
Jesus.
他在耍杂技！
He's juggling!
我们别对县辅导
派特委布太认真
SAM: Let's not take County Commissioner
Pat Webb too seriously.
我最近本想邀他在节目上辩论的
但是他拒绝了
I recently challenged him to a debate
on this program, and he declined.
你在担心什么呢，派特？
你不需要事先给我问题
What are you worried about, Pat?
You don't have to send me any questions.
你什么都可以问我
You can ask me anything you want.
他在电视上干嘛？
ANDY: What the hell is he doing
on television?
他整晚都在上面
喊着要将他的案子告上最高法院
He's on all night, screaming about
taking his lawsuit to the Supreme Court.
他真是疯了
他想将这带到华府去？
He really must be crazy.
He's gonna go to Washington with this?
他简直是疯了
He's out of his fucking mind.
世上有这样的伪君子真是可叹
他们爱做什么就做什么
It's a pity we have such hypocrisy.
Some people do what they want.
其他人却得承担后果
这就是人生
Other people have to pay
through the nose. Such is life.
安迪，去找他
告诉他辞职的时候到了
Andy, go see him. Tell him
maybe it's time he should quit.
第一点，他们的所做所为
完全的违反了宪法
SAM: First, what they did
was totally unconstitutional.
我们已在高等法院的等候单上了
SAM: We're on the list to be heard before
the U.S. Supreme Court.
这些家伙才不在乎高等法院
These guys don't care
about the Supreme Court.
他们要一切平息，要你别再搞了
They want things to quiet down.
They want you to walk away.
别搞了？安迪，你不是说真的
你难道看不到这严重性吗？
Walk away? Andy, you can't be serious.
Don't you see what's at stake?
老头说你的朋友或许该罢手了
The old man said maybe
your friend should give in.
当老头说“或许”时
就像是教皇发谕令一样
When the old man says "maybe,"
that's like a papal bull.
你不但该罢手，还该跑路
Not only should you quit, you should run.
他们每次在报上提到我的名字
就一定扯到尼奇
Every time they mention my name
in the papers, they mention Nicky, too.
这他妈的有什么帮助？
How the fuck does that help?
他带来的注目简直是谋杀
The heat he brought down is murder.
警察局本来很合作
The police department was cooperative.
他将他们激怒到
现在大家都动不了
They're pissed off.
Nobody can make a move anymore.
你能怎样呢？
What do you do about that?
-你想说什么？
-我不知道，他根本不听我的
-What are you proposing?
-I don't know. He doesn't listen to me.
或许他才该消失一阵子
这样会很糟吗？
Maybe he should get lost for a while.
Would that be so bad?
-他们不会调走尼奇的
-若他离开一阵…
-They ain't sending Nicky nowhere.
-If he took a break...
给大家移动布局的机会
it would give everybody time to maneuver.
别再搞布局的事
赶紧离开吧
I would forget about the maneuver.
I would just get out.
[Sighs]
我不能
I can't do that.
当然，安迪一到家后
尼奇就听说我们的谈话
SAM: Of course, as soon as Andy got home,
Nicky heard about our talk in the car.
第二天一大早，我就接到电话
Next morning, bright and early,
I get the call.
我得去买点东西，你要不要去？
I've got to do some shopping. Want to go?
连接尼奇的电话都不是件易事
SAM: Getting a call from Nicky
wasn't easy anymore.
暗号都没有用了
我们得想新方法
Even the codes didn't work.
So we figured out another act.
若是电话被窃听
他们只能听关于犯罪的谈话
If a phone's tapped, the Feds can only
listen in on the stuff involving crimes.
例行通话时
他们必须在几分钟后挂断
On routine calls, they have
to click off after a few minutes.
我手肘好像扭到了
GINGER: I got a sprained fucking elbow.
三点见
Meet me at 3:00.
-在凯撒宫吗？
-这条路下去再一百码处
-At Caesar's?
-100 yards further down the road.
-为什么？
-别问了，到那儿就是了
-Why?
-Don't ask questions. Just be there.
苏西克理姆有件一模一样的衣服
Suzy Cream Cheese has the same outfit.
我看到个东西
GINGER: I saw something.
这东西好可爱
Something very cute.
他出门了，棕组
AGENT: Okay, he's out. It's the ant.
Brown unit.
他带着个替身，应该是法兰克
He's with the bogey. I think it's Frankie.
尼奇比我早出门…
SAM: Nicky started out before me...
因为他要出门越来越难了
because it wasn't that easy for him
to get around anymore.
尼奇到那儿都最起码得…
Nicky couldn't even go
for a ride without changing cars...
换六次车才甩得掉跟踪他的人
at least six times
before he could shake all his tails.
因为有飞机
所以他得用地下停车场
Because of the planes,
he had to use underground garages.
[Upbeat rock music]
在沙漠中央会面总让我紧张
SAM: Meeting in the desert
always made me nervous.
那是个可怕的地方
It's a scary place.
我当然也知道沙漠里的洞
I knew about the holes
in the desert, of course.
我张望的每一处都可能是个洞
And everywhere I looked,
there could have been a hole.
通常我与尼奇会面
能活着回来…
Normally, my prospects
of coming back alive...
机率是百分之九十九
from a meeting with Nicky
were 99 out of 100.
但这次，当我听他说
离道路几百码外…
But this time, when I heard him say a
couple of hundred yards down the road...
我想应该还有一半的机率吧
I gave myself 50-50.
[Sentimental instrumental music]
你他妈的跟别人
在背后捅我是什么意思？
Where the fuck you get off
talking to people behind my back?
-跟什么人？
-你以为我不会发现吗？
-What people?
-Did you think I wouldn't find out?
我根本不知道你在说什么
I don't even know what you're talking about.
你说我害你被盯？
我得因为你被人家念？
You said I'm bringing heat on you?
I gotta listen to people because of you?
你想搞走我？
你最好准备好自己的军队？
You're ordering me out? You better get
your own fucking army!
我没有要搞走任何人
I didn't order you or anybody.
我跟安迪说你被盯上了
这是个问题
I told Andy Stone that you had heat,
and that was a problem.
你想要我离开我自己的地盘？
You want me to get out
of my own fucking town?
是啊，我说等风头过了
我才能好好经营赌场
Yeah, let the bullshit blow over
so I can run the casino.
赌场出了什么事我得负责，不是你
Anything goes wrong
with the casino, it's my ass, not yours.
你知道你之所以能管那狗屁赌场
都是因为我！
You know that you only have your fucking
casino because I made that possible!
在这儿我才算数
I'm what counts out here.
不是你他妈的什么俱乐部
也不是你那狗屁电视秀
Not your fucking country clubs
or your fucking TV shows.
你他妈的在电视上干嘛？
And what the fuck
are you doing on TV anyhow?
我每天都得接老家的电话
他们都觉得你疯了！
I get calls from back home every day.
They think you went batshit!
我上电视是因为
我必须待在赌场
I'm only on TV because I gotta be able
to hang around the casino. You don't understand that....
你不上电视也可以拿那餐饮的头衔！
You could've had the food-and-beverage
job without going on TV!
-是你想上电视吧
-对，我想上电视
-You wanted to go on TV.
-Yeah, I wanted to go on TV.
这样我才有擂台，我才可以反击
我要有知名度
That way I have a forum. I can fight back.
I'm known. People see me
若我有知名度他们就不能
随随便便打发我
They know they can't fuck around with
me like they could if I was an unknown.
That's why
你将自己变成个笑话
You're making a spectacle of yourself.
要不是你，我也不会落到这步田地
I wouldn't even be in this situation
if it wasn't for you.
你让我被盯上
You brought down so much heat on me.
我每次遇见个人
他们都只想知道我认不认识你
Every time I meet somebody,
they ask me if I know you.
所以你现在要将你执照的那件事
怪到我的头上
Sure, now you wanna blame
your fucking license on me.
当你请示我你可不可以来这儿时…
When you asked me
if you could come out here...
我是怎么说的？我就知道
不管我说什么你都会来，记得吗？
what did I tell you? I knew you'd come out
no matter what I said. Do you remember?
等一下，倒退一下
Back up a fucking minute here. One minute.
我请示你？我他妈的什么时候
请示过你我可不可以来这儿？
I asked you? When the fuck
did I ever ask you if I could come out here?
搞清楚点，死犹太人！
NICKY: Get this through your head,
you Jew motherfucker!
你是因我才在这儿！
只因为这样！
You only exist out here because of me!
That's the only reason!
要没有我，你自己…
Without me, you personally....
在这儿随便哪个还在混的
都可能宰了你！
Every fucking wise guy still around will
take a piece of your fucking Jew ass!
到时你怎么办？
我警告你了
Then where you gonna go?
You're fucking warned.
别想再踩在我头上
你这个王八蛋！
Don't go over my fucking head again,
you motherfucker, you!
[Rhythmic pop music]
有客人
Well, we got company.
看到了吗？
Did you see that?
蠢犹太人，我们一起长大的
他竟装作不认识我
Dumb Jew motherfucker. Grew up together,
and he acts like he doesn't know me.
我知道我们应该避免碰面
不过应该有其他办法吧
I know we're supposed to avoid each
other, but there's ways to do things.
去他的
Fuck him.
敬林肯总统
To Abraham Lincoln.
算了，别让这烦你
Forget about it. Don't let it bother you.
我看来很烦躁吗？
我为什么要在乎？
Does it look like it's bothering me?
Why do I give a fuck?
奥斯卡也是的
我给了他那么多钱，混蛋
Oscar, too.
All the money I gave him, that prick.
他连看都不看这边
他到底是什么毛病？
He didn't even look over.
What's his fucking problem?
-死犹太人都是一伙的，不是吗？
-他们好像玩得很快乐
-Fucking Jews stick together, don't they?
-They're having a good time.
我们也是啊
So are we.
[Phone ringing]
喂？
Yeah?
-山姆，有麻烦
-怎么了？
-Sam, we got a problem.
-What is it?
那矮子，没人跟他说
他被禁止进入赌场
BILLY: The little guy. Nobody told him
he was eighty-sixed from the joint.
我们只要都假装不认识他
We turned our heads and made out
like we didn't know who he was.
他现在在21点桌大剌剌的豪赌
He's over at the 21 table
with his nose wide open.
他从他那份抽头里拿钱
已经输了一万了
He took money out of his own kick.
His nose is open for about $10,000.
现在他很生气
Now he's really pissed.
-他要五万的筹码
-给他一万就好了
-He wants a $50,000 marker.
-Just give him $10,000.
就这样，我马上来
That's it. I'll be right down.
就如你所要求
他会去拿一万
He's gonna come up with $10,000
just the way you want.
不，我他妈的说五万！
No, I said fucking $50,000!
给我去拿
我不在乎你用什么方法
Go get it. I don't give a fuck
where you get it.
王八蛋
只会拿钱却不还来
Fuckers. They take it
but don't wanna give it back.
[Upbeat rock music]
你还笑得出来？
How the fuck can you grin?
你知道我输多少了吗？
你在乎吗？
You know how much I'm stuck?
Do you give a fuck?
给自己点掌声吧
顺便加一巴掌
Give yourself a hand,
right across your fucking mouth.
看看现在上来的这个怪胎
Look at this beaut they put in now.
雪伯提派你来抢我的吗？
NICKY: Sherbert send you in here
to rob me now?
你今晚帕撕芫昧税桑坑很多喔？
Been fucking knocking everybody's dick
in all night? Been beating the customers?
再来一张
Jag-off. Hit me.
将这张牌从你后面塞进去
Take this stiff and pound it
up your fucking ass.
再来一张
Hit me again.
这张捅你姐姐后面去，再来一张
Take this one and stick it
up your sister's ass. Hit me again.
一直看他干嘛，你要还有良心
你就宁可去当小偷
Keep looking at him. If you had any heart
at all, you'd be stealing for a living.
再给我一张
你他妈的一直看他干嘛？
Hit me again! What the fuck
you keep looking at him for?
你这，你看看
连二十张公，再来一张
You fucking.... Look at this,
20 points in a row. Hit me again.
你给钱应该跟拿钱一样快吧
NICKY: You should pay as fast
as you collect, you know.
-你得走了
-叫那王八蛋付筹码
-You gotta get out of here.
-Tell this motherfucker to pay that marker.
你没在听，我是来帮你的
你会将我们俩都毁了
You're not listening. I'm here to help you.
You're gonna bury us both.
-把钱给我
-我只批准一万，就这样
-Just give me the money.
-I'm gonna okay you $10,000, that's it.
然后你得在条子找到你之前给我走
Then you gotta get out
before the cops are all over you.
就一万
$10,000 and that's it.
你在看什么？
你这秃头的死犹太人
What are you staring at,
you bald-headed Jew prick?
-快，我们快走
-告我啊，死犹太人！
-Come on. Let's get out of here.
-Sue me, you Jew fuck!
走？
我有筹码要来耶，发牌
NICKY: Get out of here?
I got a marker coming. Deal.
我知道，但现在情况不同了
你要求的是离婚
I know, but everything's changed now.
You're talking about a divorce.
你要求你与孩子的赡养费
现在又要孩子的监护权
You're asking for alimony payments
and child support, and now custody.
我只要任何一个离婚女人想要的
I just want what any
divorced woman would get.
她一天不过清醒两个小时
She's only sober about two hours a day.
通常是早上十一点到下午一点
It's usually from 11:00 a.m. to 1:00 p.m.
我要是给她钱与珠宝
她一年内就会浪费光了
If I gave her her money and her jewels,
she's gonna piss it all away in a year.
到时你怎么办？
还不是又回来找我…
Where would you be then?
Coming right back to me...
或找什么其他的理由回来…
or finding some other excuse to come....
我们有协议，记得吗？
We had a deal. Remember that?
他说过若我们之间走不下去
我可以拿我的东西走
He said if it didn't work out between us,
I could get my things and leave.
看着我
Look in my eyes.
你知道我
SAM: You know me.
你看到任何迹象
让你觉得…
Do you see anything that makes
you think I would ever let...
以你现在的状况
我会将我的孩子交给你？
someone in your condition
take my child away from me?
有吗？
Do you?
你知道这不可能
You know that won't happen.
过了这么久…
SAM: And after all this time...
不管我多么努力，多么想…
and as hard as I tried, as much as I wanted...
我始终触碰不到她
I could never reach her.
我无法让她爱我
I could never make her love me.
我总觉得她会爱我
那么多的钱…
I always felt she should have gone
for all that money...
第一次在生命中成为一个重要的人
一个家、孩子
being somebody for the first time
in her life, a home, a kid.
但事实并非如此
那样做却行不通
That's not what happened.
It didn't work out that way.
-都好吗？
-我们能怎么办？
Everything all right?
SAM: What could we do?
过一阵子后，我们开始放对方的假
短期的不见面
After a while, we'd just take breathers
from each other. Little separations.
那时，我记得金吉儿
带着艾美去比佛利山庄
At that time, I remember Ginger
took Amy and went to Beverly Hills.
她要去逛一个礼拜的街
She was gonna spend a week shopping.
-是的，罗斯坦先生
-比佛利大饭店
OPERATOR: Yes, Mr. Rothstein.
The Beverly Hotel in Beverly Hills.
-你好，比佛利大饭店
-请找山姆罗斯坦夫人
RECEPTIONIST: Hello, Beverly Hotel.
SAM: Mrs. Sam Rothstein, please.
很抱歉，罗斯坦先生与夫人
已经退房了
RECEPTIONIST: Sorry, Mr. and Mrs.
Rothstein have checked out already.
罗斯坦先生与夫人？
Mr. and Mrs. Rothstein?
-是的，他们俩都退房了
-谢谢
RECEPTIONIST: Yes, they both checked out.
SAM: Thank you.
[Phone ringing]
喂
Hello.
我老婆跟她一个老朋友在洛杉矶
My wife is with an old friend of hers in L.A.
一个叫莱斯特戴蒙德的败类
Some lowlife named Lester Diamond.
我女儿跟他们在一起
他们会试着绑架她
My daughter's with them.
They're gonna try and kidnap her.
-你那边有人吗？
-我们会帮你搞定
SAM: Is there anybody you can send?
MAN: We'll take care of it.
[Doorbell rings]
查到电话号码与住址了
We got a number and an address.
喂，是莱斯特吗？
SAM: Hello. Is this Lester?
哪位？
Who's calling?
我是山姆罗斯坦
我要跟金吉儿讲话
This is Sam Rothstein.
I want to talk to Ginger.
她不在这儿，山姆
She's not here, Sam.
你给我听好
我要跟金吉儿说话
Listen to me very carefully.
I want to talk to Ginger.
我要我的孩子
我要她马上搭下班飞机回来
I want my kid back.
I want her put on a plane immediately.
-我知道她在，别玩把戏
-山姆，我没有
SAM: I know she's there. Don't fuck around.
LESTER: I wouldn't.
你不应这么做
You shouldn't do this.
你懂不懂？叫她听电话
SAM: You understand?
Put her on the fucking phone.
山姆，我不知道她在哪儿
Sam, I don't know where she is.
听着，我可以待会儿打给你吗？
LESTER: So, listen,
can I call you back in a few minutes?
702-472-1862
SAM: 702-472-1862.
-我马上回你
-马上
LESTER: I'll call back.
SAM: Right away.
-马上
-好的
-Right back.
-You got it.
白痴，好了
我多拖了一些时间
Schmuck. All right,
I just bought us a few minutes.
你想报复吗？
LESTER: You want to get back at this prick?
那保险箱里有两百万对吧？
LESTER: You got what, $2 million
in that box?
喂，耽误你一下？
他保险箱里有两百万对吧？
You got a minute?
He's got $2 million in the box, right?
珠宝就留给他，我们拿走现金…
You let him keep your jewels.
We take the cash...
与他唯一在乎的另一件东西
他的小公主
and the only other thing he cares about.
Her majesty.
我们去欧洲，你把头发染了
We go to Europe. You dye your hair.
我不要去欧洲
我要去看The Elephant Man
I don't want to go to Europe.
I want to go to see The Elephant Man.
我们要去欧洲，让大人讲话
你去染头发
We're going to Europe.
Let the adults talk. You dye your hair.
像我们所说的去整容
You get plastic surgery like we talked about.
你觉得他会愿意付多少赎金？
How much you think he'll pay
to get this kid back?
-我不要去欧洲
-你给我闭嘴
AMY: I don't want to go to Europe.
LESTER: Shut your mouth.
-你才闭嘴
-你要我过来？
AMY: You shut up.
LESTER: Want me to come over?
我一巴掌打死你，别找我麻烦！
LESTER: I'll smack your face.
Don't give me your shit!
这本来是个梦
但现在要实现了
This has always been a dream,
but now we're going.
-莱斯特，他打到这儿来
-他刚在电话上
-Lester, he called you here.
-Right. Ace was on the phone.
-我刚跟他讲完
-所以他知道你在哪儿
-I just talked to him.
-So he knows where you are.
这表示他现在就派人过来了
That means he's sending some
guys over here now.
这表示他在电话旁像个蠢蛋…
It means he's sitting
by the phone, like a dumbbell....
对，他就像是蠢蛋坐在电话旁
等你打给他！
GINGER: Yeah, he's sitting by the phone
waiting for you to call him back!
我们该怎么办？他可能
已经派人在门外守着了！
What are we gonna do? He's probably
got guys outside the fucking house!
-又是你在那儿鬼扯！
-快拿行李，快走！
-It's this fucking bullshit of yours!
-Get your bag! Let's go!
-什么鬼扯？你想现在讨论这吗？
-你唠叨完了没？
-What bullshit? You want to talk it over?
-Are you done yakking?
快！快上车！
Go! Get in the car!
冷静点，没人要被杀
Just relax. Nobody's killing anybody.
-他一定会杀了我
-冷静点
GINGER: I think he's gonna kill me.
NICKY: Relax.
一个小时后打这支电话给我
我想想办法
Call me back here in exactly an hour
on this phone. I'll see what I can do.
我一个小时后打给你…
I'll call you back in an hour at this number...
-你会接对不对？
-我会在
-and you'll be there, right?
-I'll be here.
听着，别再做什么蠢事了
你还好吗？
Listen, don't do anything else crazy.
You all right?
好，再见
Okay, bye.
-停止
-是她开始的
GINGER: Knock it off.
LESTER: She started it.
都是她开始的
She started the whole thing.
-你别想开车
-我来开
-Don't even think you're gonna drive.
-I'm gonna drive.
-我可不想坐疯婆子开的车
-你快把我搞疯了！
LESTER: I'm not gonna drive
with a crazy woman.
You're driving me nuts!
滚到旁边去！
我要将这小鬼装箱寄到玻利维亚去！
Get on the passenger side!
I'm sending this kid to Bolivia in a box!
我们能不能…
Can we....
[Pop music plays loudly on radio]
金吉儿打给我
Ginger called me.
Yeah?
-我说她打给我
-她想怎样？
NICKY: I just told you she called me.
SAM: What'd she want?
她不敢打给你
She was afraid to call you.
她又跟那败类在一起了
艾美在他们手上
She's with that cocksucker again.
They got Amy.
她想回来，可是她害怕你会杀了她
She wants to come back, but she's afraid
you're gonna whack her out.
他们想绑架我的孩子
你觉得我会怎样？
They're gonna kidnap my kid.
What do you want?
我知道，你怎么不来找我？
这是家务事，不是公事
I know. Why didn't you come to me?
This is family. It ain't business.
你却打电话回老家
这样让我们很难看
Meanwhile, you made calls back home.
It makes us look bad out here.
这样来来回回
Back and forth, this one and that one.
在这期间她也一样会跑了
不是吗？
In the meantime, she's gone anyway.
Am I right?
我该拿这女人怎么办？
What am I going to do with this woman?
-快把我搞疯了
-我觉得你…
SAM: Driving me fucking crazy.
NICKY: I think if you...
应该保证不会动她，她才会回来
assure her that she's gonna be
all right, she'll come back.
简直被她搞疯了
Driving me fucking crazy.
她回来后你再从长计议
NICKY: Once you get her here, think about it.
最起码先把孩子弄回来
她也想回来
Wait till you get the kid back.
She wants to come back.
这才是重点
That's the main thing here.
你要孩子不是吗？
You want your kid, don't you?
[Phone rings]
喂
SAM: Hello.
是我，你迫不及待
想跟我讲话吧？
Hi, it's me. Just who you wanted
to talk to, right?
听着，我不会问你人在哪儿
Listen, I'm not gonna
ask you where you are.
只是请你将艾美马上
送上飞机回来
Just, please, put Amy on a plane
to get her here right away.
-我别无所求
-你…
SAM: That's all I'm asking.
GINGER: Do you....
我是说，我不觉得
她应该一个人回去
I mean, I don't think
she should go by herself.
你这是什么意思？
What do you mean?
我是说…
What I mean is--
如果我回去…
Do you think if I came back....
你可以原谅我吗？
Do you think you could forgive me?
老实说，我不知道
I gotta tell you, I don't know.
我了解
I understand that.
我知道我搞砸了
I know I fucked up.
-那钱呢？盒子呢？
-老实说…
-What about the money? Where's the box?
-I gotta tell you...
我做错事了
我花了一些钱
I made some mistakes,
and I spent some money.
-少很多吗？
-蛮多的
SAM: What's it under?
GINGER: Pretty serious.
-多少
-两万五以下
SAM: How serious?
GINGER: It's under $25,000.
-两万五以下？
-对
SAM: It's under $25,000?
GINGER: Yeah.
-剩下的两百万还在吗？
-在，其他的都还在
SAM: The $2 million is still there?
GINGER: Yeah, I got the rest.
好吧，没关系
Okay, no big deal. That's okay.
他拿了两万五
He got his $25,000.
我可以接受，再多就不行了
That I'll live with. Any more, I couldn't.
好
Okay.
好啦，你在哪里？
我马上派飞机去接你
All right, all right. Where are you?
I'll send a plane for you right away.
嗨，山姆
Hi, Sam.
你拿去干嘛了？
So what'd you do with it?
什么？
With what?
钱啊
With the money.
他需要些衣服
He needed some clothes.
两万五买衣服？
$25,000 for clothes?
他还要了只表
He wanted a watch, too.
两万五买衣服和表？
$25,000 for clothes and a watch?
晚安夫人，这边请
GINO: Good evening, signora. This way.
好事是艾美回来了
SAM: The good part was I had Amy back.
我们回家，请管家来过夜
然后送孩子上床
So we went home, had the housekeeper
stay over, put the kid to bed.
我逼自己冷静
然后我们出门吃饭
I calmed myself down,
and we went to dinner.
我试着让一切缓和…
I tried to keep things nice and civil...
但是两万五买三套西装？
but $25, 000 for three suits?
这不太合理
That doesn't make much sense.
第一点，他不可能穿
一千元一套的西装
First of all, he's not gonna wear
$1,000 suits.
就算假设他穿，虽然他不会
Let's say he did, which he won't.
三天内怎么可能
量身订做25套西装？
How you gonna get fitted
for 25 suits in three days?
怎么可能量得那么快？
I mean, how could you get fitted that fast?
我付两倍的钱都不可能那么快
I can't get fitted that fast,
and I pay twice as much.
我还帮他买了只表
I bought him a watch, too.
就算是买了只好表
一只他认为是好的表…
But even if you bought him a really nice
watch, one that he thought was nice...
他根本不知道好表长什么样子
he doesn't know
what the fuck a good watch is.
假设表价在五千
最多一万二，对他来说也不可能
Say you go $5,000 to $12,000
at the most, which is impossible for him.
加上三套一千一套的西装
还剩多少？
Plus, at the most, three suits,
$1,000 apiece. That still leaves what?
-差不多一万左右
-山姆，可以停止吗？
-Around $10,000?
-Would you knock it off, Sam?
-我只是想算清楚
-没什么好算的
SAM: I'm just trying to figure it out.
GINGER: There's nothing to figure out.
我回家了，我们在协调
I'm home. We're working it out.
可是我以前也听过
“我们在协调”
But I've been told before,
"We're working it out."
你以为你回家…
You think that you're home...
在你对我与艾美所做的一切后
算是给我面子吗？
after what you just put me
through with Amy, is a favor to me?
加上表，假设你们这个周末
花费了四千好了…
Counting the watch, let's say
another $4,000 for expenses this weekend...
我相信你们一定过得很愉快
of which you must have had a good time.
至少我很确定他很愉快
I know he did. That's for sure.
我知道那狗杂种一定很快乐
I know that fucking piece
of shit had a good fucking time.
花我的钱
On my money.
你干脆就跟他上床算了
你八成也这样做了
You might as well have fucked him,
which you probably did anyway.
你看我的表情很奇怪
You're looking at me a certain way.
你热泪盈眶
You're teary-eyed.
你很难过
你真是个好演员
You're upset.
You're a good actress, you know that?
真他妈的演得好
Good fucking actress.
你可让任何人可怜你
SAM: You can fucking get pity out of people.
但我不是嫖客，好吗？
I'm not a john. You understand?
你一直以为我是
但我不是，我也不是冤大头
You always thought I was,
but I'm not. And I'm not a sucker.
那可恶的拉皮条狗杂碎
That fucking pimp cocksucker.
上次没杀了他是他命好
He's lucky I didn't kill him last time.
他活着是命好
若你们带着艾美…
SAM: Lucky he's fucking living.
If you would have stayed with Amy...
然后走人的话
他就死定了
and you had run away,
he would have been dead.
你们俩都死定了
Both of you. Dead.
Dead.
不，不公平
GINGER: No, it isn't fair.
他晚上根本不回家
有什么了不起？
He doesn't come home at night.
What is the big fucking deal?
我走，听着，我真的受不了
I go.... Listen, I just can't fucking take it.
我为什么要忍受？
这不是我们的协议
Why should I fucking take it?
That wasn't the deal.
他一副好像就只有我有过去的样子
He acts like I'm the only one
around here with a fucking past.
他永远都不让我忘记
He'll never let me live it down.
是，我试过，我当然试过
Well, yes, I have tried. Of course I've tried.
你以为我为什么回来？
What the fuck do you think
I came back here for?
不，我不，我想杀了他
No, I'm not. I want to have him killed.
对，我要杀了他
我受够了
GINGER: I want him killed. I've had it.
你要帮我吗？
So are you with me on this?
你想干掉我？我就在这儿
You want to get rid of me? Here I am.
来啊，干掉我啊
Go ahead. Get rid of me.
-喂
-是的！
SAM: Hello.
GINGER: Yes, I do!
我恨死你了！我受不了了！
GINGER: I fucking hate you!
I can't take it anymore!
是，我要杀了你！
我恨死你了！
Yes, I want to kill you!
I hate your fucking guts!
你恨死我了？
我要你现在就给我过来！
SAM: You hate my guts?
I want you to come with me now!
我要你滚！
SAM: I want you out of here!
拿好行李给我滚！
Take your fucking bag and get out of here!
我会走，但我现在就要我的钱！
I'll go, but I want my money right now!
-你会拿到钱的！别担心
-协议结束了
-You'll get your money! Don't worry.
-The arrangement is over.
-废话！
-我还是拿得到钱
SAM: No kidding!
GINGER: And I still get my money.
我现在就要一些现金
你不能就这样把我赶出街！
I need some cash now!
You can't just put me in the street!
你从一认识我就没诚实过！
You've never been straight with me
ever since I met you!
你从一开始就没爱过我！
You never even loved me in the first place!
跟你这婊子一起
我连脑后都得长眼睛！
I need eyes in the back
of my head with you, you bitch!
我怎么爱你？
你对我像对条狗一样！
How could I love you?
You treat me like I'm your fucking dog!
-你连狗都不如！
-去你的！
SAM: You're lower than a dog!
GINGER: Fuck you!
拿去！够了没？
Here! Is this enough money?
可以活两天吗？拿去！
Will it last you two fucking days? Take it!
-贪得无厌的婊子，钱拿去
-我要去银行…
-Greedy bitch. Take the fucking money.
-I'm going to the bank...
-我还要去拿我的珠宝！
-早上9点开，去拿啊
-and I'm getting my jewelry, too!
-It opens at 9:00 a.m. Be there.
别叫你的人去阻止我！
我说真的！
Don't send your guys down there
to stop me! I mean it!
我向你保证我绝对不会阻止你
I guarantee you, I will not stop you.
你别想以一口箱子就打发我！
You're not getting rid of me
with one fucking suitcase!
剩下的明天再回来拿吧
给我滚
Come back tomorrow and get the rest.
Just get out of here.
-我要带艾美走
-不行
GINGER: I'm taking Amy.
SAM: You're not.
我要，我现在去叫她
I am. I'm waking her up right now.
你w药了，你这个毒虫
给我滚
SAM: You're stoned. You're a junkie.
Get out of here.
我不是！她也是我女儿！
I am not! She's my daughter, too!
写信给我的律师吧，去你的！
SAM: Send my lawyers a letter,
god-fucking-damn you!
你跑不掉的！
你别想不遵守你的诺言！
GINGER: You're not getting away with this!
You're not gonna cut me out of my end!
王八蛋！
GINGER: Fucker!
[Car engine stops]
[Car door closes]
[Approaching footsteps]
好笑的是，经过这么多事
我还是不想让她走
SAM: The funny thing was,
after all that, I didn't want her to go.
她是我孩子的妈，我爱她
She was the mother of my kid. I loved her.
后来，我发现我并不想
将钱给她，因为我若给了…
Later, I realized I didn't want
to give her the money because if I did...
我知道将再也见不到她
I knew I'd never see her again.
在学校要开开心心的喔
Have a good day at school, okay?
好的，天使
Okay, angel.
从现在起，我随时都得知道
你与艾美在哪儿
From now on, I have to know
where you and Amy are at all times.
这是呼叫器
SAM: Here's a beeper.
我要你拿着
I want you to keep it on you.
很轻
It's very light.
让我可以随时打给你
SAM: So I can call you whenever I have to.
好吗？
Okay?
你能怎么做？
你想怎么做呢？
NICKY: What are you supposed to do?
What do you wanna do?
你想就像现在这样吗？
你也不能啊
You want to stay the way you are?
You can't do that.
两个人若合不来
总要有人出来说…
Two people don't get along,
at some point you gotta call it....
这不关我的事
但我觉得你应该这样做
It's not my business,
but I think that's what you gotta do.
你说得对，我知道
You're right. I know.
-我只是…
-什么？
-I was just--
-What?
-没什么
-你想说什么？
-Nothing.
-What were you gonna say?
-我不…
-告诉我你本来想说什么
-I don't--
-Tell me what you were gonna say.
真的？
Yeah?
我在想说你有没有认识
银行的人…
I was thinking maybe
you know somebody at the bank...
可以帮我把珠宝拿出来？
who could help me get my jewelry out?
有很多钱在那儿
There's a lot of money in there.
我愿意重赏任何可以帮助我的人
I'd be willing to take care
of anybody who helped me out.
我想想办法
Let me think about that.
我看看能找谁
一定得是可以信得过的人
Let me see who I got.
Gotta get somebody I can trust.
你也知道他是不会把珠宝给我的
You know he's never gonna
give me my jewelry.
他把那把钥匙抓得很紧
我看就差没藏到屁眼里去了
He holds that key so tight,
he's probably got it stuck up his ass.
说得好，真像是山姆
You're right. That's Sammy.
搞不好真的就在那儿
And he's probably got it there, too.
他真是命大，我本可以埋了他
He's so fucking lucky.
I could have buried him.
我本可以去欧洲并把孩子带走
I could have gone to Europe
and taken the baby.
那他可能就会找到我
并把我杀了
Then he'd have tracked me down,
and he'd have killed me.
不，他不会，但我会
No, he wouldn't. I would have.
-不过他是没错
-别闹了
-He'd have been right, too. Seriously.
-Come on.
你不能就这样把他的孩子带走
You don't take a guy's kid and then take off.
我没有，我本来有
但后来我照你所说的回家了
I didn't. I did, but then I did exactly
what you told me to do, and I came back.
你是，你照做了，很好
You did. You're right. I like that.
-我喜欢这样，你做对了
-我听了你的话
-That's what I like, you did the right thing.
-I did what you told me to.
-是的
-你总会告诉我正确的做法
-Yes, you did.
-You always tell me the right thing to do.
他真的在这儿把自己搞砸了
不是吗？
He really fucked himself up
out here, didn't he?
-是啊
-这一切改变了他的想法
-He sure did.
-Everything went to his head.
改变了
Changed.
-他变了，他已不是同一个人了
-不，他不是
-He did. He ain't the same person.
-No, he's not.
-他真的觉得自己多了不起
-的确
-He really thinks who the fuck he is.
-Exactly.
他恨我
He hates me.
他好恨我
He hates my fucking guts.
别这样，你最坚强了
这不算什么
Come on, you're a toughie.
You can take this.
-别哭
-我没你想像的坚强
NICKY: Don't cry.
GINGER: I'm not as tough as you think I am.
你有
Yes, you are.
我没有，我好怕他
I'm not, and he scares the shit out of me.
-我永远都不知道他下步要干嘛
-别这样
-I never know what he's gonna do.
-Come on.
-别怕
-我需要帮助
-Don't be scared.
-I need some help.
我需要帮助
I need some help.
你得帮我
You gotta help me.
我需要个新靠山
I need a new sponsor, Nicky.
真的，我需要个新的靠山
I do. I need a new sponsor.
-这是你想要的？
-是啊
-Is that what you want?
-Yeah.
-靠山？
-是的
-A sponsor?
-Yeah.
好，别担心
没人敢动你的
Okay. Don't worry about it.
Nobody will fuck with you anymore.
我会照顾你的
I'll take care of you.
-谢谢你
-这是你想要的，不是吗？
GINGER: Thank you.
NICKY: It's what you want, isn't it?
[Sentimental R&B music]
艾斯的老婆
MAN: That's Ace's wife.
这给老板看太好了
MAN 2: This is great for the boss.
[Approaching car]
[Door banging]
-嗨
GINGER: Hi.
SAM: Hi.
-你没回呼叫器
-我丢了
SAM: You didn't answer your beeper.
GINGER: I threw it away.
你丢了
You threw it away?
我试着带着
我知道你希望我带着…
I tried to do it.
I know that you want me to, but....
可是我开在高速公路上时
它也在响
I'm driving down the freeway
and the fucking thing beeps.
在餐馆也是，很丢脸
GINGER: I'm in a restaurant,
it's embarrassing.
我不要再带了，艾美呢？
I don't want to do it anymore. Where's Amy?
-她睡了
-我买了你要的烟
SAM: I put her to bed.
GINGER: I got your cigarettes.
奥斯卡要你跟他连络
GINGER: Oscar wants you to call him.
-你跟谁吃的午餐？
-珍妮佛
SAM: So who'd you go to lunch with?
GINGER: Jennifer.
-去哪儿吃？
-欧华赌场
SAM: Where'd you go?
GINGER: To the Riviera.
吃什么？
What'd you have?
-我叫沙拉
-珍妮佛呢？
GINGER: I had a salad.
SAM: What did Jennifer have?
她也一样
She had the same.
好
Okay.
我要你打给珍妮佛…
I want you to call Jennifer...
我要你叫她告诉你
你午餐吃了什么
and I want you to tell her
to tell you what you had for lunch.
我从另一线听
I'm gonna listen in on the other line.
-你干嘛这样？
-你知道为什么
-Why do you want to do that?
-You know why I want to do it.
-照做就是了
-好啦
-Just do it.
-Fine.
我只是需要拿个碗装这个
I just need to get the bowl for my thing.
忙线中
The line's busy.
没人在
There's nobody there.
-喂
-喂，珍妮佛，是山姆
JENNIFER: Hello?
SAM: Hello, Jennifer. It's Sam.
好啦，我没跟珍妮佛吃饭
All right. I didn't have lunch with Jennifer.
那你跟谁？
Who were you with?
一个人
I was with somebody.
我知道你有伴
是谁？
I know you were with somebody.
Who was it?
我只希望不是我想的那个人
I just hope it's not someone
who I think it might be.
我只希望不是他
I just hope it's not that.
我知道她在外面乱来
SAM: I knew she fucked around.
她做她做的
我也做我要做的…
Yeah, she did what she did,
and I did what I had to do, but...
可是，天啊
尼奇是她所能做出最糟糕的事
Jesus, Nicky was the worst thing
she could have done.
若他不愿停呢？
What if he won't stop?
我们两个可能都会没命
SAM: It could get us both killed.
我可以让他停
I can back him off.
她在必要时可以很有说服力
SAM: She was very convincing
when she wanted to be.
她是这样让他停的
And this is how she backed him off.
[Both panting]
嗨，金吉儿
Hey, Ginger.
别忘了，要是他追问你
Don't forget, if you're challenged...
不管他问你什么，你都不要承认
if he asks anything, deny everything.
懂不懂？
我不想他跟老家那头抱怨
You understand? I don't want him
bringing beefs back home.
这样麻烦就大了
That could really cause a serious problem.
得小心点
他也不是蠢蛋，懂吗？
Got to be careful.
He's not dumb, you know?
你懂我的意思吧？
You hear what I'm saying, right?
我知道，你不用告诉我
I know. You don't have to tell me that.
你当我白痴吗？
Do you think I'm stupid?
我当你白痴？不
Do I think you're stupid? No.
我当你是美女，但我得走了
I think you're beautiful. But I gotta go.
这时候，尼奇在外的事已经乱到…
SAM: By this time, Nicky had things
so fucked up on the streets...
每次玛雷诺回老家时
皮箱都越来越小
that every time Marino went back home,
the packages got smaller and smaller.
后来甚至严重到
他每走入一个地方…
It got to the point,
when he walked into the place...
他都不确定会被亲还是被杀
he didn't know whether he was
going to be kissed or killed.
法兰克，我有事问你
REMO: Frankie, I want to ask you something.
私人的事
It's private.
我要你说实话
But I want you to tell me the truth.
当然，利蒙
Of course, Remo.
我要你说真话
I want you to tell me the truth, mind you.
我对你一直都很诚实，利蒙
I always tell you the truth, Remo.
法兰克，小矮个…
Frankie, the little guy...
他不是在搞犹太人的老婆吧？
he wouldn't be fucking
the Jew's wife, would he?
因为若他有，就是个问题
Because if he is, it's a problem.
我能说什么？
FRANK: What could I say?
我知道若我答错了…
I knew if I gave the wrong answer...
尼奇、金吉儿与艾斯全部
都可能被干掉
Nicky, Ginger, Ace, all of them
could have wound up getting killed.
因为这些老家伙们有个禁忌
Because there's one thing
about these old-timers.
就是他们不能忍受搞别人老婆
They don't like any fucking around
with the other guys' wives.
那很难看
It's bad for business.
所以我撒谎
虽然我知道对盖吉撒谎…
So I lied, even though I knew
that by lying to Gaggi...
可能会害我也被干掉
I could wind up getting killed, too.
-不，我没见到这种事
-你确定？
-No, I ain't seen anything like that.
-Are you sure?
我很确定
I'm positive.
利蒙，那边现在可是一团糟
Remo, things are very
fucked up down there.
我知道，所以我才问你
I know. That's why I'm asking.
我最担心的是尼奇
You see, my main concern is Nicky.
我想知道他最近如何
过得好不好
I want to know if he's
doing all right, if he's okay.
-他很好
-我要你看好尼奇
-He's good, he's fine.
-I'm asking you to keep an eye on Nicky.
-为了我
-没问题
-Do it for me.
-No problem.
你知道，我不想得罪我们的朋友
You see, I wouldn't want to be jeopardizing
anything for our friends.
你懂吗？
You understand?
-我懂了
-好
-I understand.
-Okay.
法兰克，你是个好孩子
Frankie, you're a good boy.
谢了，利蒙
Thanks, Remo.
这时，尼奇与他那帮人
已经跌到谷底了
SAM: By now, Nicky and his crew
had already hit rock bottom.
赌城真的改变了他
Vegas really got to him.
酒精、可卡因、女人
The booze, the coke, the broads.
我是说，他开始大意
I mean, he got sloppy.
他再也不是以前那个尼奇了
He just wasn't the same Nicky anymore.
-你喝太多了
-去你的
FRANK: You must've drank too much.
NICKY: Fuck yourself.
有晚他对个家伙开了三枪…
SAM: One night, he had to belt a guy
three times...
才将他打死
before the guy finally went down.
要是以前，尼奇只要一枪就够了
In the old days,
Nicky would've decked him with one shot.
加上这些成份…
You add this into the mix....
可能赌城改变了我们全部
Maybe Vegas got to all of us.
他那帮人随着他一起堕落
His crew followed him right over the edge.
他们每天一半的时间
都在吸毒中渡过
They were all tuned up half the time
on coke.
他们开始做些蠢事
尤其是布鲁
They started doing stupid things.
The worst was Blue.
-你们要干嘛？
-警察！别下车！
-What do you guys want?
-Police! Stay in the car!
他从不知道何时该闭嘴
SAM: He never knew when
to keep his mouth shut.
-放下枪！
-去你的！
COP: Drop the gun!
BLUE: Fuck you!
条子朝布鲁开枪…
SAM: The cops shot Blue...
因为他们以为
他手上拿的潜艇堡是手枪
because they thought
his hero sandwich was a gun.
他们也许是对的
但谁知道？
They could have been right,
but who knows?
天啊，什么枪？
他手上拿的是潜艇堡
COP: Jesus Christ! What gun?
He's got a fucking hero sandwich here.
不然能怎样？这儿这么黑
COP 2: What do you want? It's pitch black.
-是锡箔纸，看来像枪！
-你这智障！
COP 2: It's tinfoil. It looked like a gun!
COP: You moron!
-我得办两个月的公文！
-该怎么办？
COP: I'll be doing paperwork for two months!
COP 2: What'll we do?
-抱歉！
-白痴！
COP 2: Sorry!
COP: You jerk-off!
更糟的是，为了报仇
尼奇那帮人有天晚上…
SAM: To make matters worse...
吸毒后跑去扫射警察的家
to get even,
Nicky's crew got stoned one night...
and started shooting up the cops' houses.
后来严重到连在掏金热潮里
都不方便讲话…
It got to the point where they couldn't
talk in the Gold Rush anymore...
因为联邦调查局在窃听
because the Feds put a wire in the wall.
他们连在外面讲话时
都得捂住嘴
Even when they talked outside,
they had to cover their mouths...
因为联邦调查局请来了
读唇语的专家
because the Feds brought in lip readers.
尼奇是从一个欠他钱的
银行职员那听说的
Nicky found out about it from a teller
who owed him money.
他又问我你跟犹太人老婆的事
FRANK: He asked me again
about you and the Jew's wife.
走、走、走
你说什么？
NICKY: Walk, walk, walk. What'd you say?
他又问我你跟犹太人老婆的事
FRANK: He asked me again
about you and the Jew's wife.
你怎么说？
NICKY: What'd you tell him?
我说我不知道
FRANK: I told him I didn't know nothing.
杰葛与东尼国理拉说
你要是有做什么就完了
FRANK: Jiggs and Tony Gorilla said
if you did anything, you're fucked up.
你想他是不是背着我回老家
跟他们抱怨？
NICKY: You think he's going home
making a beef behind my back?
不，若有的话
你应该早听到风声
FRANK: No, you would have
heard something.
-有什么阻止他这么做？
-是啊
NICKY: What's to stop him?
FRANK: I know.
我不相信他了
但老大们不会答应我干掉他的
NICKY: I don't trust him anymore,
but they'd never okay anything.
但他们一直在问
FRANK: But they keep asking about it.
当然会问罗
他们靠他赚钱
NICKY: Sure they're asking.
They earn with the prick.
我有种感觉
他好像想引发战争
NICKY: I got a funny feeling he's gonna start
a war or something.
我还不确定
但你知道我要你干嘛吗？
NICKY: I'm not sure yet.
But you know what I want you to do?
这是谁？
NICKY: Who's this guy?
谁都不是
FRANK: That ain't nobody.
你知道我要你干嘛吗？
NICKY: You know what I want you to do?
找个人在沙漠挖个洞
要他告诉你在哪儿
NICKY: Get some guys to dig a hole
in the desert and show you where it's at.
-安基罗与本斯特
-我还不确定
FRANK: Angelo and Buster.
NICKY: I'm not sure yet.
-他们肯干的
-我准备好时会跟你说…
FRANK: They'll do it.
NICKY: When I'm ready, I'll say the words:
“去找犹太人”
然后你就让他消失，懂不懂？
"Go see the Jew." And you make
it disappear. Know what I mean?
让我知道，但你得准备好
FRANK: Let me know.
But you gotta be ready.
你懂我的意思吗？
FRANK: You know what I'm talking about?
我有叫你行动吗？
NICKY: Did I say to do anything yet?
我说了我不确定，我会让你知道
我得再想想
NICKY: I said I'm not sure. I'll let you know.
I want to think about it.
那些混蛋呢？
在旅馆里吗？
NICKY: Where are these pricks at?
They're in the motel?
那里或是银行
我也不知道，到处都是
FRANK: There or in the fucking bank.
I don't know. All over the joint.
[Loud dance music]
[Phone ringing]
[Phone continues ringing]
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
有我的电话就转给雪伯提先生
Any calls for me, give them to Mr. Sherbert.
-好的，罗斯坦先生
-我回家一会儿
-Sure, Mr. Rothstein.
-I'm going home for a few seconds.
他要回家了
He's on his way home.
好的
Okay.
喂？金吉儿？
Hello? Ginger?
-爸爸，救命！
-艾美！
AMY: Help, Daddy!
SAM: Amy!
-艾美，开门！
-我不能，我被绑起来了！
SAM: Amy, open the door!
AMY: I can't! I'm tied!
[Amy screams]
-爸爸！
-发生什么事！
AMY: Dad!
SAM: What happened?
-是谁？
-是妈妈
SAM: Who did this to you?
AMY: Mommy.
我去拿刀把绳子切断
I'm gonna get a knife and cut you loose.
-不要走！
-没关系，我马上回来
AMY: No, please!
SAM: Okay, I'm gonna be right back.
-什么时候的事，甜心？
-我不知道
SAM: When did this happen, honey?
AMY: I don't know.
你妈什么时候做的？
她什么时候走的？
What time did your mother do this?
When did she leave?
我不知道
AMY: I don't know.
[Amy moans]
[Phone ringing]
-喂？
-山姆
SAM: Hello?
NICKY: Sammy.
-你是谁？
-是我
SAM: Yeah. Who's this?
NICKY: Me.
-你还好吗？
-我不好
NICKY: You okay?
SAM: No, I'm not okay.
-你怎么知道我在？
-我只想跟你谈谈
-How'd you know I was here?
-I just wanted to talk to you.
金吉儿不见了
她将艾美绑在房间并上锁
Ginger's missing. She tied Amy up
and locked her in her room.
我不知道她在哪儿
I don't know where she is.
听着，金吉儿在比萨斜塔
跟我一起
Well, listen, Ginger's here
at the Leaning Tower with me.
她在你那儿？
She's there with you?
-是，在这儿
-我马上来
NICKY: Yeah, she's here.
SAM: I'll be right over.
好的
All right.
-过来了
-非常好
-Coming over.
-Great.
[Brakes squealing]
别闹事，好吗？
Don't make a scene, all right?
我要跟那爱尔兰婊子说话
I want to talk to that Irish bitch.
她想要挽救你们的婚姻
She's trying to save your marriage.
尼奇，我要见那婊子
Nicky, I want to talk to that fucking bitch.
客气点，冷静
Be fucking nice. Calm.
客气点，别搞砸了
Be nice. Don't fuck up in here.
[Sentimental jazz music]
-嗨，山姆
-你疯了吗？
GINGER: Hi.
SAM: Are you out of your mind?
你把我们的孩子绑起来还锁门？
你疯了吗？
You tie up our kid and lock the door?
Are you out of your mind?
那是我们的孩子
你他妈的疯了吗？
That's our child. Are you out of your mind?
只是一下下而已
褓姆刚好不在
It was just for a little while.
The baby-sitter wasn't there.
我真该送你去疯人院
你下次再试试看…
I ought to have you committed.
You do that again and I'll--
我只是出去一会儿
I was just gonna be out for a little while.
-她睡了，我一会就要回去的…
-听着
She was asleep. I was gonna be back...
-在她醒来前
-听着，你这贱货…
SAM: Listen.
让我告诉你
-...before she even woke up.
-Listen, you fucking cunt...
听我说，听清楚
let me tell you something.
你别想再动她一根汗毛…
Listen to me. Listen carefully.
You ever touch her again
or do anything like that again...
我会杀了你，就这么简单
I'll fucking kill you, pure and simple.
你听到没？就这么简单
SAM: You hear me? Pure and simple.
-你为何不让我走？
-我会杀了你
GINGER: Why don't you let me go?
SAM: I'll kill you.
-你这个婊子
-你要我签什么都行
SAM: You fucking whore.
I'll sign anything you want me to sign.
我只要珠宝的钥匙
还有让我走
I just want the key to my jewelry,
and you to let me go.
-你想要珠宝？
-放我走
SAM: Want your jewelry?
GINGER: Let me go.
然后让你丢我的脸，你这只猪？
And let you disgrace me, you pig?
你给我起来当个母亲
SAM: Get up and be a mother.
立刻上车回家
Get in the car and go home right now.
起来…
Get up and get in....
-起来
-我要是你就不会这样
-Get up.
-I wouldn't do that if I were you.
-我要是你就…
-起来！
-I wouldn't do that--
-Get up!
你在威胁我吗？
Are you threatening me?
我现在就可宰了你
起来回家
I'll fucking kill you in this place.
Get up and go home.
我要走了！
I'm going!
你现在要他批准才能回家？
Now you need approval
from him to go home?
那又怎样？你从停车场进来前
又是谁在帮你吹喇叭？
So what? Who blew you in the parking lot
before you came in?
你让我作呕
You make me sick, you fuck.
-一日为娼，终生为娼
-去你的！
-Once a hooker, always a hooker.
-Oh, fuck you!
去你的，山姆罗斯坦！
Fuck you, Sam Rothstein!
Fuck you!
[Upbeat pop music]
找比利雪伯提
Billy Sherbert, please. Put him on.
-谁啊？
-听好，我待会再解释
BILLY: Who's this?
SAM: Listen, I'll explain later.
你家里有枪吗？
马上带过来
You got a gun at home?
Bring it over right away.
-冷静点，我带
-好
-Take it easy. I'll do it.
-Okay.
就留着吧！
Leave it where it is!
他在哪儿？我要杀了那犹太王八蛋！
Where is he? I want that Jew bastard killed!
把她的车藏到后面去
Hide her car in the back.
不需要藏我的车！
他早就知道了！
GINGER: There's no reason to hide my car!
He already knows!
他要是回去告状怎么办？
Supposing he goes back home
and makes a fucking beef?
-我得知道你到底跟他说了什么
-我？我说…
-I gotta know exactly what you said. Tell me.
-Me? Nothing. I said....
我说没有，不管他说什么
我都说没有
I said, no. Everything he said,
I just kept saying no.
我早跟你说这很危险
I told you this was fucking dangerous.
我说：   “金吉儿，状况很危险
你一定要小心”
I said, "Ginger, this is
a dangerous situation. Be very careful."
若真这么危险，你为何不杀了他？
If it's so fucking dangerous,
why don't you kill him?
我不会杀他，闭上你的嘴
I'm not gonna kill him. Shut the fuck up.
-杀了他，做个了断！
-别自做聪明！
-Have him killed, and get it over with!
-Don't be such a fucking smart-ass!
我跟他35年的交情
我会为了你干他？
I know the guy 35 years,
I'm gonna whack him for you?
王八蛋
NICKY: Motherfucker.
-我就知道
-那我的钱呢？
-I knew it.
-What about my money?
我现在怎么帮你拿钱？
How the fuck am I gonna
get your money now?
你还以为他会给你钱吗？
你疯了吗？
You think he'll give you money?
Are you out of your mind?
-看看你怎么对他的
-什么？
-Look what you did to this guy.
-What?
你只要闭上你的嘴
If you'd just kept your fucking mouth shut.
现在有个屁用！
我真不该淌混水的…
What's the use!
I should have never got involved--
[Ginger screaming hysterically]
喂！你这混蛋！
Hey! You motherfucker, you!
-你混蛋！
-给我滚！
GINGER: You fucker!
NICKY: Get the fuck out!
给我滚出去！
[Ginger crying]
NICKY: Get the fuck out!
-不！
-下去，冷静点！
GINGER: No!
NICKY: Get down there! Take it easy!
我根本不该管这疯子的！
NICKY: I shouldn't have gotten involved
with this nut!
你会杀了她，冷静点
FRANK: You'll kill her. Take it easy.
把她弄出去
NICKY: Get her out of here.
走吧
FRANK: Let's go.
我不需要你！
我自己会拿到我的钱！
I don't need you!
I'll get my own fucking money!
我要去找联邦调查局！
我不怕你了！
I'm going to the FBI!
I'm not scared anymore!
-好，自己小心
-这是你最后一次玩我！
NICKY: All right. Be careful.
GINGER: You've fucked with me
for the last time!
好，好
Okay. Yeah.
小心啊
NICKY: Careful.
走吧，进去
Come on. Get inside.
你瞧瞧，他妈的
Look at this. Motherfucker.
[Frank sighs]
我错了，法兰克
我这次真的搞砸了
I fucked up, Frankie.
I fucked up good this time.
我真不该跟那荡妇搞的
I should never have started
with this fucking broad.
冷静点，你能怎样呢？
Take it easy. What could you do?
是她自己送上门的，不是吗？
FRANK: I mean, she threw herself
at you, right?
我现在身处困境了
你知道吗？
I'm in a bad fucking spot here.
You know that?
里外不是人
A bad fucking spot.
[Rhythmic pop music]
我将孩子给邻居托管
SAM: I left the kid with neighbors.
将近一百万的现金与珠宝…
I had $1 million in cash and jewels...
我交给雪伯提锁在赌场
that I gave to Sherbert
to lock up in the hotel.
把这放进旅馆的保险柜
然后马上回来
Put this in the hotel safe
and I want you to come back.
她一个人，拿着枪到艾美房间去…
She's alone. Take the gun
and go into Amy's....
-在那儿等我
-下楼见我！
SAM: Just wait there for me.
GINGER: Get down here and talk to me!
你不能不理我，混蛋！
You can't fucking ignore me,
you motherfucker!
我说真的！
马上给我下来！
GINGER: I mean it! Come down here
right now!
下来见我，妈的！
GINGER: Get down here and talk to me,
God damn it!
去你的！你给我下来！
GINGER: Fuck you! Goddamn you,
come out here!
我要将车开进客厅！
GINGER: I'm going to drive this fucking car
through the living room!
你这个懦夫！混蛋！
GINGER: You fucking coward!
You motherfucker!
-出来见我
-你够了没？
GINGER: Come out here and talk to me.
SAM: Will you stop it?
-你喝醉又w药
-我没有！
SAM: You're drunk. You're on drugs.
GINGER: I am not!
-你再不停就要后悔了
-别威胁我！
-You'll be sorry if you don't stop.
-Don't you threaten me!
你无法再威胁我了！
GINGER: You're not threatening me anymore!
王八蛋！我受够你了！
You fuck! I'm sick of you!
我与尼克山多罗上床！
他是我的新靠山！
I am fucking Nicky Santoro!
He's my new sponsor!
怎么样，王八蛋！
How about that, you fuckhead!
你在看什么？滚开！
What are you looking at? Fuck off!
快进去！
关你们屁事！
Go back inside!
This is none of your business!
我再也不要每天看你脸色了！
GINGER: I don't have to take
your shit anymore!
我要去找联邦调查局！
我要去找警察！
I'm going to the FBI! I'll go to the police!
-我不会再保护你了！
-罗斯坦夫人…
-I am not protecting you anymore!
-Mrs. Rothstein--
他不让我进去！
GINGER: He won't let me inside!
罗斯坦先生，我们接到很多
关于噪音的抱怨
Mr. Rothstein, we've been getting
some complaints about the noise.
我试着回我家，但他不让我进门
I'm trying to get in my house.
He won't let me in.
我不让她进去，抱歉，蓝帝
I won't let her in. I'm sorry, Randy.
-她那样子，我不能让她进门
-不让我？
I won't, the way she's behaving.
GINGER: Won't let me in?
谁知道你进去会干嘛
SAM: Who knows what you'll do there.
我已经两天没换衣服了！
I've been in the same clothes for two days!
-我要收拾东西！什么大不了的！
-好
-I want to get my things! Big deal!
-Okay.
让她进去拿点东西，她就会走了
Let her in to get a few things.
That way she'll leave.
-这房子一半是她的
-我不敢
COP: This is half her house.
SAM: I'm afraid.
-你才不怕！
-她会乱砸东西
GINGER: You aren't afraid!
SAM: She'll destroy stuff.
-让我进去！
-喂！
-Let me in the house!
-Hey!
-混蛋！
-请等一下！
-Fucker!
-Hold on! Please!
你这样对我，你是该害怕！
GINGER: You should be afraid,
the way you treat me!
让大家都好过点
It'll make it easier on everybody.
若让她进去拿东西
我们大家就不打扰你了
COP: If we let her get her things,
we'll be out of your hair.
她要冷静下来，我就让她进来
If she calms down, I'll let her in.
-我很冷静！
-若她冷静下来…
GINGER: I am calm!
SAM: If she calms down...
我让她进来五分钟…
I will let her in for five minutes...
如果你们愿意在她不愿走时
护送她出去
if you gentlemen will escort her out
if she won't leave.
-可以进去了吗？
-这不是问题
-Can I go in?
-That's not a problem.
-杰夫，你跟她去？
-好，好，去你的！
-Jeff, would you go in with her?
-Yes. Fine! Fuck you!
你无法相信他多坏
他把我的证件都锁起来
GINGER: You wouldn't believe how mean
he is. He's locked up my papers.
我要拿它们
别让他上来这儿…
I have to get them.
Don't let him come up here...
因为它们在这书桌里
because I know they're in here
in the desk. Fuck.
注意点，他随时都会上楼
GINGER: Pay attention.
He could come up here at anytime.
你有看着他吗？
Are you watching for him?
找到了
GINGER: Got them.
我不要她在里头超过五分钟
I don't want her in there
more than a few more minutes.
很快就好了
我们也有别的事要做
It'll just be a couple minutes.
We got other things to do, too.
我们会叫她快点的
He'll hurry her up.
-其他都还好吧？
-很好
-How's everything else?
-Fine.
-你那边呢？
-不错啊，我老婆又怀孕了
-How's your family?
-Not bad. In fact, my wife's pregnant again.
-恭喜你
-谢了
-Congratulations.
-Thanks.
我们很开心
We're happy about that.
我得再拿一样东西
然后我们就可以走了
I just have to get this one more thing,
then we can go.
妈的！
GINGER: Shit! Fuck!
GINGER: Shit! God!
气死我了！别管它！
GINGER: That pisses me off! Don't worry.
若能…
It would be great...
跟我一起出去最好…
if you could follow me out of here...
因为他在威胁我！
because he's been threatening me!
保重，谢谢
Take care. Thank you.
我真不敢相信
[Crying] I can't believe this.
我只是需要领一些现金
你可以陪我来吗？
GINGER: I just need to pick up a little cash.
Could you come with me?
-你得阻止她
-抱歉，山姆
SAM: You've got to stop her.
CHARLIE: I'm sorry, Sam.
-我无能为力
-她是个毒虫，根本就疯了！
CHARLIE: What can I do?
SAM: She's a junkie. She's out of her mind!
她有钥匙，而且你们两人名字
都在户头上
She has the keys.
It's still in both your names.
我无能为力，我想要帮忙…
There's nothing I can do. I'd like to help...
-但我不能
-严格说，她不能拿
-but I can't.
-Legally, she can't take it.
-她不能，一半是我的
-听我说
SAM: She can't. Half of it is mine.
CHARLIE: Listen to me.
-我爱莫能助
-我马上到
CHARLIE: There's nothing I can do.
SAM: I'm coming down.
妈的！靠！
Shit! God damn it!
我需要个袋子
你可以帮我要个袋子吗？
I'll need a bag. Could you
ask the guy for the big bag?
-拿个袋吧
-拿去
COP: Go get a bag, man.
GINGER: Here.
-小姐，我不能拿
-你可以，你对我好好
-Lady, I can't take it.
-You can. You've been so nice to me.
好，帮我打开，好吗？
这样我就可以…
GINGER: Yes, just hold the top open.
All right? And I can....
天啊，是他！
你们得阻止他
Oh, God! It's him. You have to stop him.
因为他说他会杀了我
'Cause he said he was gonna kill me.
罗斯坦先生，等一下
COP: Mr. Rothstein, wait a minute.
请等一下
COP: Hold on a second.
-她开走了
-我们不能做什么
SAM: She's driving away.
COP: There's nothing we can do.
-我们不能做什么
-你瞧瞧
-There's nothing we can do.
-Look, look.
你们不能抓她超速吗？
看看她开多快
You can't stop her for speeding?
Look what she's doing.
-我们不能做什么，她有钥匙
-她的名字在户头上
COP: Nothing we can do. She had the key.
COP 2: She's on the account.
-我们在加油站拦她
-好的，就这么办
-Let's pull her over at that Citgo Station.
-Okay. Let's do it.
[Siren wailing]
-我们必须逮捕你
-为了什么？
-We're placing you under arrest.
-For what?
-为了协助犯罪…
-为了什么？
-For aiding and abetting--
-For what?
-为了协助犯罪…
-我只是要离开
-For aiding and abetting--
-I'm just trying to leave.
在这么多威胁之后…
SAM: After all the threats and bullshit...
金吉儿什么都没告诉他们
it turned out
Ginger didn't tell them anything.
但那时，他们也不需要她了
But, by then,
the Feds didn't need her anyway.
-他们已有足够的证据
-但我什么都没做
They had all the pieces they needed.
But I didn't do anything.
-大家就像牌九一样跟着倒
-联邦调查局！我们有拘捕令！
SAM: Everyone began to tumble,
like dominoes.
FBI! We have a warrant!
不管是窃听器上派斯康的抱怨…
SAM: Between Piscano complaining
on the wire...
还是尼奇、我与我的执照…
between Nicky, Ginger, me and my license...
天堂就这样被我们搞砸了
paradise. We managed to really fuck it up.
-妈
-门口他妈的有人
NICKY JR.: Mom.
JENNIFER: Someone's at the door now.
联邦调查局，我们有搜查令
FBI. We have a federal search warrant.
我马上知道苗头不对
所以我跑路了
NICKY: I got wind of the pinches
coming down, so I took off.
谁要待在那儿找麻烦啊？
Who needs to hang around for that bullshit?
-我是马克凯斯伯，FBI
-是吗？
-I'm Mark Casper, FBI.
-Yeah?
我可以打个电话吗？
Can I make a fucking phone call?
可以，但你不用这样对我们讲话
Yes, but you don't have to talk to us
like that.
大家都出去
往警铃的方向走
FBI AGENT: Everybody, out of the room.
Over to the alarm.
-其他人似乎都被抓了
-这地方被查封了！
NICKY: They got almost everybody else.
FBI AGENT: This area is seized!
-去拿总户头单
-我要查封所有的文件
-Get the master account list.
-I want all those papers seized.
将每个箱子都放到桌上
FBI AGENT: Put every box on the table.
[Rhythmic jazz music]
好，在这儿，所有的数字
Yes. Here we are. Little craps figures.
葛林？别提了
SAM: Green? Don't even ask.
-你的三万元
-不，所以不成立
-...$30,000 of yours.
-No. That's why it wasn't valid.
我是被敲诈的
你们想知道什么就问我
I was being extorted.
I'll tell you what you want to know.
-我不需要隐藏
-最经典的是
PHILIP: I've got nothing to hide.
NICKY: Now for the best.
我不敢相信派斯康的花费记录
竟然成了关键
I couldn't believe this shit.
Piscano's expense reports took the cake.
-这太好了
-他干脆就把蓝图给他们算了
Oh, this is good.
NICKY: He might as well give them
a blueprint.
所有人的名字、地址、日期
一切都在上面
Everybody's names, addresses,
dates, everything.
真是多谢你了，派斯康先生
你真是体帖
Thank you so much, Mr. Piscano.
How considerate of you.
-那是我妈的账目
-你被逮捕了
-Those are my mother's books.
-You're under arrest.
-真是个蠢才
-你在干嘛？
NICKY: What a fucking balloon head.
ARTIE: What are you doing?
-冷静点
-等一下！
AGENT: Take it easy.
WIFE: Wait!
-等一下，他有病！
-走开
WIFE: Wait! He's sick!
COP: Move back.
-是心脏，还呼吸吗？
-快人工呼吸！
WIFE: It's his heart! Is he breathing?
COP 2: CPR now!
艾提被搞到心脏病发…
SAM: Artie got so upset
he had a heart attack...
当他老婆的面就挂了
and dropped dead right in front of his wife.
-冷静点！
-我无法冷静！
-Calm down!
-No, I won't calm down!
-他是我丈夫，艾提！
-我们也不能…
-He's my husband! Artie!
-We can't help him if--
最后…
SAM: At the end of the day...
他们终于拿照片来给我看
they finally came to see me
with the pictures.
为什么要保护一个背叛你的朋友？
FBI AGENT: Why protect a friend
who betrayed you?
但我并不想看它们…
SAM: But I didn't want to look at them...
或是拿照片来的人
or the guys who brought them.
大人，你可看见，我的客户们
都年事已大并生病
COUNSELOR: Your Honor, as you can see,
my clients are elderly and infirm.
任何的刑责都将会
严重威胁到他们的健康
COUNSELOR: Any incarceration could pose
a serious health risk.
当老大们被逮时
有些简直老到…
NICKY: When they were arrested,
some were so old...
罪状认否程序时都需要医师
they needed doctors at their arraignment.
预审时建议将保释金额
维持现额
COUNSELOR: Pre-trial services
recommends that bail remain as set.
-现在休庭
-当情况看来他们似乎…
JUDGE: Take recess.
NICKY: When it looked like they'd get...
得为了抽头而关上25年时…
25 years to life in prison
just for skimming a casino...
不管有病没病
总有人要倒霉
sick or no fucking sick, you knew
people were going to get clipped.
所以在罪状认否程序那天
他们在法庭后头开会
So the day of the arraignment, they had
this meeting in the back of the courthouse.
当类似的事发生时
你已知道事情会怎样
When something like this happens,
you know how things are gonna work out.
最好是不要有目击者
那安迪呢？
It's always better with no witnesses.
So what about Andy?
他不会说的，史东是好家伙
He won't talk. Stone is a good kid.
跟他老爸一样带种
Stand-up guy just like his old man.
我是这么想的
That's the way I see it.
我同意，他很强悍
I agree. He's solid. He's a fucking Marine.
他没问题，一直都是
你说呢？
He's okay. He always was.
What do you think?
为什么要冒险呢？
Look, why take a chance?
我是这么想的啦
At least that's the way I feel about it.
打给艾提，告诉他不管怎样…
ANDY: Call Artie. Tell him I don't care what...
他星期四都得来我办公室
he's gotta be in my office
Thursday morning.
决定了
It's done.
非常重要
我一定得跟他谈谈
It's terribly important. I gotta
have a conversation with him.
[Gunshots muffled by silencer]
不管他们多喜欢他
他还不是家族一员
NICKY: As much as they liked him,
he wasn't one of us.
他不是意大利人
对他们来说，他随时可能供出来
He wasn't Italian. As far as they knew,
he could have talked.
要不然他可能还活着
Otherwise, he'd still be alive.
哥斯达黎加
第一个翘头的就是约翰南斯
The first one to skip was John Nance.
他在哥斯达黎加
找了个又好又隐密的地方
He found a nice,
warm, secluded place in Costa Rica.
他以为没人找得到他
He thought nobody would find him there.
[Gunshots muffled by silencer]
[Breaking glass]
但他孩子随后因犯毒
被联邦调查局逮了
NICKY: But then his kid got nabbed
by the Feds for drugs.
老大们当然怕他会出现…
So naturally, the bosses were afraid
he'd come out of hiding...
为了救孩子而把大家供出来
just to save his kid and give them all up.
所以…
So....
你想去哪里？
Where you going, jag-off?
但大家都得跟着
NICKY: But, anyway, they all had to follow.
大家都完了
Everybody went down.
去你的
Fuck you.
不知不觉…
NICKY: Before you knew it...
任何知道一点小事的人
都被干掉了
anybody who knew anything
wound up getting whacked.
不！不！
GINGER: Oh, no! No!
金吉儿走后
她对任何人都没什么用
SAM: After Ginger took off,
she wasn't much help to anybody.
她在洛杉矶结识了一些
皮条客、败类、毒虫与飞车党
She found some pimps, lowlifes,
druggies, and bikers in L.A.
几个月内，他们就把
所有的钱跟珠宝花光了
In a few months, they went through
all the money and jewels.
[Intense rock music]
当他们找到遗体时…
After they found her body...
我私下请了个医生验尸
I had a private doctor do another autopsy.
他说他们给她打了过量的毒品
He said they gave her a hot dose.
最终，她身上只剩下
价值三千六百元的全新硬币
In the end, all she had left was $3, 600
in mint condition coins.
[Intense rock music continues]
不管条子与文件
对我的汽车炸弹有什么评论…
No matter what the Feds or the papers
said about my car bombing...
一看就知道是新手干的
it was amateur night, you could tell.
不管是谁，他们将炸弹装在
副驾驶座下面
Whoever it was, they put the dynamite
under the passenger side.
他们不知道的是
除了车厂外没人知道的是…
But what they didn't know,
what nobody outside the factory knew...
那台车的驾驶座下
多加了一块铁板
was that, that model car was made with
a metal plate under the driver's seat.
全靠了它救我一命
It's the only thing that saved my life.
那炸弹从没被批准
但我想我知道是谁干的
The bombing was never authorized,
but I suspect I know who lit the fuse.
老大们也知道吧
So did the powers that be.
-你好吗？
NICKY: How are you?
BOSS: How you doing?
好几个月后一切才平息
NICKY: It took months for everything
to calm down.
但我的人终于保释出来了
But finally, my guys got out on bail.
老大们要我将我小弟
多明尼送回赌城
The bosses wanted me to send
my brother Dominick out to Vegas.
永远都是为了钱
Always the fucking dollars.
我是说，我连赌城都不能踏入
I mean, it was still too hot for me to even go
near Vegas.
所以我在个鸟不生蛋的地方
安排大家碰面
So I set up a meeting
with the guys way out in the sticks.
我不想害我小弟
对的就是对的
I didn't want my brother to get
fucked around. What's right is right.
他们才不在乎…
They don't give a fuck about--
去你妈的…
THUG: Holy fucking....
搞什么…
NICKY: What the fuck....
来啊，王八蛋！
Come on, motherfucker!
不是很猛吗？你跟你哥！
Tough guys! You and your fucking brother!
你们两个混蛋！够了！
You fucking scumbags! No more!
-法兰克！
-够了！你看着！
-Frankie!
-No more! You see? Watch!
-法兰克！你这王八蛋！
-去你的！
NICKY: Frankie! You piece of shit!
FRANK: Fuck you!
王八羔子！狗杂种！
NICKY: Fucking punk! Piece of shit!
不！
把这混蛋拖走！
No!
Take this motherfucker out!
[Dominick groaning]
别搞他了，他还活着
他还在呼吸
别搞他了，法兰克
He's still breathing.
Leave him alone. Frankie.
好了，脱他衣服
FRANK: All right. Strip him.
没种，你真他妈的没种
NICKY: No balls. You got no fucking balls.
多明尼！
Oh, Dominick!
多明尼
NICKY: Dominick.
[Nicky weeping]
来吧
FRANK: Come on.
-埋了他们？
-埋
THUG: Bury them?
FRANK: Bury them.
[Nicky moaning]
话放出去了
老大们受够了尼奇
受够了
SAM: The word was out.
他们还能忍受多久呢？
所以拿他们兄弟俩杀鸡儆猴
The bosses had enough of Nicky.
They had enough.
How much were they gonna take? So they
made an example of him and his brother.
他们俩被活埋
They buried them while they were
still breathing.
你还好吗？小心！
MAN: You all right? Watch out!
-先生，你没事吧？
-没事
MAN: Mister, you all right?
SAM: Yeah.
他们有别的事给我做
SAM: They had other ideas for me.
[Sirens wailing]
我们这儿需要帮忙！
MEDIC: We need some help over here!
你真是幸运
MEDIC 2: You sure are lucky, mister.
[Dramatic operatic music]
这城市再也不一样了
SAM: The town will never be the same.
在坦吉乐之后，大集团全权掌管
After the Tangiers,
the big corporations took it all over.
今日的赌城像是迪斯尼乐园
Today it looks like Disneyland.
孩子们玩着海盗游戏时…
While the kids play cardboard pirates...
爸爸与妈妈将房贷与大学学费…
Mommy and Daddy drop the house
payments and junior's college money...
浪费在吃角子老虎机
on the poker slots.
想当年，庄家知道你的名字
喝什么酒，玩什么牌
In the old days, dealers knew your name,
what you drank, what you played.
今天就像是在机场登记一般
Today, it's like checking into an airport.
你要是叫客房送餐
星期四给你送到就了不起了
If you order room service,
you're lucky if you get it by Thursday.
都没了，一个人拎着
装着四百万的皮箱…
Today it's all gone. A whale shows up
with $4 million in a suitcase...
就有个25岁的旅游系大学毕业生
想要他的身份字号
and some 25-year-old hotel school kid
will want his Social Security number.
全美卡车司机工会离开后…
After the Teamsters got knocked out
of the box...
大集团几乎将所有的旧赌场都拆了
the corporations tore down practically
every one of the old casinos.
而盖新金字塔的钱是从哪来的呢？
And where did the money come from
to rebuild the pyramids?
垃圾债券
Junk bonds.
圣地牙哥
还不确定？
SAM: Still not sure?
有可能，有些质疑
SAM: Probable. Maybe questionable.
好吧，知道后立即通知我
SAM: All right, let me know as soon
as you can find out.
最后，我又回到了起点
SAM: In the end, I wound up
right back where I started.
我还是会选赢家…
I could still pick winners...
也还是可以为老家
各式各样的人赚钱
and I could still make money
for all kinds of people back home.
何必搞砸好事呢？
And why mess up a good thing?
就是这样！
And that's that!
[Nostalgic instrumental music]
[Soft jazz music]